<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jon Doblados</title>
    <link>https://jon.doblados.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jon Doblados</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 17:29:55 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jon.doblados.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Settling Down With Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/settling-down-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 17:29:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/settling-down-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>For the upteenth time, I&amp;rsquo;m switching to an all-static approach to writing. Since Go (the programming language) has been quite popular with most of the 3rd-party tools we use, most particularly Traefik, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start reading and learning about this programming language and document exercises and attempts at using it for tooling. It also makes sense to use Hugo, an ultra-fast and modern static site generator written in Go, as my writing tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Apps Certified Deployment Specialist</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment-specialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment-specialist/</guid>
      <description>Back in November last year, the Apps Services Partner that I help with Google Apps Support told me that I was required to take the Google Apps for Work Deployment Specialist certification exam. I learned that Google was going to end the certification program and that I had to take the exam January 5, 2016. It turns out that they were simplifying the Partner Credential Program. All good!
So I took a crash review during the holiday break, read through all Google Apps for Work help articles I could get my hands on, and did self-study on Google Apps Administrator Fundamentals and Deployment Essentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Planning and Reports</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-planning-and-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-planning-and-reports/</guid>
      <description>In my previous employment, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any problems with submitting reports, practically because we used a time management/monitoring tool and the reports sort of generated by themselves. So when submitting daily reports isn&amp;rsquo;t the norm here at the unit, quarterly reports become quite tricky.
I&amp;rsquo;ve resorted to referring to Google Calendar as most of the stuff we do are usually scheduled. I&amp;rsquo;ve also thought of logging everything on a text file and have pelican publish this to my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering, I.T., Business Management, and Technopreneurship</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/engineering-i.t.-business-management-and-technopreneurship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/engineering-i.t.-business-management-and-technopreneurship/</guid>
      <description>By 2016, five higher education institutes (HEIs) here in the Philippines will be integrating Technopreneurship as an offered elective for their Engineering programs. I am quite thankful that the higher education authorities have included my alma mater. More than being the center of trade in Northern Mindanao, the strategic location of our city makes it the best option for I.T. companies to build or expand in.
While the article specifically mentions entrepeneurship training for future engineers and that inclusion will be done in the Engineering curricula of 5 HEIs, I feel that this is severely limiting the beneficiaries (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Announces MacBook Pro Repair Extension Program for Video Issues</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/apple-announces-macbook-pro-repair-extension-program-for-video-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/apple-announces-macbook-pro-repair-extension-program-for-video-issues/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t think there was going to be any hope for my early 2011 MacBook Pro, which had GPU-related problems after only about a year of use. The only obvious option I had was to buy a replacement laptop. But Apple seems to have been receiving a lot of reports that they&amp;rsquo;ve launched a repair progam that will fix the graphics problem for free.
If you bought a 15-inch or 17-inch MacBook Pro between early 2011 and end of 2013, as well as the first two generations of the Retina models, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got Static!</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/got-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/got-static/</guid>
      <description>I just made the first step towards moving my whole blog to GitHub and going all static! Content is generated by Pelican, a static site generator, written in Python. Why GitHub, you ask? While I can always push the static content to any of my existing web hosts, there&amp;rsquo;s a touch of geekness in writing using my favorite editor and publishing by git commits and pushes; thus GitHub. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s this year that I&amp;rsquo;m planning to pick up Python programming again, for devops reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racking Legacy Servers - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/racking-legacy-servers-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/racking-legacy-servers-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today we scheduled the racking of our old C-Class HP BladeSystem. It used to be wrapped in its own enclosure with wheels to boot, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to have it stand outside the cabinets. So we gave heads up and asked some guys to stay behind after office hours. Thanks to Mona, Eric, Jing, Tim, and Mark(?) for the assist!
Next up, the classic IBM BladeCenter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work over Christmas Break 2014</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/work-over-christmas-break-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 23:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/work-over-christmas-break-2014/</guid>
      <description>10 years ago, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be complaining at all. I could live in a datacenter for days until the job&amp;rsquo;s done. But these days, my back aches are more pronounced, and fatigue sets in more easily. This is why it&amp;rsquo;s always great to have others helping out. Thanks to the CISO and PPO teams for making the migrations happen! I may have gotten older but the one thing that doesn&amp;rsquo;t change is the thrill of the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s no longer about the number of monitors you have</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/its-no-longer-about-the-number-of-monitors-you-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/its-no-longer-about-the-number-of-monitors-you-have/</guid>
      <description>Unlike in the late 90s to mid 2000s, desktop real estate is no longer constrained by the number of monitors you use. We now tout the number of virtual machines we have access to. In fact, my ailing MBP has managed to remain useful because remote access still enables me to work on all our VMs. Our applications and storage servers are all virtualized. Even some legacy systems have been replicated on VMs, allowing us to retire old and bulky server hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Reports Redux</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/crystal-reports-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 20:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/crystal-reports-redux/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d be saying this many years down the road, but here goes anyway. Crystal Reports is my friend. Yep. Apparently, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten my disdain for this piece of software. It&amp;rsquo;s amusing (well, for me) that the last version of Crystal Reports that I used for the systems I developed back in the late 90s, is the same version I was forced to use last week, in modifying an old report template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL on Google Cloud Infrastructure Now Available</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure-now-available/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on SLMIS</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-slmis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-slmis/</guid>
      <description>End users complain because the system isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;user-friendly&amp;rdquo;. FYI, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be that way. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way we can guarantee that the system will still be helpful 25 years from now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Blog changes, etc.</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc./</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve once more moved my blog. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s on my own hosting account and it&amp;rsquo;s back to using WP. Same blog, different flavor now and moving forward. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this short discussion with a co-leader in church on going back to blogging, and he pointed out the importance of identifying to a particular niche. I said sure, it&amp;rsquo;s important, but I think I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to separate my technical gibberish from my thoughts and reflections on God and Christianity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal drop experiences with Motorola Canopy</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/signal-drop-experiences-with-motorola-canopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/signal-drop-experiences-with-motorola-canopy/</guid>
      <description>Gotta finish this quick before the signal drops again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you updated?</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/have-you-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/have-you-updated/</guid>
      <description>jon@jedi-ntbk:~$ lsb_release -aLSB Version: core-2.0-ia32:core-2.0-noarch:core-3.0-ia32:core-3.0-noarch:core-3.1-ia32:core-3.1-noarch:core-3.2-ia32:core-3.2-noarch:core-4.0-ia32:core-4.0-noarchDistributor ID: UbuntuDescription: Ubuntu 10.04.3 LTSRelease: 10.04Codename: lucid</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy alternative to the regular sunny-side up. Mae did poached eggs for the first time! Deeelish!</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/healthy-alternative-to-the-regular-sunny-side-up.-mae-did-poached-eggsfor-the-first-time-deeelish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/healthy-alternative-to-the-regular-sunny-side-up.-mae-did-poached-eggsfor-the-first-time-deeelish/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-the-month TODOs</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/end-of-the-month-todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/end-of-the-month-todos/</guid>
      <description>I have again changed the look of my tech blog. I&#39;ve actually mulled over this for quite some time since I was also thinking of just moving everything to my own hosted Wordpress install. But, lazy as I am, I was content to tweak as little as I can. Posterous has a few really nice themes built-in so moving my stuff out was really a bad idea.
In case you&#39;re curious, here are some of the things that I intend to complete this month:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVN-MantisBT Integration</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/svn-mantisbt-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 02:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/svn-mantisbt-integration/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve downloaded and installed MantisBT 1.2.3stable on linode2, and after fixing permissions issues, proceeded with the installation. I stopped when I realized I didn&#39;t have the same MantisBT version on the old server. It&#39;s always better to set up MantisBT on the target server &#34;as is&#34;, and let the install scripts handle the upgrade.
I&#39;m roughly 28% in with a server-to-server SCP of a 79Mb MySQL dump of our bugtracker. I haven&#39;t had time to check with the backups since I felt that a fresh dump is always best; but no, I remembered that several developers preferred working odd hours and they would definitely need the bug tracker up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Kernel Tuning for C500k | Urban Airship Blog</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k-urban-airship-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k-urban-airship-blog/</guid>
      <description>By Jared &#34;Lucky&#34; Kuolt on September 29, 2010Like the idea of working on large scale problems? We&amp;rsquo;re hiring talented engineers, and would love to chat with you &amp;ndash; check it out!&amp;nbsp;
Note: Concurrency, as defined in this article, is the same as it is for The C10k problem: concurrent clients (or sockets).
At Urban Airship we recently published a blog post about scaling beyond 500,000 concurrent socket connections. Hitting these numbers was not a trivial exercise so we&amp;rsquo;re going to share what we&amp;rsquo;ve come across during our testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get through your email faster with Gmail Priority Inbox</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/get-through-your-email-faster-with-gmail-priority-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 09:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/get-through-your-email-faster-with-gmail-priority-inbox/</guid>
      <description>This is great for people who do not use a GTD system yet. Try it and see how fast it learns. Priority&amp;nbsp;InboxBeta&amp;nbsp;
Welcome to Priority Inbox! By automatically separating out your most important messages, Priority Inbox makes it easy for you to read and respond to the messages that matter.
&amp;nbsp;
Get through your email fasterTry reading and replying to the messages in the &amp;ldquo;Important and Unread&amp;rdquo; section first. Mark anything that requires follow-up with a star, then go through the &amp;ldquo;Everything Else&amp;rdquo; section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to count instances of an IP address in a log file</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-an-ip-address-in-a-log-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-an-ip-address-in-a-log-file/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a quick and painless way to determine what IP addresses used our web app the most and stumbled across this excellent post.&amp;nbsp;I got reminded of the power of the command-line interface and that often, I underestimate the way these commands are supposed to make a sysad&#39;s life easier.
So here&#39;s a quick tip for counting unique visitors to your web app. Locate your web app&#39;s log file and do a quick scan of the last few lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putty on my phone FTW! ISP was acting up and was able to get Apache to work sometime past 3pm. Post-mortem shortly.</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/putty-on-my-phone-ftw-isp-was-acting-up-and-was-able-to-get-apache-towork-sometime-past-3pm.-post-mortem-shortly./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/putty-on-my-phone-ftw-isp-was-acting-up-and-was-able-to-get-apache-towork-sometime-past-3pm.-post-mortem-shortly./</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Systems Administrator @37signals (Podcast)</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/being-a-systems-administrator-37signals-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 22:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/being-a-systems-administrator-37signals-podcast/</guid>
      <description>I use Basecamp a lot. Kudos to these guys for making my job as a Systems Administrator more bearable than usual. :p
Episode #12: Being a Systems Administrator at 37signalsTime: 22:50 | 04/13/2010 | Download MP3 | Link to this episode
Mark, Joshua, and John on life as a 37signals Sys Admin
The Sys Admin team discusses hosting the 37signals apps, working with programmers, helping support, telecommuting, dealing with vendors, improving speeds in Europe, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How big is a Yottabyte? - Holy Kaw!</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/how-big-is-a-yottabyte-holy-kaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 07:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/how-big-is-a-yottabyte-holy-kaw/</guid>
      <description>And I got a long way to go. My next step doesn&#39;t happen in the next couple of months, and that&#39;s when I purchase a terabyte external hard drive for storage purposes.
Remember back in the 1970s when 200MB was the size of a tire? Now we live in a world of gigbytes and terabytes, and the future will bring zettabytes and yottabytes in everyday life. Hello, future!
k to view large</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter - Decentralize the web with Diaspora</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/kickstarter-decentralize-the-web-with-diaspora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/kickstarter-decentralize-the-web-with-diaspora/</guid>
      <description>http://kck.st/9QC2zk IMO, this is the answer to all your privacy-related concerns on Facebook. Can&amp;#8217;t wait til it launches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Web Design Goes Straight to Hell - The Oatmeal</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/how-a-web-design-goes-straight-to-hell-the-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 03:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/how-a-web-design-goes-straight-to-hell-the-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/design_hell Well I&amp;#8217;ll be! Just exactly how things go (but not with our current company, thank God). Goes to @Bambi @Lee @jenipur and all my web designer friends. ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using non-standard SSH port with TortoiseSVN</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with-tortoisesvn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 05:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with-tortoisesvn/</guid>
      <description>Some of my students reported that they were having problems connecting to their repositories using TortoiseSVN. At first, quick checks from my end didn&#39;t reveal what caused these, but I realized soon that it wasn&#39;t a server issue. It seems like the client software that they were using (TortoiseSVN) didn&#39;t know what to make of the svn+ssh://[user]@[ip]:[port]/[repo] URL.
I use RabbitVCS on my Linux boxen and get the same &#34;Network connection closed unexpectedly&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebug Lite 1.3.0 beta /via sitepoint tech times</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/firebug-lite-1.3.0-beta-via-sitepoint-tech-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/firebug-lite-1.3.0-beta-via-sitepoint-tech-times/</guid>
      <description>http://getfirebug.com/releases/lite/beta/ Man, it&amp;#8217;s about time! Some Firebug functionality on my other browsers would be awesome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[repost] System for staying on top of priorities</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/repost-system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/repost-system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve tried a lot of productivity tools to get better control over my ever-bloating task lists, and none have been as effective for me, as using Gmail with the GTDInbox add-on, and Google Tasks. How I make these work for me is a result of several months of trials, using Google Tasks initially, then with custom labeling and automatic label switching with GTDInbox.
The goal was simple, and that was to attain inbox zero at least once a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now I got the itch to shell script this [http://bash.org/?910094]</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/now-i-got-the-itch-to-shell-script-this-httpbash.org910094/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/now-i-got-the-itch-to-shell-script-this-httpbash.org910094/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System for staying on top of priorities</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2009 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of productivity tools to get better control over my ever-bloating task lists, and none have been as effective for me, as using Gmail with the GTDInbox add-on, and Google Tasks. How I make these work for me is a result of several months of trials, using Google Tasks initially, then with custom labeling and automatic label switching with GTDInbox.The goal was simple, and that was to attain inbox zero at least once a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates, finally!</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/updates-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 16:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/updates-finally/</guid>
      <description>Some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing lately: grokking Postfix (again), remapping sites for migration this week, and domain auctions.I also moved my non-tech stuff to posterous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export TweetDeck groups in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/export-tweetdeck-groups-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/export-tweetdeck-groups-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>If you have multiple installs of TweetDeck on different computers, I bet you wished there were ways to save the groups you set up. These groupings are not saved in your Twitter profile, but are kept in a local database in your computer. This means that for each install of TweetDeck, you will have to re-set up your groups, and any changes won&amp;rsquo;t replicate to your other installs.This post about copying TweetDeck settings in Windows explains this in detail, and I have been able to do the same for Ubuntu, replicating TweetDeck settings across 3 machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in 5.</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/back-in-5./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/back-in-5./</guid>
      <description>So I renewed my domain name earlier and thought about writing more just to balance the traffic I get for the domain, which is around 20% HTTP, and 80% SMTP.Mail is obviously important, and since I had Gmail handle mails, everything’s been very stress free. Google just works, right? So migrating once again back to Blogger for my rant pages is now a no-brainer. Stay tuned for more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIIX3 cannot attach drive to the Secondary Master</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/piix3-cannot-attach-drive-to-the-secondary-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/piix3-cannot-attach-drive-to-the-secondary-master/</guid>
      <description>I use VirtualBox for my server experimenting requirements, and it&amp;rsquo;s just great! Just this morning, I got an error message when I started an FC8 virtual machine.PIIX3 cannot attach drive to the Secondary Master.
VBox status code: -102 (VERR_FILE_NOT_FOUND).This thread in the forums explains that the virtual machine was looking for a disk that was supposed to be mounted and could not find it. I was using an external DVD drive and had removed it before I shut down the VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arping -s</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/arping-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/arping-s/</guid>
      <description>arping saves the day once again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Adobe Air apps on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 23:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to remove AgileAgenda after fiddling with it for a week and deciding it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to cut it. There&amp;rsquo;s no Adobe Air Application &amp;ldquo;uninstaller&amp;rdquo; in the menu, and search engine results usually point to Mac lurv, or not. Seems like uninstalling Air apps on OSX is bloody.I did find this nice article on removing Adobe Air on Linux and gave it (well parts of it) a shot.jon@jedi-ntbk:/opt$ sudo dpkg -S /opt/*</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Plesk Blues</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/more-plesk-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/more-plesk-blues/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this problem with Plesk since I started relying heavily on it in 2006. For some reason, after you&amp;rsquo;ve added your client, allocated IP address to client&amp;rsquo;s pool, added a domain, and selecting physical hosting, you get the message:
Unable to update hosting preferences: hosting update is failed: object ID is invalid
After getting this error, you get the domain listed, but still requiring set up. Attempting to complete physical hosting setup will give you same result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my must-have&#39;s for firefox</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/my-must-haves-for-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2007 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/my-must-haves-for-firefox/</guid>
      <description>in not so significant order:1. mm3-proxyswitch
2. regular expressions tester
3. del.icio.us
4. greasemonkey
4. better gmail
5. firegpg
6. downThemAll
7. save as image </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>you&#39;re looking good, opensource!</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/youre-looking-good-opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/youre-looking-good-opensource/</guid>
      <description>opensource gets another breakthrough today, as canonical launches launchpad personal package archive (PPA), an ubuntu linux developers service intended to extend collaboration in software development and give the community equal opportunity to build and package code for ubuntu on the desktop, server, and for mobile applications.great news for those itching to modify packages and contribute to the furtherance of opensource! users can make changes on packages of their choice, and these will be published in the PPA system, somewhat like a special repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plesk won&#39;t start after tweaking mysql</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/plesk-wont-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/plesk-wont-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;ve had this happen to me again the other week and as always, felt like kicking myself for not remembering.we do a lot of performance tuning on mysql, and as a result, we almost always manage to get plesk mangled. not its fault, it just can&amp;rsquo;t run without mysql, doh.not of preference, but plesk happens to be there to make handling domains easier, as a single editing point when you want to change something and not worry about missing something out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>apt-get install kicker-kblogger</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/apt-get-install-kicker-kblogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/apt-get-install-kicker-kblogger/</guid>
      <description>i don&amp;rsquo;t know with you, but i sometimes get the big push to update, if and when there&amp;rsquo;s something new (relatively, for me) to try.up for this week is my dabbling with stuff around kicker, and using kblogger to do some much needed updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelving trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/shelving-trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 15:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/shelving-trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph/</guid>
      <description>I am officially bringing down my old tech blog after Holy Week. It has virtually become a sinkhole for all kinds of spam links and I have barely done anything to keep it up-to-date.
Two&amp;nbsp;of the milestones that I&#39;ve unknowingly and unwittingly accomplished would include (in order, sorry):
1. PR6 (yea, before it went offline for almost a month, and before Google deployed new algorithms sometime in Feb)
2. 20,453 spam comments since I replaced my Wordpress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will code for hosting</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/will-code-for-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2007 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/will-code-for-hosting/</guid>
      <description>Honestly, I haven&#39;t done any coding in the last 4 months, which is really odd, because I never thought I&#39;d be this detached from programming. But I guess there&#39;s more to life than just developing or sustaining&amp;nbsp;passion for singulars. So much for trying not to stay generalist.
So I have this personal domain now, and I&#39;m just glad google apps isn&#39;t as stiff with the applications anymore. The new interface totally rocks too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IP-hijacking and then some</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</guid>
      <description>Almost a month of downtime. The servers were fine, but our IP addresses were not. Somehow, a system bug from one of the hosting companies caused our plan to include 14 other IP addresses, and we only maintained 6 as far as I am concerned.So the hosting company eventually understood what was happening and started asking the right questions. The bug is that the system allowed network administrators to assign to new clients, the IP addresses that have already been assigned to a current client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using symbolic links for MySQL data files</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data-files/</guid>
      <description>Over a year ago, we had several servers configured for high traffic websites. A mispartioning resulted in /var becoming obscenely small, and it was only after MySQL crashed that we remembered this. We couldn’t afford more downtime if we dealt with the partition size problem, so I thought of quickly moving the data files into /home/mysql/{dbname} from /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} and create the symlink /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} -&amp;gt; /home/mysql/{dbname}.I was not certain of the performance implications to this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leeching for internet access</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/leeching-for-internet-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 05:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/leeching-for-internet-access/</guid>
      <description>Sure, my bosses do this all the time…in airports, hotel lobbies, and coffee shops. The mere act of “connecting” to an unsecured wireless network doubles as a necessity and as a leaching of sorts. Gotta love wireless. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hysteria</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/hysteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/hysteria/</guid>
      <description>Casey Kasem’s American Top 40 broadcast back in April 1988 is being streamed today over XM Radio. Def Leppard’s Hysteria is currently playing. Measures and measures of this classic hit flood my ears and I can’t help but smile. There must have been thousands of Icehouse, Def Leppard, and Nelson (to name a few) playbacks since I got them cassette and 8-track tapes.
I still think that the 1980’s was the best decade to grow in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote posting to Blogger Beta</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/remote-posting-to-blogger-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2006 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/remote-posting-to-blogger-beta/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s a pretty slick Windows application that will allow you to post directly to your Blogger Beta account. The Firefox extension&amp;nbsp;Deepest Sender, which allows posting to LJ, Blogger, and Wordpress, doesn&#39;t work with Blogger Beta&amp;nbsp;yet, so here&#39;s a workaround that you can do meantime.
I prefer FOSS applications that run natively on GNU/Linux, but sometimes, you really need to use a platform where you are most productive. Writing stuff&amp;nbsp;from anywhere will mean doing this from my&amp;nbsp;Windows-run notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back and look what I checked out first!</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/im-back-and-look-what-i-checked-out-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/im-back-and-look-what-i-checked-out-first/</guid>
      <description>This is how the rear of the NetBay rack in my previous company looks like now. I headed back to CDO for Halloween vacation and was able to drop by the office to pick up some of my personal stuff. They&amp;rsquo;ve slapped in a Cisco router (where the yellow fibre cable hooks up to) and another L3 switch. The old firewall appliance is still there, reliable as ever. Cabling got more structured as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Talk with Kopete</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/using-google-talk-with-kopete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/using-google-talk-with-kopete/</guid>
      <description>I absolutely love Gaim, but the message to group feature isn&amp;rsquo;t readily available, even with gaim2-beta3, and this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me especially that I sometimes need to broadcast messages to team members over IM. Quick googling led me to Frank Spychalski&amp;rsquo;s very good article, which covers the essentials of configuring Google Talk on Kopete. For Ubuntu users, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have Kopete yet, you will need an internet connection to get the necessary packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Shift to Dapper Beta</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/my-shift-to-dapper-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/my-shift-to-dapper-beta/</guid>
      <description>Over the Holy Week, two of our home computer&amp;rsquo;s drives crashed, probably due to extensive user download, software installs, and malware. I had to do work on the laptop for a while, and since everyone in the house was itching for Internet access, I brought in a small IDE drive (roughly around 9Gb) that was mounted as slave on my office computer and popped that in the home computer. I had more than enough reasons to put Ubuntu back in there, and nobody would be complaining!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Viewed in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/best-viewed-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 09:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/best-viewed-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s so dissapointing to see CSS that you really like &amp;ldquo;unrenderable&amp;rdquo; in IE. All I can say is get Firefox now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting GNU/Linux through Competition</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/promoting-gnulinux-through-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 01:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/promoting-gnulinux-through-competition/</guid>
      <description>Met up with hardwyrd last night for preliminary competition planning. Also present were some of the pillars of GNU/Linux and FOSS in Northern Mindanao: Mr. Rem Taga of MPSC, Mr. Botp Peña of DMPC, and Mr. Vidor Balbon of Philcom. I hope to keep up with these guys considering that my GNU/Linux experience is so diversified and I&amp;rsquo;d have to polish skills on specific services, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve not even bothered tinkering with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling ntpupdate</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/disabling-ntpupdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/disabling-ntpupdate/</guid>
      <description>This has been quite overdue, as I have been wanting to disable ntpupdate since the Hoary release. What is ntpupdate anyway? It&amp;rsquo;s the program that synchronizes your system time to an ntp server. NTP is a protocol for synchronising the clocks of computer systems over packet-switched, variable-latency data networks. Since Ubuntu defaults to an ntp server somewhere in the www, and that it will attempt to sync on boot, it causes your machine to go through a much much longer startup process if an internet connection is not available at boot time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-commerce Theory and Practice</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/e-commerce-theory-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/e-commerce-theory-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>The coming finals in my e-commerce class got me browsing through piles of readings and notes and I realized that I have not fully appreciated e-commerce as I should have. A techie will know what digital signatures, catalogs, EDI&amp;rsquo;s, EFT&amp;rsquo;s, shopping carts, or SSL are, as applied to buying and selling online; but graduate school won&amp;rsquo;t even let you wallow in those. Instead, one gets tasked to relate e-commerce with business processes, and usually, look for solutions to support business processes that e-commerce systems can&amp;rsquo;t support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Extension for Firefox</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/performance-extension-for-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/performance-extension-for-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Miko for the heads up. Check out this quite nice extension to Firefox, which will allow you to do updates without having to log in to your numerous blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRASS</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2005 05:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/grass/</guid>
      <description>I had a good consultation session with my mentor last Saturday and I got great advise for my thesis. I&amp;rsquo;m planting my foot on GIS and applications, but the whole gamut of GIS is fairly large so I had to zero in on what I really wanted to focus on. Future research prospects on GIS led me to look up Geographic Resources Analysis Support System, commonly referred to as GRASS. It&amp;rsquo;s so cool because for starters, it&amp;rsquo;s GPLed, and it will run on PostgreSQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on Dune</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-dune/</guid>
      <description>Ayt, it has been almost 10 years since I last watched Dune, but the plot, the lines&amp;hellip;they all came back to me when Matt posted the Litany of Fear on his website. Sure does bring back the awe I felt back then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mysql woes</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/mysql-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 07:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/mysql-woes/</guid>
      <description>In my quest to have my &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; blog resuscitated on our new p5 server so that I have something to use for my tech notes here at work as well as my MS requirements, I downloaded MySQL-4.1.12-0.sles9.src.rpm from mysql.com in the hope of getting Wordpress running on our server. I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to install the darn thing. So I dl&amp;rsquo;ed mysql-standard-4.1.12-unknown-linux-gnu-powerpc-glibc23.tar.gz and tried to use the binaries instead.Viola! MySQL4.1.12 managed to run fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TODO 06/21</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/todo-0621/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 23:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/todo-0621/</guid>
      <description> finish Perl script that will import mail accounts to the new p52. test alias IP and check what tcp_sync error means3. do report on failed drive4. finalize schedule for website design consultation sessions with concern personnelpresent designs to stafftest clamv, amavis, &amp;amp; spamd configsget BERT report from MGC (from RIA)start and try to finish configuration work on vclassstart migrating email accounts to p5  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dumbass mode</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/dumbass-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/dumbass-mode/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;m really hoping my old server gets up soon so i can download my shit out and start publishing again from our own servers here. all my scripts and applications that have been published are there, and most of the updates i did are there. the server went out even before i could sync my local copies. dumbass right? like why in the world would you be doing sync from a remote?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTA setup</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/mta-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2005 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/mta-setup/</guid>
      <description>Pending Tjay&amp;rsquo;s visit, the reconfiguration of the Firebox will have to wait. It is important to have the CDO MTA running along with the HTTPD service in the P5-520 to be able to test the configuration in more or less &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; conditions.Public IP: 203.177.75.33Public Alias: 203.177.75.37TODO:1. set up of CDO MTA (HTTP and Postfix in one machine)2. DNS entries for cdo.cepalco.com.ph and mla.cepalco.com.ph3. Verify if HTTP NAT and SMTP NAT will not have problems with multiple domains e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on emacs</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/on-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I have been trying to find time to install Emacs (temporarily) on jjd because I really want to get my planner running asap. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing that there is currently a good following for this editor, especially when add-on functionality is introducted: like PlannerMode, which I believe will be a very good tool for me. It will allow the conception of collaborative input/development for tasks and projects.TODO:1. Install Emacs. On Ubuntu or any Debian-based distribution of Linux, type &amp;ldquo;apt-get install emacs21&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more stf blues</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/more-stf-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 23:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/more-stf-blues/</guid>
      <description>1. test batch nos. 003442 (solomon) and 003444 (intra)2. per InvtID, pick up LotSerNbr(s) as required or set by needed quantity, and insert corresponding number of rows in LotSerT3. if i will require 3 serials, then the top non-zero LotSerNbr&#39;s will be retrieved and inserted accordingly to LotSerT4. during release by solomon, QtyOnHand will be set to 0 and a new row will be created for the same item, with QtyOnHand set to 1, indicating that the item has moved locations/sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>changes for stf</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/changes-for-stf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 23:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/changes-for-stf/</guid>
      <description>1. stf transactions (data entry) over the intranet had problems when solomon tries to do a &#34;release now&#34; action.2. further analysis by LPE shows that the intranet module hasn&#39;t completely emulated the &#34;transfers&#34; transaction of solomon, in that the items transferred did not have corresponding serialized entries in LotSerT3. relations: Batch 1:1 TrnsfrDoc, Batch 1:n INTran, INTran 1:n LotSerT4. look up for LotSerT.LotSerNbr will come from LotSerMst (where all serialized items are built up)5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>soon-to-be-IBM-customer</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/soon-to-be-ibm-customer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2004 05:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/soon-to-be-ibm-customer/</guid>
      <description>What a month it has been! It was my first time to do facilitating work relevant to equipment acquisition, and everything has been so cooperative (thank God!). The only thing that&amp;rsquo;s keeping me from getting giddy with anticipation over the delivery of those servers is the fact that the PO hasn&amp;rsquo;t been issued yet. It seems to me that Purchasing people have this degree of power over everyone else, in the sense that they can always mull over our longing to have stuff bought right away and decide to do delaying tactics just for the hell of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ack...</title>
      <link>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/ack.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2004 07:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jon.doblados.net/posts/ack.../</guid>
      <description>m down to my last two modules before this quarter ends. the first modules have been deployed and parallel-tested, with just a bit of flak coming from &amp;ldquo;concerned&amp;rdquo; users (since they&amp;rsquo;re sooo used to stand-alone applications, they think that intranet applications would have the same degree of difficulty, more or less). hell my scripts generate 5k lines of values each for 10 different select elements and they wanted a more &amp;ldquo;user-friendly&amp;rdquo; output.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>