<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amalgamated Thoughts </title>
    <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amalgamated Thoughts </description>
    <generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <contact>jon@doblados.net</contact>
    <copyright>&copy; <a href="https://jondoblados.github.io/">Jon Doblados</a> 2018</copyright>
    
        <atom:link href="https://jondoblados.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Settling Down With Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/settling-down-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 17:29:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/settling-down-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;For the upteenth time, I&amp;rsquo;m switching to an all-static approach to writing. Since &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; (the programming language) has been quite popular with most of the 3rd-party tools we use, most particularly &lt;a href=&#34;https://traefik.io/&#34;&gt;Traefik&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start reading and learning about this programming language and document exercises and attempts at using it for tooling. It also makes sense to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, an ultra-fast and modern static site generator written in Go, as my writing tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/features/&#34;&gt;features of Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/benefits/&#34;&gt;benefits of using Static Site Generators&lt;/a&gt; for your blogging needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Apps Certified Deployment Specialist</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment-specialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment-specialist/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Back in November last year, the Apps Services Partner that I help with Google Apps Support told me that I was required to take the Google Apps for Work Deployment Specialist certification exam. I learned that Google was going to end the certification program and that I had to take the exam January 5, 2016. It turns out that they were simplifying the Partner Credential Program. All good!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I took a crash review during the holiday break, read through all Google Apps for Work help articles I could get my hands on, and did self-study on Google Apps Administrator Fundamentals and Deployment Essentials.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I thought I could wing it with an hour or two of readings each day. Turns out that I had to read, practice, read some more, and recall deployments I was involved in. It was very humbling because I thought I knew a lot, and that if I made sure I understood different deployment use cases, I&amp;rsquo;d be fine. Boy, was I wrong. I was pulling at my hair trying to recall concepts and best practices around:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mail delivery architectures&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Directory Sync and user provisioning from LDAP servers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Data migration from Microsoft Exchange, IBM Notes and Domino, and IMAP sources&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Configuration and support for mobile devices&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Security features like SSO, SSL, and compliance settings&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;It took me 84 gruelling minutes to complete the exam, with the proctor stopping the exam a couple of times for camera adjustments. I got too frazzled that I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize I passed the exam because right after I turned it in, the assessing system immediately presented my certificate and badge; and it took a while for that to sink in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let me know if your company wants to transition to using Google Apps as your email, collaboration, and productivity solution.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MWRfZplknOQ/WPMB7-YcYHI/AAAAAAAAcN0/B9rseAcF4kIavzFPV6p9EIEFyPNP7cxhACLcB/s1600/cert.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; &gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MWRfZplknOQ/WPMB7-YcYHI/AAAAAAAAcN0/B9rseAcF4kIavzFPV6p9EIEFyPNP7cxhACLcB/s320/cert.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;231&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Planning and Reports</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-planning-and-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-planning-and-reports/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;In my previous employment, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any problems with submitting reports, practically because we used a time management/monitoring tool and the reports sort of generated by themselves. So when submitting daily reports isn&amp;rsquo;t the norm here at the unit, quarterly reports become quite tricky.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve resorted to referring to Google Calendar as most of the stuff we do are usually scheduled. I&amp;rsquo;ve also thought of logging everything on a text file and have pelican publish this to my website.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Meantime, my reading list for the day as I decide on a workflow that will allow multiple teams to work on the university website:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sitepoint.com/one-click-app-deployment-server-side-git-hooks/&#34;&gt;http://www.sitepoint.com/one-click-app-deployment-server-side-git-hooks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/425692/what-is-your-preferred-php-deployment-strategy&#34;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/425692/what-is-your-preferred-php-deployment-strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-automate-php-app-deployment-process-using-capistrano-on-ubuntu-13&#34;&gt;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-automate-php-app-deployment-process-using-capistrano-on-ubuntu-13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering, I.T., Business Management, and Technopreneurship</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/engineering-i.t.-business-management-and-technopreneurship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/engineering-i.t.-business-management-and-technopreneurship/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;technopreneurship&#34; height=&#34;211&#34; src=&#34;https://encrypted-tbn1.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcT0x5POqU25iVphCtjb-GmPJct6XwGw3YDDZVtohhA1ydSaY6Df&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;By 2016, five higher education institutes (HEIs) here in the Philippines will be integrating Technopreneurship as an offered elective for their Engineering programs. I am quite thankful that the higher education authorities have included my alma mater. More than being the center of trade in Northern Mindanao, the strategic location of our city makes it the best option for I.T. companies to build or expand in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While the article specifically mentions &lt;a href=&#34;http://newsinfo.inquirer.net/674790/setting-up-entrepreneurship-training-for-future-engineers#ixzz3Spg7ePjv&#34;&gt;entrepeneurship training for future engineers&lt;/a&gt; and that inclusion will be done in the Engineering curricula of 5 HEIs, I feel that this is severely limiting the beneficiaries (e.g. the graduates, and ultimately, the HEIs) of this inclusion. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scope of Technopreneurship demands its inclusion not only in Engineering programs, but in Business Management (Business Administration, Financial Management, etc) and Computer Science (Information Management, Software Engineering, etc) as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the other hand, I think these may just be preliminaries. After these initial inclusions, other relevant programs may be lined up for inclusion/integration. The higher education authorities will continue to leverage priority programs in Science, Technology, Engineering, Agriculture and Mathematics (STEAM), which are critical for the country&amp;rsquo;s development.&lt;br /&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/inquirerdotnet&#34;&gt;@inquirerdotnet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Announces MacBook Pro Repair Extension Program for Video Issues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apple-announces-macbook-pro-repair-extension-program-for-video-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apple-announces-macbook-pro-repair-extension-program-for-video-issues/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://o.aolcdn.com/hss/storage/midas/1832ae613253d9905a62cc78a047028/201580477/macbook-pro-2011-630.jpg&#34; height=&#34;165&#34; style=&#34;border: none; padding: 5px;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t think there was going to be any hope for my early 2011 MacBook Pro, which had GPU-related problems after only about a year of use. The only obvious option I had was to buy a replacement laptop. But Apple seems to have been receiving a lot of reports that they&amp;rsquo;ve launched a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/asia/support/macbookpro-videoissues/&#34;&gt;repair progam&lt;/a&gt; that will fix the graphics problem for free.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you bought a 15-inch or 17-inch MacBook Pro between early 2011 and end of 2013, as well as the first two generations of the Retina models, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck. The program became available to the US and Canada last February 20, and would be available to other countries by February 27.&lt;br /&gt;These are the affected models: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (15-inch Early 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (15-inch, Late 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (Retina, 15-inch, Mid 2012)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (17-inch Early 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (17-inch Late 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (Retina, 15 inch, Early 2013)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not sure if your model is included in the list of affected products? Use this &lt;a href=&#34;https://selfsolve.apple.com/agreementWarrantyDynamic.do&#34;&gt;Check your Coverage&lt;/a&gt; tool on the Apple Support site.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got Static!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/got-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/got-static/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I just made the first step towards moving my whole blog to GitHub and going all static! Content is generated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getpelican/pelican&#34;&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator, written in Python. Why GitHub, you ask? While I can always push the static content to any of my existing web hosts, there&amp;rsquo;s a touch of geekness in writing using my favorite editor and publishing by git commits and pushes; thus GitHub. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, it&amp;rsquo;s this year that I&amp;rsquo;m planning to pick up Python programming again, for devops reasons. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually remember the last time I was this excited to post an update!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racking Legacy Servers - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/racking-legacy-servers-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/racking-legacy-servers-part-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier today we scheduled the racking of our old C-Class HP BladeSystem. It used to be wrapped in its own enclosure with wheels to boot, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to have it stand outside the cabinets. So we gave heads up and asked some guys to stay behind after office hours. Thanks to Mona, Eric, Jing, Tim, and Mark(?) for the assist!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up, the classic IBM BladeCenter!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- Place this tag in your head or just before your close body tag. --&gt; &lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://apis.google.com/js/plusone.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;!-- Place this tag where you want the widget to render. --&gt; &lt;div class=&#34;g-post&#34; data-href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/114642277785568765419/posts/7FNAGmLStBM&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work over Christmas Break 2014</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/work-over-christmas-break-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 23:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/work-over-christmas-break-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;10 years ago, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be complaining at all. I could live in a datacenter for days until the job&amp;rsquo;s done. But these days, my back aches are more pronounced, and fatigue sets in more easily. This is why it&amp;rsquo;s always great to have others helping out. Thanks to the CISO and PPO teams for making the migrations happen! I may have gotten older but the one thing that doesn&amp;rsquo;t change is the thrill of the job.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My family isn&amp;rsquo;t as thrilled, naturally. While it&amp;rsquo;s the Christmas break, they spend each day mostly without me. And when I do get home, everyone&amp;rsquo;s too tired to stay up; especially me. Sometimes I wished we could schedule downtime at work other than during holidays. But that&amp;rsquo;s how a sysad&amp;rsquo;s life goes. Meantime, there&amp;rsquo;s going to be a ton of making up with the family in the next few days.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check out some of the photos here. A happy and prosperous new year to all!  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;g-post&#34; data-href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/114642277785568765419/posts/YEt5yPsHYEm&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s no longer about the number of monitors you have</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/its-no-longer-about-the-number-of-monitors-you-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/its-no-longer-about-the-number-of-monitors-you-have/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Unlike in the late 90s to mid 2000s, desktop real estate is no longer constrained by the number of monitors you use. We now tout the number of virtual machines we have access to. In fact, my ailing MBP has managed to remain useful because remote access still enables me to work on all our VMs. Our applications and storage servers are all virtualized. Even some legacy systems have been replicated on VMs, allowing us to retire old and bulky server hardware. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;!-- Place this tag where you want the widget to render. --&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;g-post&#34; data-href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/114642277785568765419/posts/ECQTnCpHHJi&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Reports Redux</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/crystal-reports-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 20:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/crystal-reports-redux/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-LQL1lrPVviw/U6F8AIb7a-I/AAAAAAAAMDM/u0ISYYktQN4/s1600/crystal8.gif&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-LQL1lrPVviw/U6F8AIb7a-I/AAAAAAAAMDM/u0ISYYktQN4/s200/crystal8.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d be saying this many years down the road, but here goes anyway. Crystal Reports is my friend. Yep. Apparently, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten my disdain for this piece of software. It&amp;rsquo;s amusing (well, for me) that the last version of Crystal Reports that I used for the systems I developed back in the late 90s, is the same version I was forced to use last week, in modifying an old report template.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some old versions of software refuse to die primarily because many of the enterprise systems that continue to run today rely on output templates that can only be created or modified with very specific software versions. It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder there are still many &amp;ldquo;indispensable&amp;rdquo; legacy systems out there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now I wish I can say the same for plain RTF templates&amp;nbsp;+ Oracle Business Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL on Google Cloud Infrastructure Now Available</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure-now-available/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;div class=&#34;g-post&#34; data-href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/114642277785568765419/posts/VnUU1kpqwNe&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on SLMIS</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-slmis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-slmis/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;End users complain because the system isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;user-friendly&amp;rdquo;. FYI, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be that way. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way we can guarantee that the system will still be helpful 25 years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Blog changes, etc.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc./</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve once more moved my blog. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s on my own hosting account and it&amp;rsquo;s back to using WP&lt;/del&gt;. Same blog, different flavor now and moving forward. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this short discussion with a co-leader in church on going back to blogging, and he pointed out the importance of identifying to a particular niche. I said sure, it&amp;rsquo;s important, but I think I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to separate my technical gibberish from my thoughts and reflections on God and Christianity.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So I was digging through old posts earlier, and in the spirit of moving, migrations, or however you&amp;rsquo;d want to call it, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d re-share with you an old &lt;a title=&#34;Meh&#34; href=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/personal/meh/ &#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;If I pointed you to another blog of mine, would you visit that as much, considering that it would have mostly techno babble in it, and that it won’t have the indispensable “my friends” link (because it’s not on LJ)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Be kind, now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal drop experiences with Motorola Canopy</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/signal-drop-experiences-with-motorola-canopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/signal-drop-experiences-with-motorola-canopy/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_JHuHfdaBdM/T5U_ZYC0PqI/AAAAAAAAADE/jIzR8xto2aw/s1600/Screen+Shot+2012-04-23+at+7.23.02+PM.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;124&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_JHuHfdaBdM/T5U_ZYC0PqI/AAAAAAAAADE/jIzR8xto2aw/s200/Screen+Shot+2012-04-23+at+7.23.02+PM.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Gotta finish this quick before the signal drops again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you updated?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/have-you-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/have-you-updated/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;jon@jedi-ntbk:~$ lsb_release -a&lt;br/&gt;LSB Version:    core-2.0-ia32:core-2.0-noarch:core-3.0-ia32:core-3.0-noarch:core-3.1-ia32:core-3.1-noarch:core-3.2-ia32:core-3.2-noarch:core-4.0-ia32:core-4.0-noarch&lt;br/&gt;Distributor ID:    Ubuntu&lt;br/&gt;Description:    Ubuntu 10.04.3 LTS&lt;br/&gt;Release:    10.04&lt;br/&gt;Codename:    lucid&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy alternative to the regular sunny-side up. Mae did poached eggs for the first time! Deeelish!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/healthy-alternative-to-the-regular-sunny-side-up.-mae-did-poached-eggsfor-the-first-time-deeelish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/healthy-alternative-to-the-regular-sunny-side-up.-mae-did-poached-eggsfor-the-first-time-deeelish/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;div class=&#34;p_embed p_image_embed&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/Gravity.jpg.scaled1000.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/Gravity.jpg.scaled1000-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gravity&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobileways.de/gravity&#34;&gt;Gravity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-the-month TODOs</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/end-of-the-month-todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/end-of-the-month-todos/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Todo&#34; height=&#34;363&#34; src=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/todo.jpg.scaled500-300x272.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I have again changed the look of my tech blog. I&#39;ve actually mulled over this for quite some time since I was also thinking of just moving everything to my own hosted Wordpress install. But, lazy as I am, I was content to tweak as little as I can. Posterous has a few really nice themes built-in so moving my stuff out was really a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case you&#39;re curious, here are some of the things that I intend to complete this month:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Finish half of my self-imposed OpenStack Compute reading assignment. Oh wait, that wouldn&#39;t be half, since I intend to test run an OpenStack Compute instance. :p&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. With my buddy Romar, complete and deploy a hosting infrastructure over AWS, using of all things, Pound as a proxy, with lots of small and micro EC2 instances serving data from a single, extra large and high-memory RDS instance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Upgrade the main EC2 instance where Pound lives so it can take a beating. I will most likely do some tests with the actual traffic in order to determine if Pound is memory or CPU extensive; and this will help me decide which type of instance to upgrade to later on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Upload one of my audio rants as a podcast. My being slightly OC doesn&#39;t help at all, really. I got half a mind wanting to redo them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. Complete a custom theme for my wife&#39;s food blog. Yeah, I owe her big time. Maybe I ought to bump this up to #1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you do stuff like I do, I&#39;d be glad to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVN-MantisBT Integration</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/svn-mantisbt-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 02:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/svn-mantisbt-integration/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;04&#34; height=&#34;314&#34; src=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/04.png.scaled500-300x196.png&#34; width=&#34;479&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I&#39;ve downloaded and installed MantisBT 1.2.3stable on linode2, and after fixing permissions issues, proceeded with the installation. I stopped when I realized I didn&#39;t have the same MantisBT version on the old server. It&#39;s always better to set up MantisBT on the target server &#34;as is&#34;, and let the install scripts handle the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m roughly 28% in with a server-to-server SCP of a 79Mb MySQL dump of our bugtracker. I haven&#39;t had time to check with the backups since I felt that a fresh dump is always best; but no, I remembered that several developers preferred working odd hours and they would definitely need the bug tracker up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up, install the different source and meta plugins needed to make this mashup work. Excellent guide &lt;a href=&#34;http://leetcode.net/blog/2009/01/integrating-git-svn-with-mantisbt/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Kernel Tuning for C500k | Urban Airship Blog</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k-urban-airship-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k-urban-airship-blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;By Jared &#34;Lucky&#34; Kuolt on September 29, 2010&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;background: #e1dcd6; border: 1px solid #d7d2cc; padding: 10px;&#34;&gt;Like the idea of working on large scale problems? We&amp;rsquo;re hiring talented engineers, and would love to chat with you &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://urbanairship.com/jobs/&#34;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: Concurrency, as defined in this article, is the same as it is for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kegel.com/c10k.html&#34;&gt;The C10k problem&lt;/a&gt;: concurrent clients (or sockets).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Urban Airship we recently published a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/08/24/c500k-in-action-at-urban-airship/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about scaling beyond 500,000 concurrent socket connections. Hitting these numbers was not a trivial exercise so we&amp;rsquo;re going to share what we&amp;rsquo;ve come across during our testing. This guide is specific to Linux and has some information related to Amazon EC2, but it is not EC2-centric. These principles should apply to just about any Linux platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our usage, squeezing out as many possible socket connections per server is valuable. Instead of running 100 servers with 10,000 connections each, we&amp;rsquo;d rather run 2 servers with 500,000 connections apiece. To do this we made the socket servers pretty much &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; socket servers. Any communication between the client and server is passed through &lt;a href=&#34;http://kr.github.com/beanstalkd/&#34;&gt;a queue&lt;/a&gt; and processed by a worker. Having less for the socket server to do means less code, cpu-usage, and ram-usage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;To get to these numbers we must consider the Linux kernel itself. A number of configurations needed tweaking. But first, an anecdote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Kernel, OOM, LOWMEM, and You&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We first tested our code on a local Linux box that had Ubuntu 64-bit with 6GB of RAM, connecting with several Ubuntu VMs per client using bridged network adapters so we could ramp up our connections. We&amp;rsquo;d fire up the server and run our clients locally to see just how many connections we could hit. We noticed that we could hit 512,000 with our Java server not even breaking a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next step was to test on EC2. We first wanted to see what sort of numbers we could get on &amp;ldquo;Small&amp;rdquo; instances, which are 1.7GB 32-bit VMs. We also had to fire up a number of other EC2 instances to act as clients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We watched the numbers go up and up without a hitch until, seemingly randomly, the Java server fell over. It didn&amp;rsquo;t print any exceptions or die gracefully&amp;mdash;it was killed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We tried the same process again to see if we could replicate the behavior. Killed again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grepping through syslog, we found this line:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Out of Memory: Killed process 2178 java&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The OOM-killer killed the Java process. Having watched the free RAM closely, this was odd because we had at least 500MB free at the time of the kill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next time we ran it we watched the contents of &lt;code&gt;/proc/meminfo&lt;/code&gt;. What we noticed was a steady decline of the field &amp;ldquo;LowFree&amp;rdquo;, the amount of LOWMEM that is available. LOWMEM is the kernel-addressable RAM space used for kernel data. Data like socket buffers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we increased the number of sockets each socket&amp;rsquo;s buffers increased the amount of LOWMEM used. Once LOWMEM was full the kernel (instead of simply panicking) found the user process responsible for the usage and promptly killed it so it could continue to function.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a standard EC2 Small, the configuration is such that the LOWMEM is around 717MB and the rest is &amp;ldquo;given&amp;rdquo; to the user. The kernel is smart about reallocating LOWMEM for the user, but not the other way around. The assumption is that the kernel will use very little ram, or at least a predictable finite amount, and the user should be allowed to go crazy. What we needed with our socket server was just the opposite. We needed the kernel to use all the ram it needed&amp;mdash;our Java server rarely uses above a few hundred MB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;(For an in-depth rundown, take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://kerneltrap.org/node/2450&#34;&gt;High Memory In The Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a 32-bit system the kernel-addressable RAM space is 4GB. Making sure the proper space reserved for the kernel is important. But on 64-bit (x86-64) Linux the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X86-64#Linux&#34;&gt;kernel-addressable space is 64TB (terabytes)&lt;/a&gt;. At the current state of computing this is effectively limitless, and as such you will not even see LowMem in &lt;code&gt;/proc/meminfo&lt;/code&gt; because it is &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; LOWMEM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we created some EC2 Large instances (each of which is 64-bit with 7.5GB of RAM) and ran our tests again, this time without any surprises. The sockets were added happily and the kernel took all the RAM it needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Long story short, you can only scale to so many sockets on a 32-bit platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Kernel Options&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several parameters exist to allow for tuning and tweaking of socket-related parameters. In &lt;code&gt;/etc/sysctl.conf&lt;/code&gt; there are a few options we&amp;rsquo;ve modified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;First is &lt;code&gt;fs.file-max&lt;/code&gt;, the maximum file descriptor limit. The default is quite low so this should be adjusted. Be careful if you&amp;rsquo;re not ready to go super high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, we have the socket buffer parameters &lt;code&gt;net.ipv4.tcp_rmem&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;net.ipv4.tcp_wmem&lt;/code&gt;. These are the buffers for reads and writes respectively. Each requires three integer inputs: min, default, and max. These each correspond to the number of bytes that may be buffered for a socket. Set these low with a tolerant max to reduce the amount of ram used for each socket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The relevant portions of our config look like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;fs.file-max = 999999&lt;br/&gt;net.ipv4.tcp_rmem = 4096 4096 16777216&lt;br/&gt;net.ipv4.tcp_wmem = 4096 4096 16777216&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meaning that the kernel allows for 999,999 open file descriptors and each socket buffer has a minimum and default 4096-byte buffer, with a sensible max of 16MB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also modified &lt;code&gt;/etc/security/linux.conf&lt;/code&gt; to allow for 999,999 open file descriptors for all users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;#                 &lt;br/&gt;*               -       nofile         999999&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may want to look at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ss64.com/bash/limits.conf.html&#34;&gt;manpage&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Testing&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;When testing, we were able to get about 64,000 connections per client by increasing the number of ephemeral ports allowed on both the client and the server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;echo &amp;quot;1024 65535&amp;quot; &amp;gt; /proc/sys/net/ipv4/ip_local_port_range&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This effectively allows every ephemeral port above 1024 be used instead of the default, which is a much lower (and typically more sane) default.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The 64k Connection Myth&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a common misconception that you can only accept 64,000 connections per IP address and the only way around it is to add more IPs. This is &lt;em&gt;absolutely false&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The misconception begins with the premise that there are only so many ephemeral ports per IP. The truth is that the limit is based on the IP &lt;em&gt;pair&lt;/em&gt;, or said another way, the client and server IPs together. A single client IP can connect to a server IP 64,000 times and so can another client IP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Were this myth true it would be a significant and easy-to-exploit DDoS vector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scaling for Everyone&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we set out to establish half a million connections on a single server we were diving deep into water that wasn&amp;rsquo;t well documented. Sure, we know that C10k is relatively trivial, but how about an order of magnitude (and then some) above that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately we&amp;rsquo;ve been able to achieve success without too many serious problems. Hopefully our solutions can help save time for those out there looking to solve the same problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Posted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/android/&#34; title=&#34;View all posts in android&#34; rel=&#34;category tag&#34;&gt;android&lt;/a&gt; &amp;bull; Tagged with &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/tag/64bit/&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;64bit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/tag/c500k/&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;c500k&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/tag/ec2/&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;ec2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/tag/kernel/&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;kernel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/tag/kittensftw/&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;kittensftw&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/tag/linux/&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;5 Responses&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c4f07c10c49799c211793cca5b3d3ee9?s=64&amp;amp;d=&amp;lt;path_to_url&amp;gt;&amp;amp;r=G&#34; height=&#34;64&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;64&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://magarshak.com&#34; rel=&#34;external nofollow&#34;&gt;Magarshak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; at 3:48 pm on September 29, 2010&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wow, amazing! Now if only I could load 500k concurrent PHP scripts at the same time, without having 2MB eaten up by each in memory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/09/29/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k/?replytocom=827#respond&#34; class=&#34;comment-reply-link&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/e904ebfe4e19721369c3ee4788cf1ef0?s=64&amp;amp;d=&amp;lt;path_to_url&amp;gt;&amp;amp;r=G&#34; height=&#34;64&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;64&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;seaesliek&lt;/cite&gt; at 4:52 pm on September 29, 2010&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can: Write in C.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/09/29/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k/?replytocom=828#respond&#34; class=&#34;comment-reply-link&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/57eb5bcc18e3f4c08ed6111fb48b96fc?s=64&amp;amp;d=&amp;lt;path_to_url&amp;gt;&amp;amp;r=G&#34; height=&#34;64&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;64&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Cristian&lt;/cite&gt; at 7:15 pm on September 29, 2010&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is this &amp;ldquo;posted in android&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/09/29/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k/?replytocom=829#respond&#34; class=&#34;comment-reply-link&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/e4804b99a5e5e0224bd974d6bac0a578?s=64&amp;amp;d=&amp;lt;path_to_url&amp;gt;&amp;amp;r=G&#34; height=&#34;64&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;64&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;lucky&lt;/cite&gt; at 7:37 pm on September 29, 2010&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cristian,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We created the C500k for our Android Push infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/09/29/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k/?replytocom=830#respond&#34; class=&#34;comment-reply-link&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/276da40e2b12446e2e5f994f36c794c3?s=64&amp;amp;d=&amp;lt;path_to_url&amp;gt;&amp;amp;r=G&#34; height=&#34;64&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;64&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Wil&lt;/cite&gt; at 8:20 pm on September 29, 2010&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Great article!  As someone who once struggled to understand these settings in the past, this is the best description I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;One minor correction: it&amp;rsquo;s /etc/security/limits.conf, not /etc/security/linux.conf.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/09/29/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k/?replytocom=831#respond&#34; class=&#34;comment-reply-link&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Leave a Reply&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/09/29/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k#&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;Click here to cancel reply.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.urbanairship.com/blog/2010/09/29/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k/&#34;&gt;blog.urbanairship.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is so helpful. Everything described here reminded me and a fellow-sysad what we went through troubleshooting an OOM issue. So uncanny, it&#39;s de ja vu!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get through your email faster with Gmail Priority Inbox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/get-through-your-email-faster-with-gmail-priority-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 09:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/get-through-your-email-faster-with-gmail-priority-inbox/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; border-collapse: collapse;&#34;&gt;This is great for people who do not use a GTD system yet. Try it and see how fast it learns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;gmail_quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mail.google.com/mail/help/intl/en/priority-inbox.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/images/io_video.png&#34; alt=&#34;sections&#34; style=&#34;float: right; padding-left: 20px; border: none;&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/images/io_gmail.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gmail&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 10px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;font-size: 160%; line-height: 26px; font-weight: bold; padding-bottom: 2px;&#34;&gt;Priority&amp;nbsp;Inbox&lt;sup style=&#34;font-size: x-small; color: #6b6c6e;&#34;&gt;Beta&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;clear: left;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Priority Inbox! By automatically separating out your most important messages, Priority Inbox makes it easy for you to read and respond to the messages that matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1 style=&#34;font-size: 130%; clear: both;&#34;&gt;Get through your email faster&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/images/io_sections.png&#34; alt=&#34;sections&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try reading and replying to the messages in the &amp;ldquo;Important and Unread&amp;rdquo; section first. Mark anything that requires follow-up with a star, then go through the &amp;ldquo;Everything Else&amp;rdquo; section. If you leave Priority Inbox, you can return to it by clicking the link next to Inbox on the side navigation of Gmail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1 style=&#34;font-size: 130%;&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gmail&amp;rsquo;s servers look at several types of information to identify the email that&amp;rsquo;s important to you, including who you email and chat with most, how often you email with these people, and which keywords appear frequently in the emails you read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1 style=&#34;font-size: 130%; clear: both;&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Train Priority Inbox&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Priority Inbox makes a mistake, you can use the &lt;img src=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/images/io_mark.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mark important&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/images/io_unmark.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mark not important&#34; /&gt; buttons to correctly mark a conversation as important or not important, and Priority Inbox will quickly learn what you care about most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/images/io_menu.png&#34; alt=&#34;sections&#34; style=&#34;float: right; padding-left: 20px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1 style=&#34;font-size: 130%;&#34;&gt;And more&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;padding-bottom: 8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Customize Priority Inbox:&lt;/strong&gt; You can change what type of email you see in each section (like switching the &amp;ldquo;Important and Unread&amp;rdquo; section to just &amp;ldquo;Important&amp;rdquo;). Just click on the section headers or visit the Priority Inbox tab under &lt;a href=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/#settings/priorityinbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Settings&lt;/a&gt; and choose to &amp;ldquo;customize inbox groups.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;padding-bottom: 8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Use filters to guarantee importance:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to be absolutely sure that some messages are always marked as important (like email from your boss), you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/#settings/filters&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;set up a filter&lt;/a&gt; and choose &amp;ldquo;Always mark it as important.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;padding-bottom: 8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Search by importance:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to see all the messages that have been marked as important, both read and unread, do a Gmail search for &amp;ldquo;is:important.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Switching back to your old inbox:&lt;/strong&gt; If Priority Inbox isn&amp;rsquo;t for you, you can easily switch back to your normal inbox by clicking &amp;ldquo;Inbox&amp;rdquo; on the left or hide Priority Inbox altogether from Gmail &lt;a href=&#34;https://mail.google.com/hosted/focusoutsourcing.com/#settings/priorityinbox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Settings&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about managing your email with Priority Inbox, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mail.google.com/support/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=185708&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gmail Help Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;- The Gmail Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;padding-top: 20px; text-align: center; font-size: 80%; color: grey;&#34;&gt;Google, Inc. 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to count instances of an IP address in a log file</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-an-ip-address-in-a-log-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-an-ip-address-in-a-log-file/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a quick and painless way to determine what IP addresses used our web app the most and stumbled across this excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://encodable.com/tech/blog/2008/12/17/Count_IP_Addresses_in_Access_Log_File_BASH_OneLiner&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;I got reminded of the power of the command-line interface and that often, I underestimate the way these commands are supposed to make a sysad&#39;s life easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So here&#39;s a quick tip for counting unique visitors to your web app. Locate your web app&#39;s log file and do a quick scan of the last few lines. In my case, this is what I saw:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;112.198.79.223 - - [10/Jul/2010:00:57:29 -0400] &#34;POST /v2/api/execute.php?method=upload_time&amp;amp;ver=win1.1.15 HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 116 &#34;-&#34; &#34;Mozilla/5.0&#34;&lt;br /&gt;117.241.112.254 - - [10/Jul/2010:00:57:30 -0400] &#34;POST /v2/api/execute.php?method=timestat&amp;amp;ver=win1.1.15 HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 288 &#34;-&#34; &#34;Mozilla/5.0&#34;&lt;br /&gt;80.249.84.105 - - [10/Jul/2010:00:57:29 -0400] &#34;POST /v2/api/execute.php?method=offtime&amp;amp;ver=win1.1.15 HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 19 &#34;-&#34; &#34;Mozilla/5.0&#34;&lt;br /&gt;117.241.112.254 - - [10/Jul/2010:00:57:32 -0400] &#34;POST /v2/api/execute.php?method=get_defaults&amp;amp;ver=win1.1.15 HTTP/1.1&#34; 200 77 &#34;-&#34; &#34;Mozilla/5.0&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this log format, the IP address appears first, so we will only need to get the first set of characters, separated by a space. In order to count instances of an IP address, we sort the IP addresses so similar IP addresses are grouped together, then count them. Then we sort them again so that the sums are arranged. The number of unique IPs may give you pages of standard output, so optionally, if you only want to see which IP addresses accessed the web app the most, we look at the top results only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So these are the commands used, piped one after the other, with the output:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[root@server2 ~]# cat /var/log/httpd/access_ssl.log | awk &#39;{print $1}&#39; | sort | uniq -c | sort -nr | head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;71612 216.157.78.237&lt;br /&gt; 34094 120.28.205.244&lt;br /&gt; 30091 119.93.97.54&lt;br /&gt; 25078 120.28.214.104&lt;br /&gt; 18949 120.28.195.151&lt;br /&gt; 17929 58.107.64.40&lt;br /&gt; 14877 212.98.174.235&lt;br /&gt; 14752 117.241.112.143&lt;br /&gt; 14429 120.28.247.74&lt;br /&gt; 12864 117.241.113.183&lt;br /&gt; [root@server2 ~]#&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Happy counting, err reporting!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putty on my phone FTW! ISP was acting up and was able to get Apache to work sometime past 3pm. Post-mortem shortly.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/putty-on-my-phone-ftw-isp-was-acting-up-and-was-able-to-get-apache-towork-sometime-past-3pm.-post-mortem-shortly./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/putty-on-my-phone-ftw-isp-was-acting-up-and-was-able-to-get-apache-towork-sometime-past-3pm.-post-mortem-shortly./</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Gravity&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; src=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/Gravity.jpg.scaled500-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobileways.de/gravity&#34;&gt;Gravity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Systems Administrator @37signals (Podcast)</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/being-a-systems-administrator-37signals-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 22:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/being-a-systems-administrator-37signals-podcast/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt; I use Basecamp a lot. Kudos to these guys for making my job as a Systems Administrator more bearable than usual. :p&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal; font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&#34;margin-top: 10px; margin-left: 1px; border-left-width: 4px !important; border-left-style: solid !important; border-left-color: #dddddd !important; padding-left: 10px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 style=&#34;font-size: 1.17em;&#34;&gt;Episode #12: Being a Systems Administrator at 37signals&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time: 22:50 | 04/13/2010 | &lt;a name=&#34;#episode12&#34; href=&#34;http://37assets.s3.amazonaws.com/audio/37signals_podcast_ep12-04_13_10.mp3&#34;&gt;Download MP3&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/podcast/#episode12&#34;&gt;Link to this episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark, Joshua, and John on life as a 37signals Sys Admin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sys Admin team discusses hosting the 37signals apps, working with programmers, helping support, telecommuting, dealing with vendors, improving speeds in Europe, and more. Related links:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rackspace.com&#34;&gt;Rackspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dell.com/&#34;&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dcenvironments.com/general_redundancy.htm&#34;&gt;Definitions: Redundancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rethink.unspace.ca/2007/3/8/facebook-just-gets-it-right&#34;&gt;Facebook Just Gets It Right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/podcast/#episode12&#34;&gt;37signals.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How big is a Yottabyte? - Holy Kaw!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-big-is-a-yottabyte-holy-kaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 07:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-big-is-a-yottabyte-holy-kaw/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And I got a long way to go. My next step doesn&#39;t happen in the next couple of months, and that&#39;s when I purchase a terabyte external hard drive for storage purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&#34;margin-top: 10px; margin-left: 1px; border-left-width: 4px !important; border-left-style: solid !important; border-left-color: #dddddd !important; padding-left: 10px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember back in the 1970s when 200MB was the size of a tire? Now we live in a world of gigbytes and terabytes, and the future will bring zettabytes and yottabytes in everyday life. Hello, future!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://holykaw.alltop.com/how-big-is-a-yottabyte-0#&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/media_httpensdigitalk_fmGoh.jpg.scaled500-154x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 14px; color: #ffffff;&#34;&gt;k to view large&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Download full size (80 KB)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.digitalkamera.com/how-big-is-a-yottabyte-infograph/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Digital Kamera&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tons of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.alltop.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://holykaw.alltop.com/how-big-is-a-yottabyte-0#comment&#34;&gt;holykaw.alltop.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter - Decentralize the web with Diaspora</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kickstarter-decentralize-the-web-with-diaspora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kickstarter-decentralize-the-web-with-diaspora/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kck.st/9QC2zk&#34;&gt;http://kck.st/9QC2zk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IMO, this is the answer to all your privacy-related concerns on Facebook. Can&amp;#8217;t wait til it launches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Web Design Goes Straight to Hell - The Oatmeal</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-a-web-design-goes-straight-to-hell-the-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 03:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-a-web-design-goes-straight-to-hell-the-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/design_hell&#34;&gt;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/design_hell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well I&amp;#8217;ll be! Just exactly how things go (but not with our current company, thank God). Goes to @Bambi @Lee @jenipur and all my web designer friends. ^_^&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using non-standard SSH port with TortoiseSVN</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with-tortoisesvn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 05:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with-tortoisesvn/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Some of my students reported that they were having problems connecting to their repositories using &lt;a href=&#34;http://tortoisesvn.tigris.org/&#34;&gt;TortoiseSVN&lt;/a&gt;. At first, quick checks from my end didn&#39;t reveal what caused these, but I realized soon that it wasn&#39;t a server issue. It seems like the client software that they were using (TortoiseSVN) didn&#39;t know what to make of the &lt;code&gt;svn+ssh://[user]@[ip]:[port]/[repo]&lt;/code&gt; URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rabbitvcs.org/&#34;&gt;RabbitVCS&lt;/a&gt; on my Linux boxen and get the same &#34;Network connection closed unexpectedly&#34; message. A colleague at work suggested that since a non-standard port for SSH is used, I should modify my &lt;code&gt;/home/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/.subversion/config&lt;/code&gt; , look for the &lt;span style=&#34;font-family: monospace;&#34;&gt;[tunnels] &lt;/span&gt;section, and append &lt;code&gt;-p [port number]&lt;/code&gt; for the svn tunnel named ssh. Since this particular repository is just one among the dozens I access, I can&#39;t modify the default svn tunnel. Instead, I added a custom tunnel for each of the servers that use non-standard SSH ports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the repo that my students were trying to access, I used &lt;code&gt;ssh2212 = $SVN_SSH ssh -q -o ControlMaster=no -p 2212&lt;/code&gt;. So the URL now looks like &lt;code&gt;svn+ssh2212://[user]@[ip]:2212/[repo]&lt;/code&gt; and I was able to connect successfully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Windows, there are several ways to do this. Since the OS doesn&#39;t have a native SSH client executable, users will rely on Cygwin, Putty, or on TortoisePlink.exe (in newer versions of TortoiseSVN).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can try any of the following solutions (they&#39;re all searchable in the Internets) and see if you can get around the problem. I&#39;ve tried them all on a Windows guest OS on VirtualBox and only the last three solutions worked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Using Putty: Use saved session name from Putty in the URL: &lt;code&gt;svn+ssh://[user]@[saved putty session name]/[repo]&lt;/code&gt;. Make sure that you configure the session to already use the correct port. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Using Putty: Alternately, use &lt;code&gt;IP:port&lt;/code&gt; format for the Putty saved session name so that you still use the &lt;code&gt;svn+ssh://[user]@[ip]:[port]/[repo]&lt;/code&gt; URL format, but you&#39;re actually calling the saved session name. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;c. Using client packaged with Tortoise. In TortoiseSVN settings -&amp;gt; Network, change SSH client to &lt;code&gt;&#34;C:Program FilesTortoiseSVNbinTortoisePlink.exe&#34;&lt;/code&gt; and use standard &lt;code&gt;svn+ssh://[user]@[ip]:[port]/[repo]&lt;/code&gt; URL. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;d. Same as d., but for the SSH client, append &lt;code&gt;-P [port number]&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;e. Using a wrapper script, such as the one provided &lt;a href=&#34;http://unformatt.com/news/non-standard-ssh-ports-with-tortoise-svn/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (excellent solution btw), and use it as the SSH client executable in TortoiseSVN settings -&amp;gt; Network.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hope any one of these work for you. As an inside joke from one of my sysad friends, it was also suggested that I save myself the troubles and just log in to the server and revert to the default SSH port. LOL.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebug Lite 1.3.0 beta /via sitepoint tech times</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/firebug-lite-1.3.0-beta-via-sitepoint-tech-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/firebug-lite-1.3.0-beta-via-sitepoint-tech-times/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getfirebug.com/releases/lite/beta/&#34;&gt;http://getfirebug.com/releases/lite/beta/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Man, it&amp;#8217;s about time! Some Firebug functionality on my other browsers would be awesome!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[repost] System for staying on top of priorities</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/repost-system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/repost-system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve tried a lot of productivity tools to get better control over my ever-bloating task lists, and none have been as effective for me, as using Gmail with the GTDInbox add-on, and Google Tasks. How I make these work for me is a result of several months of trials, using Google Tasks initially, then with custom labeling and automatic label switching with GTDInbox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal was simple, and that was to attain inbox zero at least once a day. GTDInbox allows me to mark or tag emails containing tasks with action, wait-for, delegated, and finished. After the emails are tagged, they get added to Google Tasks, so that I&amp;#8217;ll have an easy way to pull up a related email for a particular task. Lastly, these emails get archived, keeping the goal of inbox zero in mind, always.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What tools do you use, and have you already gotten into a rhythm of using these efficiently while working?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now I got the itch to shell script this [http://bash.org/?910094]</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/now-i-got-the-itch-to-shell-script-this-httpbash.org910094/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/now-i-got-the-itch-to-shell-script-this-httpbash.org910094/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content></content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System for staying on top of priorities</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2009 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of productivity tools to get better control over my ever-bloating task lists, and none have been as effective for me, as using Gmail with the GTDInbox add-on, and Google Tasks. How I make these work for me is a result of several months of trials, using Google Tasks initially, then with custom labeling and automatic label switching with GTDInbox.&lt;p /&gt; The goal was simple, and that was to attain inbox zero at least once a day. GTDInbox allows me to mark or tag emails containing tasks with action, wait-for, delegated, and finished. After the emails are tagged, they get added to Google Tasks, so that I&amp;rsquo;ll have an easy way to pull up a related email for a particular task. Lastly, these emails get archived, keeping the goal of inbox zero in mind, always.&lt;p /&gt; What tools do you use, and have you already gotten into a rhythm of using these efficiently while working?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates, finally!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/updates-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 16:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/updates-finally/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing lately: grokking Postfix (again), remapping sites for migration this week, and domain auctions.&lt;p /&gt;I also moved my non-tech &lt;a href=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net&#34;&gt;stuff&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://posterous.com&#34;&gt;posterous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export TweetDeck groups in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/export-tweetdeck-groups-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/export-tweetdeck-groups-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;If you have multiple installs of TweetDeck on different computers, I bet you wished there were ways to save the groups you set up.  These groupings are not saved in your Twitter profile, but are kept in a local database in your computer.  This means that for each install of TweetDeck, you will have to re-set up your groups, and any changes won&amp;rsquo;t replicate to your other installs.&lt;p /&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/ljKUO&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about copying TweetDeck settings in Windows explains this in detail, and I have been able to do the same for Ubuntu, replicating TweetDeck settings across 3 machines.  Just take note of some of the differences that I&amp;rsquo;m going to point out here.&lt;p /&gt;Adobe Air for Linux uses the &lt;code&gt;.appdata&lt;/code&gt; directory in your home directory, for profile settings, configurations, etc. In the computer that has your groups and is the source for the export, change working directory into &lt;code&gt;.appdata&lt;/code&gt;, and look for the &lt;code&gt;TweetDeckFast.{some hash here}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;jon@jedi-ntbk:~$ cd .appdata&lt;br /&gt;jon@jedi-ntbk:~/.appdata$ ls&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: rgb(51, 51, 255);&#34;&gt;Adobe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;cookie_file.txt&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: rgb(51, 51, 255);&#34;&gt;de.makesoft.twhirl.0EA062BC275E7ED1E6EC3762EFFD73C7158ADF33.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: rgb(51, 51, 255);&#34;&gt;jrcf_H7t6Ap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;jrcf_RA5I7w&lt;br /&gt;jrcf_wdLW48&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: rgb(51, 204, 0);&#34;&gt;Snippage.B28FB424FD6880E47B18D7D649F6CC93BDE9B29B.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: rgb(51, 51, 255);&#34;&gt;TweetDeckFast.F9107117265DB7542C1A806C8DB837742CE14C21.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;jon@jedi-ntbk:~/.appdata$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;Change directory to the one that says &lt;code&gt;TweeDeckFast&lt;/code&gt; and list the contents. Change directory into &lt;code&gt;Local Store&lt;/code&gt; and you should find two files that has your username.  In my case, they are&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;preferences_jjdoblados.xml&lt;br /&gt;td_26_jjdoblados.db&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;Simply copy these two files to any target machine in the same directory where you got them.  Make sure that TweetDeck is closed before copying.  When done copying, start TweetDeck and you will have all of your groups intact!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in 5.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-in-5./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-in-5./</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;So I renewed my domain name earlier and thought about writing more just to balance the traffic I get for the domain, which is around 20% HTTP, and 80% SMTP.&lt;p /&gt;Mail is obviously important, and since I had Gmail handle mails, everything’s been very stress free. Google just works, right? So migrating once again back to Blogger for my rant pages is now a no-brainer. Stay tuned for more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIIX3 cannot attach drive to the Secondary Master</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/piix3-cannot-attach-drive-to-the-secondary-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/piix3-cannot-attach-drive-to-the-secondary-master/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virtualbox.org&#34; title=&#34;VirtualBox&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; for my server experimenting requirements, and it&amp;rsquo;s just great!  Just this morning, I got an error message when I started an FC8 virtual machine.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;PIIX3 cannot attach drive to the Secondary Master.&lt;br /&gt;VBox status code: -102 (VERR_FILE_NOT_FOUND).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.virtualbox.org/viewtopic.php?p=805&#34; title=&#34;PIIX3 cannot attach drive to the Secondary Master&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt; in the forums explains that the virtual machine was looking for a disk that was supposed to be mounted and could not find it.  I was using an external DVD drive and had removed it before I shut down the VM.&lt;p /&gt;You&amp;rsquo;d get the same problem if you set up a VM to use a mounted disk or some other mass storage device.  To fix this, simply uncheck the non-existent devices in the VM settings while the VM is powered down.  Alternately, you can plug the devices back in before you power up the VM.&lt;p /&gt;If after doing these steps you still get the error, check if the devices do get mounted and are accessible from the host as you may be dealing with broken or non-functional devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arping -s</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/arping-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/arping-s/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;arping saves the day once again!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Adobe Air apps on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 23:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I was trying to remove AgileAgenda after fiddling with it for a week and deciding it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to cut it.  There&amp;rsquo;s no Adobe Air Application &amp;ldquo;uninstaller&amp;rdquo; in the menu, and search engine results usually point to Mac lurv, or not.  Seems like uninstalling Air apps on OSX is bloody.&lt;p /&gt;I did find this nice &lt;a href=&#34;http://digitalspaghetti.me.uk/index.php/DigitalSpaghetti/Remove_Adobe_AIR_in_linux&#34;&gt;article on removing Adobe Air on Linux&lt;/a&gt; and gave it (well parts of it) a shot.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;jon@jedi-ntbk:/opt$ sudo dpkg -S /opt/*&lt;br /&gt;adobeair-enu: /opt/Adobe AIR&lt;br /&gt;com.agileagenda.agileagenda.f49a4d8df78a1fee7a3be440dc11bab18d922274.1: /opt/AgileAgenda&lt;br /&gt;de.makesoft.twhirl.0ea062bc275e7ed1e6ec3762effd73c7158adf33.1: /opt/twhirl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;I merely copied the package name of AgileAgenda, ran &lt;code&gt;dpkg&lt;/code&gt; with the right switches, and pfft app&amp;rsquo;s gone!  Menu entry seems to be gone too.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;jon@jedi-ntbk:/opt$ sudo dpkg -P com.agileagenda.agileagenda.f49a4d8df78a1fee7a3be440dc11bab18d922274.1&lt;br /&gt;(Reading database &amp;hellip; 128350 files and directories currently installed.)&lt;br /&gt;Removing com.agileagenda.agileagenda.f49a4d8df78a1fee7a3be440dc11bab18d922274.1 &amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;jon@jedi-ntbk:/opt$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Plesk Blues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-plesk-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-plesk-blues/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this problem with Plesk since I started relying heavily on it in 2006.  For some reason, after you&amp;rsquo;ve added your client, allocated IP address to client&amp;rsquo;s pool, added a domain, and selecting physical hosting, you get the message:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;posterous_short_quote&#34;&gt;Unable to update hosting preferences: hosting update is failed: object ID is invalid&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After getting this error, you get the domain listed, but still requiring set up.  Attempting to complete physical hosting setup will give you same result.  First thing you&amp;rsquo;d want to look at would be some log.  For all of its peculiarities, Plesk has an organized directory tree.  Look at &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/psa/admin/logs/httpsd_error_log&lt;/code&gt; and you&amp;rsquo;ll see that skeleton or template is missing.&lt;p /&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know exactly where to get the &lt;code&gt;.skel&lt;/code&gt; directory, but some Googling led me to &lt;code&gt;/home/httpd/vhosts/.skel/0&lt;/code&gt;, which after some directory skimming, I was able to verify as non-existent.  I simply copied an existing &lt;code&gt;.skel&lt;/code&gt; directory from one of our other servers and redid the physical hosting setup.&lt;p /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can find out what&amp;rsquo;s causing the &lt;code&gt;.skel&lt;/code&gt; directory to cease to exist.  This is a fairly easier to solve issue.  I so need to start looking in forums of Parallels (formerly SWSoft) for solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my must-have&#39;s for firefox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-must-haves-for-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2007 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-must-haves-for-firefox/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;in not so significant order:&lt;p /&gt;1. mm3-proxyswitch&lt;br /&gt;2. regular expressions tester&lt;br /&gt;3. &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us&#34;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;4. greasemonkey&lt;br /&gt;4. better gmail&lt;br /&gt;5. firegpg&lt;br /&gt;6. downThemAll&lt;br /&gt;7. save as image &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>you&#39;re looking good, opensource!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/youre-looking-good-opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/youre-looking-good-opensource/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;div&gt;opensource gets another breakthrough today, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://canonical.com&#34;&gt;canonical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computerworld.com/action/article.do?command=viewArticleBasic&amp;amp;articleId=9048520&amp;amp;intsrc=news_ts_head&#34;&gt;launches&lt;/a&gt; launchpad personal package archive (PPA), an ubuntu linux developers service intended to extend collaboration in software development and give the community equal opportunity to build and package code for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com&#34;&gt;ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; on the desktop, server, and for mobile applications.&lt;p /&gt;great news for those itching to modify packages and contribute to the furtherance of opensource! users can make changes on packages of their choice, and these will be published in the PPA system, somewhat like a special repository.&lt;p /&gt;aptly, users get the updates from the system whenever new versions of the packages become available.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plesk won&#39;t start after tweaking mysql</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plesk-wont-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plesk-wont-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve had this happen to me again the other week and as always, felt like kicking myself for not remembering.&lt;p /&gt;we do a lot of performance tuning on mysql, and as a result, we almost always manage to get plesk mangled. not its fault, it just can&amp;rsquo;t run without mysql, doh.&lt;p /&gt;not of preference, but plesk happens to be there to make handling domains easier, as a single editing point when you want to change something and not worry about missing something out.&lt;p /&gt;so there&amp;rsquo;s a custom /etc/my.cnf that we use, and with changes to limits done (both on mysql and via ulimit), you&amp;rsquo;d think that a reload of mysqld would do. (we use InnoDB btw)&lt;p /&gt;normally, that&amp;rsquo;s all you need to have mysqld read off the new settings. if you&amp;rsquo;ve grown so dependent on plesk (like i have), you would not notice that mysqld didn&amp;rsquo;t actually start, and you will get an error when you load plesk, thinking that it&amp;rsquo;s a plesk error:&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;ERROR: PleskMainDBException&lt;br /&gt;MySQL query failed: Incorrect information in file: &amp;lsquo;./psa/misc.frm&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0: /usr/local/psa/admin/plib/common_func.php3:218&lt;br /&gt;db_query(string &amp;lsquo;select param, val from misc&amp;rsquo;)&lt;br /&gt;1: /usr/local/psa/admin/plib/common_func.php3:497&lt;br /&gt;get_param(string &amp;lsquo;mysql41_compatible&amp;rsquo;)&lt;br /&gt;2: /usr/local/psa/admin/plib/common_func.php3:394&lt;br /&gt;db_set_names()&lt;br /&gt;3: /usr/local/psa/admin/plib/common_func.php3:373&lt;br /&gt;db_connect_real(string &amp;lsquo;localhost&amp;rsquo;, string &amp;lsquo;admin&amp;rsquo;, string &amp;lsquo;*******&lt;em&gt;&amp;rsquo;, string &amp;lsquo;psa&amp;rsquo;)&lt;br /&gt;4: /usr/local/psa/admin/plib/common_func.php3:353&lt;br /&gt;db_connect()&lt;br /&gt;5: /usr/local/psa/admin/auto_prepend/auth.php3:82&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;even a restart of the plesk service will not work:&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[root@jedi]# /etc/init.d/psa restart&lt;br /&gt;Unable to query parameter by query select val from misc where param=&amp;lsquo;mysql41_compatible&amp;rsquo;: Incorrect information in file: &amp;lsquo;./psa/misc.frm&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;Unable to query parameter by query select val from misc where param=&amp;lsquo;mysql41_compatible&amp;rsquo;: Incorrect information in file: &amp;lsquo;./psa/misc.frm&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;Mysql error: Incorrect information in file: &amp;lsquo;./psa/key_history.frm&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;Processing config directory: /usr/local/psa/admin/conf/httpsd.&lt;/em&gt;.include&lt;br /&gt;Syntax OK&lt;br /&gt;/usr/local/psa/admin/bin/httpsdctl restart: httpd restarted&lt;br /&gt;ERROR 1033 (HY000) at line 1: Incorrect information in file: &amp;lsquo;./psa/sessions.frm&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;so this is a mysqld failing to start properly problem. to fix this, go to your mysql datadir and see if the sizes of your innodb log files match those in your .cnf. we usually set innodb_log_file_size = 256M and innodb_log_buffer_size = 256M in /etc/my.cnf.&lt;p /&gt;if they don&amp;rsquo;t match, stop mysqld, remove the ib_logfile0 and ib_logfile1 files, and start mysqld. be careful not to delete the ibdata1 or ibdata2 files or you lose your data. avoid using rm -r ib* (yea, wildcards and fast fingers give sysads their most stupefying moments)&lt;p /&gt;innodb will recreate the log files to match your .cnf and mysqld now becomes available for plesk.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>apt-get install kicker-kblogger</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apt-get-install-kicker-kblogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apt-get-install-kicker-kblogger/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;i don&amp;rsquo;t know with you, but i sometimes get the big push to update, if and when there&amp;rsquo;s something new (relatively, for me) to try.&lt;p /&gt;up for this week is my dabbling with stuff around kicker, and using kblogger to do some much needed updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelving trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/shelving-trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 15:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/shelving-trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I am officially bringing down my old tech blog after Holy Week. It has virtually become a sinkhole for all kinds of spam links and I have barely done anything to keep it up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Two&amp;nbsp;of the milestones that I&#39;ve unknowingly and unwittingly accomplished would include (in order, sorry):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;1. PR6 (yea, before it went offline for almost a month, and before Google deployed new algorithms sometime in Feb)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;2. 20,453 spam comments since I replaced my Wordpress.com API key sometime in Nov, 2006.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Beginning today, I will post techie stuff in this blog. It&#39;s the same ol&#39; renamed-a-hundred-times Blogger account, but with a different twist, now that it&#39;s using a personalized domain.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fear not, for&amp;nbsp;my old Blogger URI will still work. I&#39;m just not sure if you will be redirected or if there will be a rewrite. TODO: find out how Blogger does this.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will code for hosting</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/will-code-for-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2007 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/will-code-for-hosting/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I haven&#39;t done any coding in the last 4 months, which is really odd, because I never thought I&#39;d be this detached from programming. But I guess there&#39;s more to life than just developing or sustaining&amp;nbsp;passion for singulars. So much for trying not to stay generalist.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I have this personal domain now, and I&#39;m just glad google apps isn&#39;t as stiff with the applications anymore. The new interface totally rocks too. I just need to host the domain somewhere, for&amp;nbsp;sites and blogs and stuff.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re family, and you have a blogger account,&amp;nbsp;I can get you your custom domain working.&amp;nbsp;The default blogspot.com&amp;nbsp;publishing URL will&amp;nbsp;redirect to your custom domain, so I guess you won&#39;t be losing any visitors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not that sure about this, but I feel that there will be&amp;nbsp;noticeable changes in how your blog fares with SE&#39;s. Some SEO stuff that I&#39;ve picked up tell me you can&#39;t have same content in multiple&amp;nbsp;sites, similar to double-posting.&amp;nbsp;Seems like you can get penalized for that. Question is, will&amp;nbsp;the application of this redirecting exercise on blog a (that has already been indexed) be seen as&amp;nbsp;same content with blog b (which is where blog a will redirect to, if and only if you decide on a custom domain), from a search engine&#39;s view?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyway, I need a host. :)&amp;nbsp;Ironically, I handle dozens of hosts; but I can&#39;t get anywhere close to those (all dedicated servers..boohoohoo) without first coughing up lots of cash. Yea I suppose I could just code for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IP-hijacking and then some</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Almost a month of downtime. The servers were fine, but our IP addresses were not. Somehow, a system bug from one of the hosting companies caused our plan to include 14 other IP addresses, and we only maintained 6 as far as I am concerned.&lt;p /&gt;So the hosting company eventually understood what was happening and started asking the right questions. The bug is that the system allowed network administrators to assign to new clients, the IP addresses that have already been assigned to a current client.&lt;p /&gt;We spent crazy hours figuring out what happened. Since the domains were not loading our sites, and instead were redirecting to some domains we don’t own (real bad sites btw), we checked if .htaccess was modified and tested if it was working at all. I also did double checks on virtual host configurations and they all looked clean.&lt;p /&gt;I started thinking that it was a routing issue. We were not using the publicly routable IPs for the virtual hosts; instead, we used internal IPs as mapped to the firewall hardware. A lookup on the domain/s that we were being redirected to reported different IP addresses, which didn’t readily confirm my suspicions, but stressed the possibility of IP-hijacking.&lt;p /&gt;It’s not supposed to be taken in the context of BGP (border gateway protocol), as this is beyond me. Instead, think of your assumption over IP addresses that we’re using, to serve your websites. Sounds clear? I hope it does. I got pretty lost myself and it isn’t after deep digging at the hosting company’s end that their errors became apparent.&lt;p /&gt;So in the light of this realization, I’ve already moved the domains to some other hosting. Way too much work and way uncool.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using symbolic links for MySQL data files</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data-files/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Over a year ago, we had several servers configured for high traffic websites. A mispartioning resulted in /var becoming obscenely small, and it was only after MySQL crashed that we remembered this. We couldn’t afford more downtime if we dealt with the partition size problem, so I thought of quickly moving the data files into /home/mysql/{dbname} from /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} and create the symlink /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} -&amp;gt; /home/mysql/{dbname}.&lt;p /&gt;I was not certain of the performance implications to this. I heard from a fellow Linux junkie here that there may be a slight penalties in terms of access speed, since /home was meant for generic read/write, whereas /var was accessed in a very quick manner. Gotta verify this. But for now, I dwell in the power of symbolic links.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leeching for internet access</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/leeching-for-internet-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 05:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/leeching-for-internet-access/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Sure, my bosses do this all the time…in airports, hotel lobbies, and coffee shops. The mere act of “connecting” to an unsecured wireless network doubles as a necessity and as a leaching of sorts. Gotta love wireless. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hysteria</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hysteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hysteria/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Casey Kasem’s American Top 40 broadcast back in April 1988 is being streamed today over XM Radio. Def Leppard’s Hysteria is currently playing. Measures and measures of this classic hit flood my ears and I can’t help but smile. There must have been thousands of Icehouse, Def Leppard, and Nelson (to name a few) playbacks since I got them cassette and 8-track tapes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still think that the 1980’s was the best decade to grow in. All those crazy get-ups that now look fugly, the hair, and man, the dance moves! I did all those, and proudly at that. You wouldn’t blame me though, because like anyone who’s an 80’s kid, I’m peculiar. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote posting to Blogger Beta</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/remote-posting-to-blogger-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2006 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/remote-posting-to-blogger-beta/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a pretty slick Windows application that will allow you to post directly to your Blogger Beta account. The Firefox extension&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/1811/&#34;&gt;Deepest Sender&lt;/a&gt;, which allows posting to LJ, Blogger, and Wordpress, doesn&#39;t work with Blogger Beta&amp;nbsp;yet, so here&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://windowslivewriter.spaces.live.com/blog/cns!D85741BB5E0BE8AA!757.entry&#34;&gt;workaround&lt;/a&gt; that you can do meantime.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I prefer FOSS applications that run natively on GNU/Linux, but sometimes, you really need to use a platform where you are most productive. Writing stuff&amp;nbsp;from anywhere will mean doing this from my&amp;nbsp;Windows-run notebook. Not so much an issue, I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back and look what I checked out first!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/im-back-and-look-what-i-checked-out-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/im-back-and-look-what-i-checked-out-first/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Media_httpstaticflick_xzrba&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/media_httpstaticflick_xzrbA.jpg.scaled500-225x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is how the rear of the NetBay rack in my previous company looks like now. I headed back to CDO for Halloween vacation and was able to drop by the office to pick up some of my personal stuff. They&amp;rsquo;ve slapped in a Cisco router (where the yellow fibre cable hooks up to) and another L3 switch. The old firewall appliance is still there, reliable as ever. Cabling got more structured as well. Now that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about!&lt;p /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s crazy, but when you&amp;rsquo;ve got a baby that you built for years and had to leave one time or another, you get somewhat near it and it&amp;rsquo;s the first thing you look for!&lt;p /&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m proud of starting this and making things happen, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud of the team that continued to make things happen. Hats off to Ian, Gayang, Sherlabs, and Derf. You&amp;rsquo;re all the best! Make them drool! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Talk with Kopete</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-google-talk-with-kopete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-google-talk-with-kopete/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love Gaim, but the message to group feature isn&amp;rsquo;t readily available, even with gaim2-beta3, and this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me especially that I sometimes need to broadcast messages to team members over IM. Quick googling led me to Frank Spychalski&amp;rsquo;s very good &lt;a href=&#34;http://amazing-development.com/archives/2006/01/20/using-google-talk-with-kopete/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, which covers the essentials of configuring Google Talk on Kopete. For Ubuntu users, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have Kopete yet, you will need an internet connection to get the necessary packages.&lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ sudo apt-get install -y kopete qca-tls&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;The &lt;code&gt;qca-tls&lt;/code&gt; package will ensure that you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to connect using the default encryption protocol. After these packages install, start Kopete, and create a new Jabber account if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it yet. On the first tab, set up your Jabber ID to use your Gmail address:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jabber Id: &amp;lt;yourid&amp;gt;@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;On the &amp;ldquo;Connection&amp;rdquo; tab, use &lt;code&gt;talk.google.com&lt;/code&gt; as your server and  tick all the boxes like so:&lt;p /&gt;&lt;code&gt;[x] Use protocol encryption (SSL)&lt;br /&gt; [x] Allow plain-text password authentication&lt;br /&gt; [x] Override default server information&lt;br /&gt;     Server: [talk.google.com]         Port: [5223]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;p /&gt;Done!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Shift to Dapper Beta</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-shift-to-dapper-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-shift-to-dapper-beta/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Over the Holy Week, two of our home computer&amp;rsquo;s drives crashed, probably due to extensive user download, software installs, and malware. I had to do work on the laptop for a while, and since everyone in the house was itching for Internet access, I brought in a small IDE drive (roughly around 9Gb) that was mounted as slave on my office computer and popped that in the home computer. I had more than enough reasons to put Ubuntu back in there, and nobody would be complaining!&lt;p /&gt;Initially, I did a Breezy install and got all the needed packages up to-date. I wanted more so I changed all &amp;ldquo;breezy&amp;rdquo; references to &amp;ldquo;dapper&amp;rdquo; in &lt;code&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list&lt;/code&gt;, and did &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get dist-upgrade&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;abbr title=&#34;If I Remember Correctly&#34;&gt;IIRC&lt;/abbr&gt;, a total of 940+ packages had to be updated over an estimated 4 and a half hours. I left the computer running overnight, woke up at around 2 am and finished the installs and configurations.&lt;p /&gt;By morning, my wife, daughter, and sister-in-law, were able to use the computer for Internet surfing. I was able to recover their personal documents and multimedia files in the office; and just last night uploaded their files via an external USB-mounted hard drive that we use for mobile backups at work.&lt;p /&gt;I just love Dapper! The default Human theme&amp;rsquo;s colors and icons just totally rawk, and for a while, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to install another theme. Well my kid really likes Gartoon, and since her gcompris theme is already in Gartoon, I installed that theme as well.&lt;p /&gt;Mark Shuttleworth posted an announcement last night on planning Dapper+1. He divulged that the codename for the next release would be the &amp;ldquo;Edgy Eft&amp;rdquo;, saying that:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;posterous_medium_quote&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edgy is all about cutting edge, perhaps bleeding edge,&lt;br /&gt;brand new code and infrastructure. It will be the right time to bring in&lt;br /&gt;some seriously interesting but definitely edgy new technologies which&lt;br /&gt;lay the groundwork for the next wave of Ubuntu development.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;ldquo;bleeding edge&amp;rdquo; phrase is so Fedora Core, but IMO, Ubuntu won&amp;rsquo;t be like that in any way. Mark did say they were going to explore slightly unfamiliar territory that is out of the mainstream. This controlled exploration of technology will definitely bring Ubuntu as a GNU/Linux distribution to very, very high levels. The good stuff is just around the corner: Xen for virtualization (awesome GPLed technology that &lt;a href=&#34;rimuhosting.com&#34;&gt;rimuhosting.com&lt;/a&gt; has been using for years!), multi-architecture support, and the XGL that blows away just about everyone.&lt;p /&gt;To infinity, and beyond!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Viewed in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/best-viewed-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 09:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/best-viewed-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so dissapointing to see CSS that you really like &amp;ldquo;unrenderable&amp;rdquo; in IE. All I can say is get Firefox now!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting GNU/Linux through Competition</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/promoting-gnulinux-through-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 01:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/promoting-gnulinux-through-competition/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Met up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://baudizm.blogsome.com&#34;&gt;hardwyrd&lt;/a&gt; last night for preliminary competition planning. Also present were some of the pillars of GNU/Linux and FOSS in Northern Mindanao: Mr. Rem Taga of MPSC, Mr. Botp Peña of DMPC, and Mr. Vidor Balbon of Philcom. I hope to keep up with these guys considering that my GNU/Linux experience is so diversified and I&amp;rsquo;d have to polish skills on specific services, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve not even bothered tinkering with. Can you say Dovecot or Cyrus?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling ntpupdate</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disabling-ntpupdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disabling-ntpupdate/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This has been quite overdue, as I have been wanting to disable &lt;code&gt;ntpupdate&lt;/code&gt; since the Hoary release. What is &lt;code&gt;ntpupdate&lt;/code&gt; anyway? It&amp;rsquo;s the program that synchronizes your system time to an ntp server. &lt;abbr title=&#34;Network Time Protocol&#34;&gt;NTP&lt;/abbr&gt; is a protocol for synchronising the clocks of computer systems over packet-switched, variable-latency data networks. Since Ubuntu defaults to an ntp server somewhere in the www, and that it will attempt to sync on boot, it causes your machine to go through a much much longer startup process if an internet connection is not available at boot time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As I am lugging my lappy around a lot and I have not much of a need for the program, I knew I had to take it out and save me minutes of boot time. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ealden.net&#34;&gt;Ealden&lt;/a&gt; taught me how to remove &lt;code&gt;ntpupdate&lt;/code&gt;, and I suppose we can change the arguments to remove other programs as well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo update-rc.d -f ntpdate remove&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;update-rc.d&lt;/code&gt; will remove any system startup links for &lt;code&gt;/etc/init.d/ntpdate&lt;/code&gt;, or any instances of such in the different run levels. Usage is as follows:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;CodeRay&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  &lt;div class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;usage: update-rc.d [-n] [-f] &amp;lt;basename&amp;gt; remove&lt;br/&gt;       update-rc.d [-n] &amp;lt;basename&amp;gt; defaults [NN | sNN kNN]&lt;br/&gt;       update-rc.d [-n] &amp;lt;basename&amp;gt; start|stop NN runlvl [runlvl] [&amp;hellip;] .&lt;br/&gt;                -n: not really&lt;br/&gt;                -f: force&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-commerce Theory and Practice</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/e-commerce-theory-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/e-commerce-theory-and-practice/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;The coming finals in my e-commerce class got me browsing through piles of readings and notes and I realized that I have not fully appreciated e-commerce as I should have. A techie will know what digital signatures, catalogs, EDI&amp;rsquo;s, EFT&amp;rsquo;s, shopping carts, or SSL are, as applied to buying and selling online; but graduate school won&amp;rsquo;t even let you wallow in those. Instead, one gets tasked to relate e-commerce with business processes, and usually, look for solutions to support  business processes that e-commerce systems can&amp;rsquo;t support.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;TODO: a) Finish schematic diagram of a typical e-commerce (server/merchant  client/customer setup), b) complete customizations on osCommerce, c) harden authentication module, d) re-read security framework paper&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Extension for Firefox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/performance-extension-for-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/performance-extension-for-firefox/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://maxspark.bounceme.net&#34;&gt;Miko&lt;/a&gt; for the heads up. Check out this quite nice extension to Firefox, which will allow you to do updates without having to log in to your &lt;em&gt;numerous&lt;/em&gt; blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRASS</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2005 05:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/grass/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I had a good consultation session with my mentor last Saturday and I got great advise for my thesis. I&amp;rsquo;m planting my foot on GIS and applications, but the whole gamut of GIS is fairly large so I had to zero in on what I really wanted to focus on. Future research prospects on GIS led me to look up Geographic Resources Analysis Support System, commonly referred to as &lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.ath.cx/grass.html&#34;&gt;GRASS&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s so cool because for starters, it&amp;rsquo;s GPLed, and it will run on PostgreSQL. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily designed for Linux so I need to have &lt;a href=&#34;http://cygwin.com&#34;&gt;Cygwin&lt;/a&gt; run on the host that I will be using to interface with our Linux and non-Linux backends.&lt;p /&gt;In a nutshell, my thesis will be concentrating on GIS and data warehouse integration. Should there be an existing or current data warehouse for me to work on, I should be able to model the integration, using the appropriate schema. Should there be no data warehouse, I will have to model from scratch and present and enforce the design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on Dune</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-dune/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Ayt, it has been almost 10 years since I last watched Dune, but the plot, the lines&amp;hellip;they all came back to me when Matt posted the &lt;a href=&#34;http://divisionbyzero.blogsome.com/2005/08/07/on-fear/trackback/&#34;&gt;Litany of Fear&lt;/a&gt; on his website. Sure does bring back the awe I felt back then.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mysql woes</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 07:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-woes/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;In my quest to have my &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; blog resuscitated on our new p5 server so that I have something to use for my tech notes here at work as well as my MS requirements, I downloaded &lt;code&gt;MySQL-4.1.12-0.sles9.src.rpm&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mysql.com&#34;&gt;mysql.com&lt;/a&gt; in the hope of getting &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; running on our server. I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to install the darn thing. So I dl&amp;rsquo;ed &lt;code&gt;mysql-standard-4.1.12-unknown-linux-gnu-powerpc-glibc23.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt; and tried to use the binaries instead.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Viola! MySQL4.1.12 managed to run fine. The only problem is that even with all the usual accounts set up, including privileges and access rights to hosts set up correctly, wordpress can&amp;rsquo;t connect to the localhost database. Baaaaad!!! I ended up setting up the database on my trusty workstation and connected to that instead.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/claim/2huq9dg32&#34; rel=&#34;me&#34;&gt;Technorati Profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TODO 06/21</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/todo-0621/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 23:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/todo-0621/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finish Perl script that will import mail accounts to the new p5&lt;br/&gt;2. test alias IP and check what tcp_sync error means&lt;br/&gt;&lt;del&gt;3. do report on failed drive&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br/&gt;4. finalize schedule for website design consultation sessions with concern personnel&lt;br/&gt;&lt;del&gt;present designs to staff&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;del&gt;test clamv, amavis, &amp;amp; spamd configs&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;del&gt;get BERT report from MGC (from RIA)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;del&gt;start and try to finish configuration work on vclass&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;del&gt;start migrating email accounts to p5&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dumbass mode</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/dumbass-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/dumbass-mode/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m really hoping my old server gets up soon so i can download my shit out and start publishing again from our own servers here. all my scripts and applications that have been published are there, and most of the updates i did are there. the server went out even before i could sync my local copies. dumbass right? like why in the world would you be doing sync from a remote? ah, but i was &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; editing&amp;hellip;which is very very bad, imo.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s to hoping i can ssh back to that server again within the week. arghh!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTA setup</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mta-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2005 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mta-setup/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Pending Tjay&amp;rsquo;s visit, the reconfiguration of the Firebox will have to wait. It is important to have the CDO MTA running along with the HTTPD service in the P5-520 to be able to test the configuration  in more or less &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; conditions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Public IP: 203.177.75.33&lt;br/&gt;Public Alias: 203.177.75.37&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;TODO:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;1. set up of CDO MTA (HTTP and Postfix in one machine)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;2. DNS entries for cdo.cepalco.com.ph and mla.cepalco.com.ph&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;3. Verify if HTTP NAT and SMTP NAT will not have problems with multiple domains e.g. cepalco.com.ph (for HTTP) and cdo.cepalco.com.ph or mla.cepalco.com.ph (for SMTP) even if email addresses won&amp;rsquo;t change, like that of &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info@cepalco.com.ph&#34;&gt;info@cepalco.com.ph&lt;/a&gt; (with CDO MTA) and &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mgcamila@cepalco.com.ph&#34;&gt;mgcamila@cepalco.com.ph&lt;/a&gt; (with MLA MTA)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on emacs</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-emacs/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I have been trying to find time to install Emacs (temporarily) on jjd because I really want to get my planner running asap. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing that there is currently a good following for this editor, especially when add-on functionality is introducted: like &lt;a href=&#34;http://sacha.free.net.ph&#34;&gt;PlannerMode&lt;/a&gt;, which I believe will be a very good tool for me. It will allow the conception of collaborative input/development for tasks and projects.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;TODO:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;1. Install Emacs. On Ubuntu or any Debian-based distribution of Linux, type &amp;ldquo;apt-get  install emacs21&amp;rdquo;. On Windows, download and unpack the fullbin  archive from  &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/windows/emacs/emacs-21.3-fullbin-i386.tar.gz&#34;&gt;http://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/windows/emacs/emacs-21.3-fullbin-i386.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; (Unpack with Winzip/WinRAR).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;2. Start Emacs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;3. Make a directory for your Emacs Lisp files. Could be &lt;code&gt;~/elisp&lt;/code&gt; or  &lt;code&gt;C:elisp&lt;/code&gt;, or something like that.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;4. Download the stable version of Planner from  &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sacha.free.net.ph/notebook/emacs/sacha-stable.tar.gz&#34;&gt;http://sacha.free.net.ph/notebook/emacs/sacha-stable.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.  Unpack this in Emacs Lisp directory. Directories will be:  &lt;code&gt;~/elisp/emacs-wiki&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;~/elisp/planner&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;~/elisp/remember&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;5. Read through the instructions at  &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emacswiki.org/cgi-bin/wiki/PlannerModeQuickStart&#34;&gt;http://www.emacswiki.org/cgi-bin/wiki/PlannerModeQuickStart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  or the documentation at  &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sacha.free.net.ph/notebook/doc/dev/planner/planner-el.html&#34;&gt;http://sacha.free.net.ph/notebook/doc/dev/planner/planner-el.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sacha concurs with several other developers I know, in that Emacs is actually less intimidating than most people think it is. The bigger concern here now is getting the right time in space for playing around with Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more stf blues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-stf-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 23:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-stf-blues/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;1. test batch nos. 003442 (solomon) and 003444 (intra)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;2. per InvtID, pick up LotSerNbr(s) as required or set by needed quantity, and insert corresponding number of rows in LotSerT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;3. if i will require 3 serials, then the top non-zero LotSerNbr&#39;s will be retrieved and inserted accordingly to LotSerT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;4. during release by solomon, QtyOnHand will be set to 0 and a new row will be created for the same item, with QtyOnHand set to 1, indicating that the item has moved locations/sites. no modification/update necessary for intranet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;5. to supply the defaults for LotSerT, with appropriate values for LotSerNbr, LineNbr, LineRef, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>changes for stf</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/changes-for-stf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 23:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/changes-for-stf/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;1. stf transactions (data entry) over the intranet had problems when solomon tries to do a &#34;release now&#34; action.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;2. further analysis by LPE shows that the intranet module hasn&#39;t completely emulated the &#34;transfers&#34; transaction of solomon, in that the items transferred did not have corresponding serialized entries in LotSerT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;3. relations: Batch 1:1 TrnsfrDoc, Batch 1:n INTran, INTran 1:n LotSerT&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;4. look up for LotSerT.LotSerNbr will come from LotSerMst (where all serialized items are built up)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;5. &lt;code&gt;SELECT LotSerNbr FROM LotSerMst WHERE InvtId=&#39;1002122&#39; AND SiteId=&#39;LOG-MCS&#39; AND Status = &#39;A&#39; AND WhseLoc=&#39;MAIN&#39; AND QtyOnHand &amp;gt; 0 ORDER BY LotSerNbr ASC&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>soon-to-be-IBM-customer</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/soon-to-be-ibm-customer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2004 05:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/soon-to-be-ibm-customer/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;What a month it has been! It was my first time to do facilitating work relevant to equipment acquisition, and everything has been so cooperative (thank God!). The only thing that&amp;rsquo;s keeping me from getting giddy with anticipation over the delivery of those servers is the fact that the PO hasn&amp;rsquo;t been issued yet. It seems to me that Purchasing people have this degree of power over everyone else, in the sense that they can always mull over our longing to have stuff bought right away and decide to do delaying tactics just for the hell of it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I wished we had arrived earlier for the second day round of technical sessions of the 1st ICT summit held here. Flight delays brought about by the big typhoon caused major shifting of schedules and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure a lot of people missed the sessions they signed up for, except maybe for those ICT die-hards who spent three whole days there and attended all the tracks they could. &lt;a href=&#34;http://villageidiotsavant.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;Dominique Cimafranca&lt;/a&gt; of IBM was to talk about Data Management Storage Solutions and we missed his session! It would have been nice if we got him to address some of our concerns, yada yada yada.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hope IBM delivers before the year ends. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ack...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ack.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2004 07:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jon Doblados</author>
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ack.../</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;m down to my last two modules before this quarter ends. the first modules have been deployed and parallel-tested, with just a bit of flak coming from &amp;ldquo;concerned&amp;rdquo; users (since they&amp;rsquo;re sooo used to stand-alone applications, they think that intranet applications would have the same degree of difficulty, more or less). hell my scripts generate 5k lines of values each for 10 different select elements and they wanted a more &amp;ldquo;user-friendly&amp;rdquo; output. tsk. :P&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;i posted a concern of mine on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/ossa-ph/&#34;&gt;Open Source Software Association - Phils.&lt;/a&gt; message board and got this for an answer from one of &amp;ldquo;them&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;first of all, let me iterate on few keypoints, branded computers like the IBM/RS6000 is not TOY, and is not Cheap, for that reason it is should be running critical applications, coz your paying for it, i dont see a reason why should turn in into a frankenstein, i suggest you focus on the problem at hand. linux and freebsd are fun to play with, but it always been a common practice not to play on production environment.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;my reply:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;posterous_medium_quote&#34;&gt;I agree that the RS6000 B50 is not a &amp;ldquo;TOY&amp;rdquo; as you call it. It has been running several of our most critical applications since we acquired it. These applications are to be ported to another machine in a month (on an HP NetServer), which will leave the B50 unused. I am currently running intranet applications on an old P3 machine and am offered to use the B50 for these applications, which are very much critical as far as we are concerned as the bulk of data entry and processing occurs via intranet. Rest assured, we are not &amp;ldquo;Frankenstein-ing&amp;rdquo; boxes here, as we all know the value of our machines. I&amp;rsquo;m just opening myself to options; thus this research. Thanks for the suggestions though.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;oh well&amp;hellip;some people seem more aghast when i go tell them that we have an IBM server here, much more when i ask them if i could try and run FreeBSD on it. they all think it&amp;rsquo;s sacrilegious or sumthin. so blame me, i&amp;rsquo;m finding a good use for it :P&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;*yawn&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>