<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Triggered</title>
    <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Triggered</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 22:08:06 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://triggered.doblados.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/pages/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 22:08:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/pages/home/</guid>
      <description>Some text goes here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, Facebook</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/goodbye-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 21:36:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/goodbye-facebook/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, I started getting reminders to enable Facebook Protect, some feature meant to protect certain people who may be targeted by folks up to no good or even other social media platforms. Meta specifically mentions accounts of politicians or candidates who may require additional protection during elections.
So the funny thing is that I&amp;rsquo;m no politician, and I barely even post about politics. I avoid doing so as much as I can, for my sanity&amp;rsquo;s sake, and well, for friendships&#39; sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>A Christian, husband, father, watered-down g33k, 80s kid, cloud platforms, k8s, devops, and all-around janitor. Heart survivor, now with new plumbing and taking each day as it comes, all glory to God! 
Attribution Notes Copyright 2021 - All content, i.e. photos, videos, and other media, are mine, unless otherwise specified. Content in this site are protected by a Creative Commons Attribution-Non-Commercial 3.0 License. Feel free to view from this blog, and to link to the different posts as long as you retain the original link of the resources you use and do not make commercial use of any of the contents here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
