<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Galleries on </title>
    <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/galleries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Galleries on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/galleries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our daughter&#39;s happy 13th</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/our-daughters-happy-13th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/our-daughters-happy-13th/</guid>
      <description>Our daughter asked to celebrate her birthday a day ahead, with her 8th grade classmates. They had water gun and balloon fights, and bags of holi powder to throw around. They also played frisbee and volleyball on the village streets and watched scary movies when it got dark. There were lots of food too! I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it was going to be so much fun! Thanks to my dear wife for making preparations, especially the cooking and baking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2013</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2013/</guid>
      <description>We decided to go to Cebu and spend Christmas this year with my parents and brother. I suppose it has been more than 15 years since we last celebrated Christmas together. The trip was really stressful because it was passenger season. But it was really worth lugging heavy bags since the cousins got to goof off and have a lot of fun, and the grandparents got to see all of their grandchildren in one place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civic Stories - December 2012</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/civic-stories---december-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/civic-stories---december-2012/</guid>
      <description>I sort of miss being in the backseat. A lot of my goofing off years have been conducted within the confines of the passenger doors, backside of the front seats, and the backseat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honor God, Make Disciples</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/honor-god-make-disciples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/honor-god-make-disciples/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, I started attending this workshop/training for leaders at Victory CDO. It&amp;rsquo;s called Training for Victory (T4V), and it was a once-a-week engagement for about 10 weeks; although it took longer than that because of several holidays around that time. We graduated and were commissioned, not as pastors, but as servants who will lead people to take on a personal relationship with Christ. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace, I was also the recipient of the Award for Excellence during the ceremonies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kids on Photobooth</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</guid>
      <description>Miguel and Isabel goofing off in front of the laptop. They discovered the 4-shot option and started taking pictures by themselves.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t mind if I start posting more pictures here. I’ve really been keeping myself from posting these to Facebook, which was the natural tendency, no thanks to endless egging by the family. But no. It’s been a couple of years now that I’ve wanted to steer clear from FB when it comes to posting pictures; especially of family.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covered area expansion project</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/covered-area-expansion-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 22:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/covered-area-expansion-project/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve recently decided to cover the whole area where the outdoor canteen was and turn into an activity area. I was supposed to have completed the electrical wiring last Saturday but the materials were delivered at noon and I was already quite content with just spending the afternoon with the kids.
Will post more pictures this week as we try and finish the fascia, flooring, and electrical works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GWF Team CDO</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/gwf-team-cdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 08:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/gwf-team-cdo/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way since 2006; but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until 2009 that we had a solid team based in CDO. We&amp;rsquo;re not even all sysads, but we love the fact that besides Romar, who has been my friend from way back, it was only after Carlo and Alvin joined GWF did we learn where they&amp;rsquo;re from.
Looking forward to another TBA at the later part of this year, hopefully with more people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musuan Trip</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/musuan-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/musuan-trip/</guid>
      <description>We went to Musuan, in Bukidnon. It&amp;rsquo;s home to the &amp;ldquo;boob&amp;rdquo; mountain, hence the name &amp;ldquo;Musuan&amp;rdquo;. Our dear Aunt Celia passed on and relatives from all over convened in CMU (where she was administrator). We spent the night in RR Family Spring Resort in Tubigon, border of Maramag, and after the wake swam in the fresh water pools, braving the intense cold. :D</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
