<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Work on Aggregated Thinking</title>
    <link>http://jon.doblados.net/tags/community-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Work on Aggregated Thinking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 11:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jon.doblados.net/tags/community-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sign up for the first MapUp this 2014!</title>
      <link>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/sign-up-for-first-mapup-this-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 11:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/sign-up-for-first-mapup-this-2014/</guid>
      <description>This is our opening salvo for the year. Since we started last year, GBG Cagayan de Oro has been receiving a lot of good feedback from the locals. But we&amp;rsquo;ve put our attention on the areas where we can improve, and I really believe that this mapping event is a step towards that direction. A well-mapped city improves tourism and support services. It also opens numerous planning opportunities for the local government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community work, with Google.</title>
      <link>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/community-work-with-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 18:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/community-work-with-google/</guid>
      <description>Community work, with Google.
Thank you mentors +Aileen Apolo +Chelle Gray +Vince Tabor and +Mohd Hadi Shafie Awang Othman!
Thank you to my counterparts +Jerome Locson +Johnn Mendoza +Katherine Yap +Dulce Rose Lada +Rosario Juan +Juned Sonido and +Avel Manansala for inspiring me to do more for the community.
Thank you to our GDG counterpart +Josan Astrid Dometita for your exuberance and continuing support for the &amp;ldquo;old ones&amp;rdquo; hehe
+AMDG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just yesterday, August 7, we had our first academe-focused event, which we called &#34;Enhancing Research...</title>
      <link>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/just-yesterday-august-7-we-had-our/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 22:13:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/just-yesterday-august-7-we-had-our/</guid>
      <description>Just yesterday, August 7, we had our first academe-focused event, which we called &amp;ldquo;Enhancing Research with Google Technologies&amp;rdquo;. We partnered with the Kinaadman Research Center (KRC) and through the auspices of Dr. Ester Raagas, Director of the KRC, 67.7% of the entire university faculty population who were also research grantees, were able to learn about Google Drive.
The workshop focused on emphasizing the features of Google Drive and Google+ that are applicable for rapid data gathering, information sharing, collaborative work, and documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last July 20, we had our Diversity and Inclusion event for women, which we called &#34;Empowering Women ...</title>
      <link>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/last-july-20-we-had-our-diversity-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 21:17:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jon.doblados.net/posts/last-july-20-we-had-our-diversity-and/</guid>
      <description>Last July 20, we had our Diversity and Inclusion event for women, which we called &amp;ldquo;Empowering Women on the Go&amp;rdquo;. We worked with a local JCI chapter, JCI Bai Lawanen, and their members were able to listen to Harriet Fernandez, a director for an IT unit at Xavier University, and Shayryl Mae Ramos, a learning management system administrator, also at Xavier University.
The workshop was on Google Drive and on being able to balance work and home roles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
