<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hosting on </title>
    <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/hosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hosting on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to count instances of an IP address in a log file</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-an-ip-address-in-a-log-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-an-ip-address-in-a-log-file/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a quick and painless way to determine what IP addresses used our web app the most and stumbled across this excellent post. I got reminded of the power of the command-line interface and that often, I underestimate the way these commands are supposed to make a sysad&amp;rsquo;s life easier.
So here&amp;rsquo;s a quick tip for counting unique visitors to your web app. Locate your web app&amp;rsquo;s log file and do a quick scan of the last few lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>plesk won&#39;t start after tweaking mysql</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/plesk-wont-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/plesk-wont-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;ve had this happen to me again the other week and as always, felt like kicking myself for not remembering.
we do a lot of performance tuning on mysql, and as a result, we almost always manage to get plesk mangled. not its fault, it just can&amp;rsquo;t run without mysql, doh.
not of preference, but plesk happens to be there to make handling domains easier, as a single editing point when you want to change something and not worry about missing something out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IP-hijacking and then some</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</guid>
      <description>Almost a month of downtime. The servers were fine, but our IP addresses were not. Somehow, a system bug from one of the hosting companies caused our plan to include 14 other IP addresses, and we only maintained 6 as far as I am concerned.
So the hosting company eventually understood what was happening and started asking the right questions. The bug is that the system allowed network administrators to assign to new clients, the IP addresses that have already been assigned to a current client.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using symbolic links for MySQL data files</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data-files/</guid>
      <description>Over a year ago, we had several servers configured for high traffic websites. A mispartioning resulted in /var becoming obscenely small, and it was only after MySQL crashed that we remembered this. We couldn’t afford more downtime if we dealt with the partition size problem, so I thought of quickly moving the data files into /home/mysql/{dbname} from /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} and create the symlink /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} -&amp;gt; /home/mysql/{dbname}.
I was not certain of the performance implications to this.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
