<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on Triggered</title>
    <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on Triggered</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Apps Certified Deployment Specialist</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment-specialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment-specialist/</guid>
      <description>Back in November last year, the Apps Services Partner that I help with Google Apps Support told me that I was required to take the Google Apps for Work Deployment Specialist certification exam. I learned that Google was going to end the certification program and that I had to take the exam January 5, 2016. It turns out that they were simplifying the Partner Credential Program. All good!
So I took a crash review during the holiday break, read through all Google Apps for Work help articles I could get my hands on, and did self-study on Google Apps Administrator Fundamentals and Deployment Essentials.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sign up for the first MapUp this 2014!</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/sign-up-for-the-first-mapup-this-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/sign-up-for-the-first-mapup-this-2014/</guid>
      <description>This is our opening salvo for the year. Since we started last year, GBG Cagayan de Oro has been receiving a lot of good feedback from the locals. But we&amp;rsquo;ve put our attention on the areas where we can improve, and I really believe that this mapping event is a step towards that direction. A well-mapped city improves tourism and support services. It also opens numerous planning opportunities for the local government.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MySQL on Google Cloud Infrastructure Now Available</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Announcement here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community work, with Google.</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/community-work-with-google./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/community-work-with-google./</guid>
      <description>Community work, with Google. Thank you mentors Aileen Apolo, Chelle Gray, Vince Tabor, and Mohd Hadi Shafie Awang Othman!
Thank you to my counterparts Jerome Locson, Johnn Mendoza, Katherine Yap, Dulce Rose Lada, Rosario Juan, Juned Sonido, and Avel Manansala for inspiring me to do more for the community.
Thank you to our GDG counterpart Josan Astrid Dometita for your exuberance and continuing support for the &amp;ldquo;old ones&amp;rdquo; hehe
+AMDG</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shelving trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/shelving-trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 15:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/shelving-trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph/</guid>
      <description>I am officially bringing down my old tech blog after Holy Week. It has virtually become a sinkhole for all kinds of spam links and I have barely done anything to keep it up-to-date.
Two of the milestones that I&amp;rsquo;ve unknowingly and unwittingly accomplished would include (in order, sorry):
PR6 (yea, before it went offline for almost a month, and before Google deployed new algorithms sometime in Feb) 20,453 spam comments since I replaced my Wordpress.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
