<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albums on </title>
    <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/albums/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albums on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 19:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/albums/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uncle Bong in SG</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/uncle-bong-in-sg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 19:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/uncle-bong-in-sg/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over two decades since I last saw Uncle Bong. He would usually drop by Diamond Village in Novaliches, Quezon City to visit Lola Magding and my mother&amp;rsquo;s side of the family there. Back then, I was still in college, and I think he had also just started working, in the automotive industry.
He has since worked in cruise ships and it was a good stroke of fortune when he told me that they would be dry-docking in Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2019</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2019/</guid>
      <description>Dad and mum, Jen, Rob, Ava, and Rob&amp;rsquo;s parents spent the holidays here in Singapore. For once, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to take that many photos, but everything&amp;rsquo;s been awesome, especially Miguel&amp;rsquo;s and Ava&amp;rsquo;s gift opening.
Luckily, I managed to retrieve some of the most important photos, which are those of dining out! :D</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mae&#39;s Bday 2019</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/maes-bday-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 19:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/maes-bday-2019/</guid>
      <description>Dad and Mom dropped by Singapore to celebrate Mae&amp;rsquo;s birthday with us. It was two days of hectic shopping at the IMM, dining out, and cooking for an instant birthday party at the flat with colleagues at work and cousins in SG! Happy birthday, pangga!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CDO and Cebu 2019</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/cdo-and-cebu-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/cdo-and-cebu-2019/</guid>
      <description>These are some of the pictures I took during the CDO (Cagayan de Oro) and Cebu legs of our 2019 trip to the Philippines. In CDO, we did a joint birthday celebration for our kids since their birthdays are just a week apart. It was a great time to catch up with extended family and friends.
We then flew to Cebu City and spent a couple of days meeting family and close friends.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
