<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on Triggered</title>
    <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on Triggered</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#20</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/20/</guid>
      <description>My daughter turns 20 today. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t be any more proud of her. She&amp;rsquo;s been through a lot and though all that, she had her share of victories here and there, like getting her advanced diploma last year, and getting into University this year.You&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way, langga! Know that we will always be here to support you and your goals. Papa, Mama, and Miguel love you very much!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncle Bong in SG</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/uncle-bong-in-sg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 19:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/uncle-bong-in-sg/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over two decades since I last saw Uncle Bong. He would usually drop by Diamond Village in Novaliches, Quezon City to visit Lola Magding and my mother&amp;rsquo;s side of the family there. Back then, I was still in college, and I think he had also just started working, in the automotive industry.
He has since worked in cruise ships and it was a good stroke of fortune when he told me that they would be dry-docking in Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2019</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2019/</guid>
      <description>Dad and mum, Jen, Rob, Ava, and Rob&amp;rsquo;s parents spent the holidays here in Singapore. For once, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to take that many photos, but everything&amp;rsquo;s been awesome, especially Miguel&amp;rsquo;s and Ava&amp;rsquo;s gift opening.
Luckily, I managed to retrieve some of the most important photos, which are those of dining out! :D</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mae&#39;s Bday 2019</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/maes-bday-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 19:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/maes-bday-2019/</guid>
      <description>Dad and Mom dropped by Singapore to celebrate Mae&amp;rsquo;s birthday with us. It was two days of hectic shopping at the IMM, dining out, and cooking for an instant birthday party at the flat with colleagues at work and cousins in SG! Happy birthday, pangga!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CDO and Cebu 2019</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/cdo-and-cebu-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/cdo-and-cebu-2019/</guid>
      <description>These are some of the pictures I took during the CDO (Cagayan de Oro) and Cebu legs of our 2019 trip to the Philippines. In CDO, we did a joint birthday celebration for our kids since their birthdays are just a week apart. It was a great time to catch up with extended family and friends.
We then flew to Cebu City and spent a couple of days meeting family and close friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our daughter&#39;s happy 13th</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/our-daughters-happy-13th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/our-daughters-happy-13th/</guid>
      <description>Our daughter asked to celebrate her birthday a day ahead, with her 8th grade classmates. They had water gun and balloon fights, and bags of holi powder to throw around. They also played frisbee and volleyball on the village streets and watched scary movies when it got dark. There were lots of food too! I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it was going to be so much fun! Thanks to my dear wife for making preparations, especially the cooking and baking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2013</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2013/</guid>
      <description>We decided to go to Cebu and spend Christmas this year with my parents and brother. I suppose it has been more than 15 years since we last celebrated Christmas together. The trip was really stressful because it was passenger season. But it was really worth lugging heavy bags since the cousins got to goof off and have a lot of fun, and the grandparents got to see all of their grandchildren in one place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kids on Photobooth</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</guid>
      <description>Miguel and Isabel goofing off in front of the laptop. They discovered the 4-shot option and started taking pictures by themselves.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t mind if I start posting more pictures here. I’ve really been keeping myself from posting these to Facebook, which was the natural tendency, no thanks to endless egging by the family. But no. It’s been a couple of years now that I’ve wanted to steer clear from FB when it comes to posting pictures; especially of family.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimsum again</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/dimsum-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 22:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/dimsum-again/</guid>
      <description>We love Dimsum Diner, but we gotta start learning to keep ourselves from eating there too often. Why? We&amp;rsquo;re all high risk people, that&amp;rsquo;s why.
In this set, my sister-in-law was playing around with the camera settings, which explains the no-flash feature. Will try to do another shoot next time and will play with ISO and WB. Not a DSLR. Lugging that with us during family eat-outs is overkill.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
