<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aggregated Thinking</title>
    <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aggregated Thinking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:05:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Family Visits Singapura</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/family-visits-singapura/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/family-visits-singapura/</guid>
      <description>My parents and in-laws traveled to SG last September and it was truly memorable! I&amp;rsquo;m trying out some code to display a Google Photos album and it&amp;rsquo;s quite cool that I&amp;rsquo;m able to embed the album here.
Credits to Pavex for the great tool. He details out how to use it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the OFW leap</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/making-ofw-leap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 23:27:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/making-ofw-leap/</guid>
      <description>Over a year ago, a friend invited me to take on a job in Singapore. Whenever I get asked about working overseas, I’d say I’d give it some thought. And almost always, I wouldn’t give it any more than that, knowing that I wouldn’t be able to bear being away from family over extended periods of time.
Fast forward today and I&amp;rsquo;m doing the OFW bit and all, with my family in tow!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Apps Certified Deployment Specialist</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:03:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/google-apps-certified-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Back in November last year, the Apps Services Partner that I help with Google Apps Support told me that I was required to take the Google Apps for Work Deployment Specialist certification exam. I learned that Google was going to end the certification program and that I had to take the exam January 5, 2016. It turns out that they were simplifying the Partner Credential Program. All good!
So I took a crash review during the holiday break, read through all Google Apps for Work help articles I could get my hands on, and did self-study on Google Apps Administrator Fundamentals and Deployment Essentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Planning and Reports</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-planning-and-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 11:01:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-planning-and-reports/</guid>
      <description>In my previous employment, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any problems with submitting reports, practically because we used a time management/monitoring tool and the reports sort of generated by themselves. So when submitting daily reports isn&amp;rsquo;t the norm here at the unit, quarterly reports become quite tricky.
I&amp;rsquo;ve resorted to referring to Google Calendar as most of the stuff we do are usually scheduled. I&amp;rsquo;ve also thought of logging everything on a text file and have pelican publish this to my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Forward</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/moving-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 10:58:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/moving-forward/</guid>
      <description>In a month&amp;rsquo;s time, I would be transferring offices again. I started from a very technical department, under the administration cluster. A year and about 3 months later, I was given the privilege to transfer to one of the most influential and authoritative departments in the academic cluster. It was still a split engagement, with me going back and forth these two offices.
And for almost 2 years, I improved processes, handled, battled, and took care of hundreds of scenarios, cases, and situations that seem to always come with the university seasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering, I.T., Business Management, and Technopreneurship</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/engineering-it-business-management-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:51:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/engineering-it-business-management-and/</guid>
      <description>By 2016, five higher education institutes (HEIs) here in the Philippines will be integrating Technopreneurship as an offered elective for their Engineering programs. I am quite thankful that the higher education authorities have included my alma mater. More than being the center of trade in Northern Mindanao, the strategic location of our city makes it the best option for I.T. companies to build or expand in.
While the article specifically mentions entrepeneurship training for future engineers and that inclusion will be done in the Engineering curricula of 5 HEIs, I feel that this is severely limiting the beneficiaries (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Announces MacBook Pro Repair Extension Program for Video Issues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apple-announces-macbook-pro-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 10:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apple-announces-macbook-pro-repair/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t think there was going to be any hope for my early 2011 MacBook Pro, which had GPU-related problems after only about a year of use. The only obvious option I had was to buy a replacement laptop. But Apple seems to have been receiving a lot of reports that they&amp;rsquo;ve launched a repair progam that will fix the graphics problem for free.
If you bought a 15-inch or 17-inch MacBook Pro between early 2011 and end of 2013, as well as the first two generations of the Retina models, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Tales 0215</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/civic-tales-0215/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 10:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/civic-tales-0215/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got Static!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/got-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 10:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/got-static/</guid>
      <description>I just made the first step towards moving my whole blog to GitHub and going all static! Content is generated by Pelican, a static site generator, written in Python. Why GitHub, you ask? While I can always push the static content to any of my existing web hosts, there&amp;rsquo;s a touch of geekness in writing using my favorite editor and publishing by git commits and pushes; thus GitHub.
Also, it&amp;rsquo;s this year that I&amp;rsquo;m planning to pick up Python programming again, for devops reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Bonding for 2015</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/first-bonding-for-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 10:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/first-bonding-for-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racking Legacy Servers - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/racking-legacy-servers-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 10:33:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/racking-legacy-servers-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today we scheduled the racking of our old C-Class HP BladeSystem. It used to be wrapped in its own enclosure with wheels to boot, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to have it stand outside the cabinets. So we gave heads up and asked some guys to stay behind after office hours. Thanks to Mona, Eric, Jing, Tim, and Mark(?) for the assist!
Next up, the classic IBM BladeCenter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A better Monday than most</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/a-better-monday-than-most/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 10:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/a-better-monday-than-most/</guid>
      <description>The day&amp;rsquo;s just begun and I&amp;rsquo;m already up to my neck with work. But I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining. At least it&amp;rsquo;s server stuff and not some other crap!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work over Christmas Break 2014</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/work-over-christmas-break-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 23:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/work-over-christmas-break-2014/</guid>
      <description>10 years ago, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be complaining at all. I could live in a datacenter for days until the job&amp;rsquo;s done. But these days, my back aches are more pronounced, and fatigue sets in more easily. This is why it&amp;rsquo;s always great to have others helping out. Thanks to the CISO and PPO teams for making the migrations happen! I may have gotten older but the one thing that doesn&amp;rsquo;t change is the thrill of the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s no longer about the number of monitors you have</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/its-no-longer-about-number-of-monitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 12:08:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/its-no-longer-about-number-of-monitors/</guid>
      <description>Unlike in the late 90s to mid 2000s, desktop real estate is no longer constrained by the number of monitors you use. We now tout the number of virtual machines we have access to. In fact, my ailing MBP has managed to remain useful because remote access still enables me to work on all our VMs. Our applications and storage servers are all virtualized. Even some legacy systems have been replicated on VMs, allowing us to retire old and bulky server hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Reports Redux</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/crystal-reports-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 20:13:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/crystal-reports-redux/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d be saying this many years down the road, but here goes anyway. Crystal Reports is my friend. Yep. Apparently, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten my disdain for this piece of software. It&amp;rsquo;s amusing (well, for me) that the last version of Crystal Reports that I used for the systems I developed back in the late 90s, is the same version I was forced to use last week, in modifying an old report template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GBG Cagayan de Oro Turns One</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gbg-cagayan-de-oro-turns-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 16:17:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gbg-cagayan-de-oro-turns-one/</guid>
      <description>We had our 1st anniversary last week as a Google Business Group community. We look forward to doing more for Cagayan de Oro and the surrounding municipalities this year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our daughter&#39;s happy 13th</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/our-daughters-happy-13th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 11:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/our-daughters-happy-13th/</guid>
      <description>Our daughter asked to celebrate her birthday a day ahead, with her 8th grade classmates. They had water gun and balloon fights, and bags of holi powder to throw around. They also played frisbee and volleyball on the village streets and watched scary movies when it got dark. There were lots of food too! I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it was going to be so much fun! Thanks to my dear wife for making preparations, especially the cooking and baking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign up for the first MapUp this 2014!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/sign-up-for-first-mapup-this-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 11:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/sign-up-for-first-mapup-this-2014/</guid>
      <description>This is our opening salvo for the year. Since we started last year, GBG Cagayan de Oro has been receiving a lot of good feedback from the locals. But we&amp;rsquo;ve put our attention on the areas where we can improve, and I really believe that this mapping event is a step towards that direction. A well-mapped city improves tourism and support services. It also opens numerous planning opportunities for the local government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL on Google Cloud Infrastructure Now Available</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 14:03:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-on-google-cloud-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2013</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/christmas-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 06:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/christmas-2013/</guid>
      <description>We decided to go to Cebu and spend Christmas this year with my parents and brother. I suppose it has been more than 15 years since we last celebrated Christmas together. The trip was really stressful because it was passenger season. But it was really worth lugging heavy bags since the cousins got to goof off and have a lot of fun, and the grandparents got to see all of their grandchildren in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late upload. And no, I wasn&#39;t able to have a picture taken with Cardinal Tagle. :p</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/late-upload-and-no-i-wasn-able-to-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 07:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/late-upload-and-no-i-wasn-able-to-have/</guid>
      <description>Late upload. And no, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to have a picture taken with Cardinal Tagle. :p
This was posted on Google+</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community work, with Google.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/community-work-with-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 18:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/community-work-with-google/</guid>
      <description>Community work, with Google.
Thank you mentors +Aileen Apolo +Chelle Gray +Vince Tabor and +Mohd Hadi Shafie Awang Othman!
Thank you to my counterparts +Jerome Locson +Johnn Mendoza +Katherine Yap +Dulce Rose Lada +Rosario Juan +Juned Sonido and +Avel Manansala for inspiring me to do more for the community.
Thank you to our GDG counterpart +Josan Astrid Dometita for your exuberance and continuing support for the &amp;ldquo;old ones&amp;rdquo; hehe
+AMDG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just yesterday, August 7, we had our first academe-focused event, which we called &#34;Enhancing Research...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/just-yesterday-august-7-we-had-our/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 22:13:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/just-yesterday-august-7-we-had-our/</guid>
      <description>Just yesterday, August 7, we had our first academe-focused event, which we called &amp;ldquo;Enhancing Research with Google Technologies&amp;rdquo;. We partnered with the Kinaadman Research Center (KRC) and through the auspices of Dr. Ester Raagas, Director of the KRC, 67.7% of the entire university faculty population who were also research grantees, were able to learn about Google Drive.
The workshop focused on emphasizing the features of Google Drive and Google+ that are applicable for rapid data gathering, information sharing, collaborative work, and documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last July 20, we had our Diversity and Inclusion event for women, which we called &#34;Empowering Women ...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/last-july-20-we-had-our-diversity-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 21:17:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/last-july-20-we-had-our-diversity-and/</guid>
      <description>Last July 20, we had our Diversity and Inclusion event for women, which we called &amp;ldquo;Empowering Women on the Go&amp;rdquo;. We worked with a local JCI chapter, JCI Bai Lawanen, and their members were able to listen to Harriet Fernandez, a director for an IT unit at Xavier University, and Shayryl Mae Ramos, a learning management system administrator, also at Xavier University.
The workshop was on Google Drive and on being able to balance work and home roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back at the LCCT. Now experts at layover management.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-at-lcct-now-experts-at-layover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 22:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-at-lcct-now-experts-at-layover/</guid>
      <description>Back at the LCCT. Now experts at layover management.
This was posted on Google+…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Googlers and GBG Managers learning from each other and collaborating on different practices that can...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/googlers-and-gbg-managers-learning-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 17:01:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/googlers-and-gbg-managers-learning-from/</guid>
      <description>Googlers and GBG Managers learning from each other and collaborating on different practices that can be adopted for communities! #searchsummit2013
This was posted on Google+…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from Googlers and other managers about communities and empowering them for greater things with...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/learning-from-googlers-and-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 12:56:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/learning-from-googlers-and-other/</guid>
      <description>Learning from Googlers and other managers about communities and empowering them for greater things with Google. #searchsummit2013
This was posted on Google+…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentine Surprise</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/valentine-surprise-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 17:06:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/valentine-surprise-comments/</guid>
      <description>Awww. How sweet of the wifey! Connie - Feb 5, 2013Awww. How sweet of the wifey!
Amazing Story Sir Jon, you are so blessed :)
She is! Still smarting for not having anything prepared, but yeah, it&amp;rsquo;ll pass :)
Thanks Rhee. All glory to God. How did your day of hearts go?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentine Surprise</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/valentine-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 17:06:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/valentine-surprise/</guid>
      <description>Each year, on Valentine&amp;rsquo;s day, I usually surprise my darling wife with a letter/card, or a bouquet of roses. As it was a yearly thing, I knew she sort of expected these surprises; she&amp;rsquo;d look surprised, but I knew she wasn&amp;rsquo;t really. Occasionally, she does get surprised. Like that time back in Cebu when I bought her a rather intricate bouquet of flowers. Her head spun when she found out how much I paid for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on SLMIS</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-slmis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 17:15:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-slmis/</guid>
      <description>End users complain because the system isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;user-friendly&amp;rdquo;. FYI, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be that way. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way we can guarantee that the system will still be helpful 25 years from now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migs in the Office!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/migs-in-office-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 07:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/migs-in-office-comments/</guid>
      <description>I know about Thor&amp;rsquo;s hammer, but who or what is&amp;hellip; E.J. - Jan 0, 2013I know about Thor&amp;rsquo;s hammer, but who or what is the Mjolnir you&amp;rsquo;re referring to? :)
@ejpadero It&amp;rsquo;s right on top of that stack of papers in front of Miguel :D
Mjolnir is a black bag? :D
Oh, wait. My four eyes see it now. LOL. Mini hammer!
@ejpadero he takes his mini-Mjolnir everywhere he goes lol</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migs in the Office!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/migs-in-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 07:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/migs-in-office/</guid>
      <description>Miguel got real bored at home and wanted to go and meet his classmates. Since school doesn&amp;rsquo;t start until the 7th, I decided to take him with me to the office. He immediately got busy with the miniclip games and ignored Mjolnir the whole time!
[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;rectangular&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;3167,3166&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civic Stories - December 2012</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/civic-stories-december-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 16:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/civic-stories-december-2012/</guid>
      <description>I sort of miss being in the backseat. A lot of my goofing off years have been conducted within the confines of the passenger doors, backside of the front seats, and the backseat.
[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;4&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;rectangular&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;3012,3011,3010,3009,3008,3007,3006,3005,3004,3003&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Blog changes, etc.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 18:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc-comments/</guid>
      <description>http://jon.doblados.net/2012/11/revisited-blog-cha... Jon Janairo Doblados - Nov 3, 2012http://jon.doblados.net/2012/11/revisited-blog-changes-etc/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Blog changes, etc.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 18:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve once more moved my blog. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s on my own hosting account and it&amp;rsquo;s back to using WP. Same blog, different flavor now and moving forward. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this short discussion with a co-leader in church on going back to blogging, and he pointed out the importance of identifying to a particular niche. I said sure, it&amp;rsquo;s important, but I think I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to separate my technical gibberish from my thoughts and reflections on God and Christianity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honor God, Make Disciples</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/honor-god-make-disciples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:48:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/honor-god-make-disciples/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, I started attending this workshop/training for leaders at Victory CDO. It&amp;rsquo;s called Training for Victory (T4V), and it was a once-a-week engagement for about 10 weeks; although it took longer than that because of several holidays around that time. We graduated and were commissioned, not as pastors, but as servants who will lead people to take on a personal relationship with Christ. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace, I was also the recipient of the Award for Excellence during the ceremonies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured images are so hard to use!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/featured-images-are-so-hard-to-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:34:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/featured-images-are-so-hard-to-use/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so I&amp;rsquo;m spoiled. Anyone kind enough to explain why they appear in some posts and why they don&amp;rsquo;t in others (featured images added, doh)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids on Photobooth</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:16:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</guid>
      <description>Miguel and Isabel goofing off in front of the laptop. They discovered the 4-shot option and started taking pictures by themselves.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t mind if I start posting more pictures here. I’ve really been keeping myself from posting these to Facebook, which was the natural tendency, no thanks to endless egging by the family. But no. It’s been a couple of years now that I’ve wanted to steer clear from FB when it comes to posting pictures; especially of family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/thank-you-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 21:12:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/thank-you-comments/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re welcome, Jon. Having suffered form DHF&amp;hellip; Joseph Somera - Jun 3, 2012You&amp;rsquo;re welcome, Jon. Having suffered form DHF myself, I know the hardships and trials that come with it. This was a big reason for me to decide to become a blood donor. It flows within us to give, and flows through us to save others. While I can&amp;rsquo;t necessarily donate - being on the other side of the world - what I can give is support and encouragement, as well as a call to potential blood donors as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 21:12:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>I am home, and enjoying my second lease in life, one slow day at a time. I have never been hospitalized for something as life-threatening as DHF with complications before, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit frustrating that even when I&amp;rsquo;m already out of the hospital, I could not move around as much as I want. I could not even attempt to lift and carry my son when he feels like asking me to hoist him up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal drop experiences with Motorola Canopy</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/signal-drop-experiences-with-motorola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 19:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/signal-drop-experiences-with-motorola/</guid>
      <description>Gotta finish this quick before the signal drops again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templates!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 12:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of new templates on Blogger now. The last time I checked in 2009, there were just the old themes that sort of grow old on you faster than gym socks.
My only gripe is that getting all of my posts imported from a Wordpress platform is rather difficult. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to just start from a clean slate, but I have tons of notes from my old posts and I&amp;rsquo;d like to see them all from one site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel, lately.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-lately-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 23:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-lately-comments/</guid>
      <description>i like the last 2 pics. kulit! haha. Connie - Dec 6, 2011i like the last 2 pics. kulit! haha.
Love the hair! boy, Miguel is sure growing up FAST !
He seems to be enjoying a growth spurt. He&amp;rsquo;s been eating a lot and still drinking a lot.
Super kulit nga! 2 years to go daw until he settles down haha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel, lately.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-lately/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 23:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-lately/</guid>
      <description>Since we moved apartments, the little man started doing facial expressions that always gets us wondering how he got them. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried capturing these expressions with a camera but it&amp;rsquo;s a lot harder than simply having the phone or the point-and-shoot handy at all times.
Well today was a treat. He fired up one facial expression, and let me take a picture! Yay!
[nggallery id=6]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covered area expansion project</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/covered-area-expansion-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 22:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/covered-area-expansion-project/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve recently decided to cover the whole area where the outdoor canteen was and turn into an activity area. I was supposed to have completed the electrical wiring last Saturday but the materials were delivered at noon and I was already quite content with just spending the afternoon with the kids.
[nggallery id=5]
Will post more pictures this week as we try and finish the fascia, flooring, and electrical works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GWF Team CDO</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gwf-team-cdo-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 08:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gwf-team-cdo-comments/</guid>
      <description>Woot! ^_^ Hardwyrd - Aug 3, 2011Woot! ^_^
We should plan for a bigger get-together. What say you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GWF Team CDO</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gwf-team-cdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 08:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gwf-team-cdo/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way since 2006; but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until 2009 that we had a solid team based in CDO. We&amp;rsquo;re not even all sysads, but we love the fact that besides Romar, who has been my friend from way back, it was only after Carlo and Alvin joined GWF did we learn where they&amp;rsquo;re from.
[nggallery id=4]
Looking forward to another TBA at the later part of this year, hopefully with more people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching over the little one in our school&#39;s playroom.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/watching-over-little-one-in-our-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 15:45:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/watching-over-little-one-in-our-school/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you updated?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/have-you-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/have-you-updated/</guid>
      <description>jon@jedi-ntbk:~$ lsb_release -a LSB Version: core-2.0-ia32:core-2.0-noarch:core-3.0-ia32:core-3.0-noarch:core-3.1-ia32:core-3.1-noarch:core-3.2-ia32:core-3.2-noarch:core-4.0-ia32:core-4.0-noarch Distributor ID: Ubuntu Description: Ubuntu 10.04.3 LTS Release: 10.04 Codename: lucid</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview (Dense) anyone?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/preview-dense-anyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 23:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/preview-dense-anyone/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to understand why Gmail&amp;rsquo;s new look gives me the migraines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicks for the (no longer) little girl.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kicks-for-no-longer-little-girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 16:06:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kicks-for-no-longer-little-girl/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goofing off at SM.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/goofing-off-at-sm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 17:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/goofing-off-at-sm/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tarp sign got installed this am, just before parents&#39; orientation. #hci</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/tarp-sign-got-installed-this-am-just/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 13:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/tarp-sign-got-installed-this-am-just/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For dinner, it&#39;s tuna, mayo, spices, and lettuce.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/for-dinner-it-tuna-mayo-spices-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 19:16:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/for-dinner-it-tuna-mayo-spices-and/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Park and around HK - April 2011</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ocean-park-and-around-hk-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 19:51:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ocean-park-and-around-hk-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>[[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]
 ](http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/IMG_4992.JPG.scaled1000.jpg)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disneyland, HK - April 2011</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disneyland-hk-april-2011-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 13:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disneyland-hk-april-2011-comments/</guid>
      <description>Was testing a plugin for Wordpress, but feel free &amp;hellip; Jon Janairo Doblados - Nov 0, 2012Was testing a plugin for Wordpress, but feel free to view the pics anyway. :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disneyland, HK - April 2011</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disneyland-hk-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 13:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disneyland-hk-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kowloon, Disneyland, HK - April 2011</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kowloon-disneyland-hk-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 11:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kowloon-disneyland-hk-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;4&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;post&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;479,480,481,482,483,484,485,486,487,488,489,490,491,492,493,494,495,496,497,498,499,500,501,502,503,504,505,506,507,508,509,510,511,512,513,514,439,440,441,442,443,444,445,446,447,448,449,450,451,452,453,454,455,456,457,458,459,460,461,462,463,464,465,466,467,468,469,470,471,472,473,474,475,476,477,478&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cebu, April 2011</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/cebu-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 10:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/cebu-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel does videoke</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-does-videoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 20:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-does-videoke/</guid>
      <description>19032011.mp4
Watch on Posterous
Shot with a phone camera. Jon Miguel, who&amp;rsquo;s only a year and 11 months, trying out the videoke machine and doing some really rad facial expressions while singing. Please do watch the two others below. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother editing because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get Pitivi to import mp4 files properly.

19032011(002).mp4
Watch on Posterous

19032011(001).mp4
Watch on Posterous</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s eat!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/let-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 19:49:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/let-eat/</guid>
      <description>A simple celebration and dinner at home. Mae did all of the cooking, except for the humba and paklay, courtesy of Dad. Different cameras used here. :)
[[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]
](http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/IMG_5577.JPG.scaled1000.jpg)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy alternative to the regular sunny-side up. Mae did poached eggs for the first time! Deeelish!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/healthy-alternative-to-regular-sunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 06:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/healthy-alternative-to-regular-sunny/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-the-month TODOs</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/end-of-month-todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 19:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/end-of-month-todos/</guid>
      <description>I have again changed the look of my tech blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually mulled over this for quite some time since I was also thinking of just moving everything to my own hosted Wordpress install. But, lazy as I am, I was content to tweak as little as I can. Posterous has a few really nice themes built-in so moving my stuff out was really a bad idea.
In case you&amp;rsquo;re curious, here are some of the things that I intend to complete this month:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skyflakes dipped in soda. Yum!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/skyflakes-dipped-in-soda-yum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 17:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/skyflakes-dipped-in-soda-yum/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Cake</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/japanese-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 17:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/japanese-cake/</guid>
      <description>More of the sweet stuff that we&amp;rsquo;re not supposed to be eating. Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s just me who&amp;rsquo;s restricted from eating this (and Mom), but it&amp;rsquo;s a rare treat from Dad&amp;rsquo;s good friend Ted Tanaka so I had a little morsel. :p
I love the meticulous way these cakes are packed.
[gallery orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans for a 500-Word Project</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plans-for-500-word-project-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 21:13:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plans-for-500-word-project-comments/</guid>
      <description>Stupid me left the commenting disabled. :( You can&amp;hellip; Jon Doblados - Feb 1, 2011Stupid me left the commenting disabled. :( You can now leave comments folks! :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans for a 500-Word Project</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plans-for-500-word-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 21:13:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plans-for-500-word-project/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t written a proper blog entry since 2006. I feel that my recent entries are worthy of post tags that I would consider &amp;ldquo;forgettable&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;archive-able&amp;rdquo; (if there is such a thing).
I so need motivation. Anything to get the old drive for writing flowing in my veins again. I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate any inputs from you. Just leave a comment.
At this stage, I can&amp;rsquo;t say I still want this blog focused on work and tech stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Little :p</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/chicken-little-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 09:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/chicken-little-p/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel: wucha lookin&#39; at?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-wucha-lookin-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 22:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-wucha-lookin-at/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first capp in a long time. Until next month! :p #bawal</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-capp-in-long-time-until-next-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 13:27:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-capp-in-long-time-until-next-comments/</guid>
      <description>I got busted. Hehe Jon Doblados - Jan 1, 2011I got busted. Hehe</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first capp in a long time. Until next month! :p #bawal</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-capp-in-long-time-until-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 13:27:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-capp-in-long-time-until-next/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musuan Trip</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/musuan-trip-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 11:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/musuan-trip-comments/</guid>
      <description>very nice place parang makakapag relax ka talaga. &amp;hellip; Fe Janairo - Jan 1, 2011very nice place parang makakapag relax ka talaga. Sobrang lamig ba kaya walang ibang tao?
Yes Auntie, it&amp;rsquo;s quite cold because it was early morning. Most of those who checked in the houses were still asleep. Kysa and Miguel were already swimming as early as 7am. The walk-in guests started arriving around 830am and by 11am, the place was already packed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musuan Trip</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/musuan-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 11:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/musuan-trip/</guid>
      <description>We went to Musuan, in Bukidnon. It&amp;rsquo;s home to the &amp;ldquo;boob&amp;rdquo; mountain, hence the name &amp;ldquo;Musuan&amp;rdquo;. Our dear Aunt Celia passed on and relatives from all over convened in CMU (where she was administrator). We spent the night in RR Family Spring Resort in Tubigon, border of Maramag, and after the wake swam in the fresh water pools, braving the intense cold. :D
[[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]
 ](http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/IMG_4480.JPG.scaled1000.jpg)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost 10yrs old and she&#39;s only gone this far. ^_^</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/almost-10yrs-old-and-she-only-gone-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 10:12:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/almost-10yrs-old-and-she-only-gone-this/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Time (and Miguel&#39;s dance moves)</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-time-and-miguel-dance-moves-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 08:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-time-and-miguel-dance-moves-comments/</guid>
      <description>Testing if this shows up. Jon Doblados - Jan 1, 2011Testing if this shows up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Time (and Miguel&#39;s dance moves)</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-time-and-miguel-dance-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 08:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-time-and-miguel-dance-moves/</guid>
      <description>Miguel has this rather curious dance step somewhere just before the refrain of the dance track The Time (Dirty Bit) by BEP. Not his full dance though since he was busy running around doing other stuff. :D
  movie1_01_01.avi
Watch on Posterous</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My best friend and I ^_^</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-best-friend-and-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 15:32:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-best-friend-and-i/</guid>
      <description>[gallery orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel coupe de cheveux, by Peter</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-coupe-de-cheveux-by-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 23:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-coupe-de-cheveux-by-peter/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today, we let Miguel tag along with us to David&amp;rsquo;s in Divisoria. We weren&amp;rsquo;t sure if Miguel was ready to have his first &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; haircut. After seeing all of us get trimmed by Peter (he&amp;rsquo;s the only one who cuts our hair), it looked like he was okay to get one too, until someone wrapped a barber&amp;rsquo;s cape around his neck and the screeching started. LOL!
He did pause a few times to try to smile at the camera through tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I lurv going places - Miguel</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-lurv-going-places-miguel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 22:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-lurv-going-places-miguel/</guid>
      <description>[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimsum again</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/dimsum-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 22:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/dimsum-again/</guid>
      <description>We love Dimsum Diner, but we gotta start learning to keep ourselves from eating there too often. Why? We&amp;rsquo;re all high risk people, that&amp;rsquo;s why.
In this set, my sister-in-law was playing around with the camera settings, which explains the no-flash feature. Will try to do another shoot next time and will play with ISO and WB. Not a DSLR. Lugging that with us during family eat-outs is overkill.
[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s the twin! @ricpac @CagayanDeOroCT @jumords @vicmadz @carloborja @hardwyrd @katleenmae @lifediscourse</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/here-twin-ricpac-cagayandeoroct-jumords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 19:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/here-twin-ricpac-cagayandeoroct-jumords/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kysa Knows</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kysa-knows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 23:48:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kysa-knows/</guid>
      <description>Well here are a couple of shots of our princess, who was trying to finish off her purchases so she can brush teeth and sleep already. She&amp;rsquo;s tried doing some blogging in her spare time (I think this is a good thing for her) and you can follow her here.

Nomnomnom! First shot settings were F/7.1, ISO-400, shutter speed of 0.81sec

Next shot used F/2.8, ISO-400, and shutter speed of 1/10sec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVN-MantisBT Integration</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/svn-mantisbt-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 02:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/svn-mantisbt-integration/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded and installed MantisBT 1.2.3stable on linode2, and after fixing permissions issues, proceeded with the installation. I stopped when I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the same MantisBT version on the old server. It&amp;rsquo;s always better to set up MantisBT on the target server &amp;ldquo;as is&amp;rdquo;, and let the install scripts handle the upgrade.
I&amp;rsquo;m roughly 28% in with a server-to-server SCP of a 79Mb MySQL dump of our bugtracker. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to check with the backups since I felt that a fresh dump is always best; but no, I remembered that several developers preferred working odd hours and they would definitely need the bug tracker up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ate taking her time @oMF Lit Bookshop</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ate-taking-her-time-omf-lit-bookshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 18:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ate-taking-her-time-omf-lit-bookshop/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our favorite &#34;Bubbles!&#34; video</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/our-favorite-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 11:01:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/our-favorite-video/</guid>
      <description>Taken some months back. Always makes us smile when we see this.

15052010.mp4
Watch on Posterous</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m hungry! Where&#39;s the food??!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-hungry-where-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:16:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-hungry-where-food/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fore!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/fore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 10:06:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/fore/</guid>
      <description>Too bad he doesn&amp;rsquo;t like my tennis racquet (just yet).
[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;4&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DiDiBoDiDiBoDiBoDi!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/didibodidibodibodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 09:58:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/didibodidibodibodi/</guid>
      <description>Too close to the TV. That&amp;rsquo;s how he likes it. (So he can press buttons all he wants)
[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;4&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Kernel Tuning for C500k | Urban Airship Blog</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k-urban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/linux-kernel-tuning-for-c500k-urban/</guid>
      <description>By Jared &amp;ldquo;Lucky&amp;rdquo; Kuolt on September 29, 2010 Like the idea of working on large scale problems? We’re hiring talented engineers, and would love to chat with you – check it out!
 Note: Concurrency, as defined in this article, is the same as it is for The C10k problem: concurrent clients (or sockets).
 At Urban Airship we recently published a blog post about scaling beyond 500,000 concurrent socket connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get through your email faster with Gmail Priority Inbox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/get-through-your-email-faster-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 09:33:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/get-through-your-email-faster-with/</guid>
      <description>This is great for people who do not use a GTD system yet. Try it and see how fast it learns.
 Priority InboxBeta
Welcome to Priority Inbox! By automatically separating out your most important messages, Priority Inbox makes it easy for you to read and respond to the messages that matter.
Get through your email faster Try reading and replying to the messages in the &amp;ldquo;Important and Unread&amp;rdquo; section first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mall rat in the making :p</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mall-rat-in-making-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 00:03:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mall-rat-in-making-p/</guid>
      <description>[[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]
](http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/08182010.jpg.scaled1000.jpg)
It&amp;rsquo;s greatthat we&amp;rsquo;ve started to take Miguel along each time we&amp;rsquo;re in the mall. It&amp;rsquo;s doing wonders for his social skills. :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best friends taking time off with kids :p</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/best-friends-taking-time-off-with-kids-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 16:37:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/best-friends-taking-time-off-with-kids-p/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too busy with fries...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/too-busy-with-fries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2010 00:39:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/too-busy-with-fries/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast after early morning church service</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/breakfast-after-early-morning-church-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 12:15:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/breakfast-after-early-morning-church-comments/</guid>
      <description>Miguel&amp;rsquo;s mama took one look at the pictures he&amp;hellip; Jon Doblados - Aug 0, 2010Miguel&amp;rsquo;s mama took one look at the pictures here and decided to give him a haircut when we got home. Will post new pics when he wakes up from his morning nap. :)
astig, pero cute pa rin. sabi ng kasambahay dito, based on her experience, kakapal daw ang buhok kung kakalbuhin
Ah, but we only trimmed his hair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast after early morning church service</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/breakfast-after-early-morning-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 12:15:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/breakfast-after-early-morning-church/</guid>
      <description>[[gallery orderby=&amp;ldquo;post_date&amp;rdquo;]
](http://jon.doblados.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/08012010.jpg.scaled1000.jpg)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to count instances of an IP address in a log file</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-ip-address-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-to-count-instances-of-ip-address-in/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a quick and painless way to determine what IP addresses used our web app the most and stumbled across this excellent post. I got reminded of the power of the command-line interface and that often, I underestimate the way these commands are supposed to make a sysad&amp;rsquo;s life easier.
So here&amp;rsquo;s a quick tip for counting unique visitors to your web app. Locate your web app&amp;rsquo;s log file and do a quick scan of the last few lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The things Miguel does on a usual day</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-things-miguel-does-on-usual-day-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 18:59:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-things-miguel-does-on-usual-day-comments/</guid>
      <description>GRABE KA CUTE! :) jenipur - Jul 0, 2010GRABE KA CUTE! :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The things Miguel does on a usual day</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-things-miguel-does-on-usual-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 18:59:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-things-miguel-does-on-usual-day/</guid>
      <description>miguel1.mp4
Watch on Posterous
In a month or so he&amp;rsquo;ll be too big to fit in his laundry basket. He has his eye on the bigger hamper in our room.

miguel2.mp4
Watch on Posterous
He runs around and does the &amp;ldquo;happy feet&amp;rdquo;. He also likes running while on top of the air bed, but I can&amp;rsquo;t get any video of that yet as I&amp;rsquo;m too busy going after him lest he bounce too hard and hit the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever wondered how I look like after pulling an all-nighter?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ever-wondered-how-i-look-like-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 10:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ever-wondered-how-i-look-like-after/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putty on my phone FTW! ISP was acting up and was able to get Apache to work sometime past 3pm. Post-mortem shortly.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/putty-on-my-phone-ftw-isp-was-acting-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 03:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/putty-on-my-phone-ftw-isp-was-acting-up/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Systems Administrator @37signals (Podcast)</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/being-systems-administrator-37signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 22:51:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/being-systems-administrator-37signals/</guid>
      <description>I use Basecamp a lot. Kudos to these guys for making my job as a Systems Administrator more bearable than usual. :p
 Episode #12: Being a Systems Administrator at 37signals Time: 22:50 | 04/13/2010 | Download MP3 | Link to this episode
Mark, Joshua, and John on life as a 37signals Sys Admin
The Sys Admin team discusses hosting the 37signals apps, working with programmers, helping support, telecommuting, dealing with vendors, improving speeds in Europe, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How big is a Yottabyte? - Holy Kaw!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-big-is-yottabyte-holy-kaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 07:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-big-is-yottabyte-holy-kaw/</guid>
      <description>And I got a long way to go. My next step doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen in the next couple of months, and that&amp;rsquo;s when I purchase a terabyte external hard drive for storage purposes.
 Remember back in the 1970s when 200MB was the size of a tire? Now we live in a world of gigbytes and terabytes, and the future will bring zettabytes and yottabytes in everyday life. Hello, future!
k to view large</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New theme, needs more work</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/new-theme-needs-more-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 22:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/new-theme-needs-more-work/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m doing some major cosmetic changes with this blog; and I&amp;rsquo;m sort of working off this to-do:
1. come up with a manageable set of tags
2. update posts with appropriate tags
3. look for any form of twitter integration
Yes, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging more now. More than anything else, I need the writing exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After a busy afternoon of play, Ate Kysa attended to her brother and shared a meal with him.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/after-busy-afternoon-of-play-ate-kysa-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 17:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/after-busy-afternoon-of-play-ate-kysa-comments/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re so lucky Miguel. Cute ka na, may ate ka&amp;hellip; Anonymous - May 6, 2010You&amp;rsquo;re so lucky Miguel. Cute ka na, may ate ka pa like Kysa.
Thank you Auntie. Indeed he&amp;rsquo;s blessed to have an Ate who is so fond of him. She&amp;rsquo;s as much of a blessing to us as well. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After a busy afternoon of play, Ate Kysa attended to her brother and shared a meal with him.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/after-busy-afternoon-of-play-ate-kysa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 17:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/after-busy-afternoon-of-play-ate-kysa/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel&#39;s first giddyap!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-first-giddyap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 21:48:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-first-giddyap/</guid>
      <description>05202010.mp4
Watch on Posterous
Spur of the moment thing. I was never really good with &amp;ldquo;anticipation&amp;rdquo; so didn&amp;rsquo;t take a better recording gadget with us. We didn&amp;rsquo;t think Miguel was going to point at the carousel since he would normally ignore this. I guess he&amp;rsquo;s starting to appreciate things around him more, now that he&amp;rsquo;s walking&amp;hellip;and running&amp;hellip;and stumbling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter - Decentralize the web with Diaspora</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kickstarter-decentralize-web-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 01:27:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/kickstarter-decentralize-web-with/</guid>
      <description>http://kck.st/9QC2zk
IMO, this is the answer to all your privacy-related concerns on Facebook. Can’t wait til it launches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Jejemon Bashing</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/stop-jejemon-bashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 13:44:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/stop-jejemon-bashing/</guid>
      <description>It’s not my business, but I’m really tired of all of these jejemon-bashing stuff I’m seeing in twitter and facebook. Why not make an effort to educate these language-challenged people?
Come on people, this monster’s been around a long time. It just took on a new name. Let’s do something productive. ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fever and what-not&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/fever-and-what-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 06:08:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/fever-and-what-not/</guid>
      <description>I dare not say what we hope our daughter didn’t get that’s causing her on and off high fever since Tuesday night. We’re still hopeful that it’s some ordinary viral infection that’s been plaguing kids these hot El Nino days.
My wife and I are in distress due to lack of sleep, but we’re still hopeful. We were advised to wait until 6pm tonight to get another CBC exam. That’s because aside from her fever, she hasn’t been showing the other symptoms, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ang pinoy at ang Starbucks. Latte Loco? ERR. (source: teentalk)</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ang-pinoy-at-ang-starbucks-latte-loco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 07:31:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ang-pinoy-at-ang-starbucks-latte-loco/</guid>
      <description>pinoytumblr:
 modifyyona:
 1. Only in the Philippines will you see people ditching the comfort of sipping a cup of Starbucks coffee inside the airconditioned store and preferring instead to sit outside and be soaked dry by the heat of the tropical sun.
The reason? Kailangan makita ng friends/classmates/kakilala ko na nandito ako sa Starbucks! Magpapakasosyal na lang, e di i-todo ko na.
The lesson? Sit where you would be seen easily the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 22:32:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_13/</guid>
      <description>Goes to show that at this hour, they’re outsourcing kings! (via @bleepster)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Web Design Goes Straight to Hell - The Oatmeal</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-web-design-goes-straight-to-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 03:04:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/how-web-design-goes-straight-to-hell/</guid>
      <description>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/design_hell
Well I’ll be! Just exactly how things go (but not with our current company, thank God). Goes to @Bambi @Lee @jenipur and all my web designer friends. ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etymology of the term &#34;uyab&#34;</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/etymology-of-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 00:57:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/etymology-of-term/</guid>
      <description>http://www.villageidiotsavant.com/2010/02/etymology-of-uyab.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using non-standard SSH port with TortoiseSVN</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 05:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with-comments/</guid>
      <description>I should note that that code gets added into /home&amp;hellip; devkinetic - May 4, 2010I should note that that code gets added into /home/USERNAME/.subversion/config under the [tunnels] section.
Thanks for pointing this out. Edited the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using non-standard SSH port with TortoiseSVN</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 05:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-non-standard-ssh-port-with/</guid>
      <description>Some of my students reported that they were having problems connecting to their repositories using TortoiseSVN. At first, quick checks from my end didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal what caused these, but I realized soon that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a server issue. It seems like the client software that they were using (TortoiseSVN) didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to make of the svn+ssh://[user]@[ip]:[port]/[repo] URL.
I use RabbitVCS on my Linux boxen and get the same &amp;ldquo;Network connection closed unexpectedly&amp;rdquo; message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebug Lite 1.3.0 beta /via sitepoint tech times</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/firebug-lite-130-beta-via-sitepoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/firebug-lite-130-beta-via-sitepoint/</guid>
      <description>http://getfirebug.com/releases/lite/beta/
Man, it’s about time! Some Firebug functionality on my other browsers would be awesome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[repost] System for staying on top of priorities</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/repost-system-for-staying-on-top-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 11:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/repost-system-for-staying-on-top-of/</guid>
      <description>I’ve tried a lot of productivity tools to get better control over my ever-bloating task lists, and none have been as effective for me, as using Gmail with the GTDInbox add-on, and Google Tasks. How I make these work for me is a result of several months of trials, using Google Tasks initially, then with custom labeling and automatic label switching with GTDInbox.
The goal was simple, and that was to attain inbox zero at least once a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 13:19:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_5/</guid>
      <description>Because pictures speak a thousand words. Pftt!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_3807/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 05:56:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_3807/</guid>
      <description>When you’re as forgetful as I am</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 09:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_4/</guid>
      <description>Doug should just stick to doing “point!” :D
eclair:
 Awwww, Doug is so cute here. Look at those eyes and ears!
forky:
 lordartworks:
 cosmicsquirreljustice:
 (via fagtasticvoyage)
 DOUG!
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now I got the itch to shell script this [http://bash.org/?910094]</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/now-i-got-itch-to-shell-script-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 15:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/now-i-got-itch-to-shell-script-this/</guid>
      <description>Doug should just stick to doing “point!” :D
eclair:
 Awwww, Doug is so cute here. Look at those eyes and ears!
forky:
 lordartworks:
 cosmicsquirreljustice:
 (via fagtasticvoyage)
 DOUG!
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>backing up</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/backing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 11:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/backing-up/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so I griped earlier about failing at being an early adopter. Just when I thought something wouldn’t launch and I turn my back, everyone else then starts getting on it and using it. :p
So maybe I’ll just delete my old LJ account and start ranting here, for real. My Posterous account would then be a photoblog of sorts, since I can post directly to it via Gravity on my phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel loves his gelato! #fb</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-loves-his-gelato-fb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 20:19:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-loves-his-gelato-fb/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the family&#39;s New Year&#39;s gathering later, featuring Mae&#39;s famous death by cheese spaghetti! ^_^ #fb</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/for-family-new-year-gathering-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 11:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/for-family-new-year-gathering-later/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from the courts. Kysa has a wicked top spin, and she showed her Mama how she does it. Real proud of her!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-from-courts-kysa-has-wicked-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 09:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-from-courts-kysa-has-wicked-top/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System for staying on top of priorities</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2009 20:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/system-for-staying-on-top-of-priorities/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of productivity tools to get better control over my ever-bloating task lists, and none have been as effective for me, as using Gmail with the GTDInbox add-on, and Google Tasks. How I make these work for me is a result of several months of trials, using Google Tasks initially, then with custom labeling and automatic label switching with GTDInbox.
The goal was simple, and that was to attain inbox zero at least once a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for her Christmas event in school. Thanks to mom-la for the makeup. I almost didn&#39;t recognize her hehe</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ready-for-her-christmas-event-in-school-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 15:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ready-for-her-christmas-event-in-school-comments/</guid>
      <description>wow&amp;hellip; so grown up and looking very much a lady&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; fely - Dec 4, 2009wow&amp;hellip; so grown up and looking very much a lady&amp;hellip;miss you a lot kyse, really do&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for her Christmas event in school. Thanks to mom-la for the makeup. I almost didn&#39;t recognize her hehe</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ready-for-her-christmas-event-in-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 15:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ready-for-her-christmas-event-in-school/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermom</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/supermom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 20:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/supermom/</guid>
      <description>I love my wife. She&amp;rsquo;s all about the greater levels of thoughtfulness
that I don&amp;rsquo;t have, and earlier today, she&amp;rsquo;s outdone herself once more.
In a few hours she had completed all of her Christmas shopping for my
god-children and nephews and nieces. No thanks to me; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand
gift shopping unless it&amp;rsquo;s for her or my kids, much worse if it&amp;rsquo;s for
some other people.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I&amp;rsquo;m all for giving gifts as long as it&amp;rsquo;s in the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh that&#39;s good! More please!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/oh-that-good-more-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 22:34:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/oh-that-good-more-please/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And Miguel tries his first sip of soda.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/and-miguel-tries-his-first-sip-of-soda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 14:42:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/and-miguel-tries-his-first-sip-of-soda/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At McDo SM with Mae, Angela, Kysa, and Miguel.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/at-mcdo-sm-with-mae-angela-kysa-and-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 14:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/at-mcdo-sm-with-mae-angela-kysa-and-comments/</guid>
      <description>oh god. my haircut -__-&amp;quot; jen - Nov 3, 2010oh god. my haircut -__-&amp;quot;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At McDo SM with Mae, Angela, Kysa, and Miguel.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/at-mcdo-sm-with-mae-angela-kysa-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 14:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/at-mcdo-sm-with-mae-angela-kysa-and/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates, finally!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/updates-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 16:38:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/updates-finally/</guid>
      <description>Some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing lately: grokking Postfix (again), remapping sites for migration this week, and domain auctions.
I also moved my non-tech stuff to posterous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His ate and Mama are going to be just as busy dealing with them chicks as well ^_^</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/his-ate-and-mama-are-going-to-be-just/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 00:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/his-ate-and-mama-are-going-to-be-just/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can see myself dealing with all the ladies who will be tweeting, texting, and calling Miguel some years from now..</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-can-see-myself-dealing-with-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 00:19:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-can-see-myself-dealing-with-all/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheez! (Ate, I&#39;ll post this here then I&#39;ll have Mama post in FB ok?)</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/cheez-ate-i-post-this-here-then-i-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 09:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/cheez-ate-i-post-this-here-then-i-have/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel&#39;s ready for church.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-ready-for-church-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 07:58:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-ready-for-church-comments/</guid>
      <description>he sure is wearing his sunday best :o) connie - Nov 5, 2009he sure is wearing his sunday best :o)
@connieluayon Indeed. And he has that toothy smile to boot ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel&#39;s ready for church.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-ready-for-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 07:58:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/miguel-ready-for-church/</guid>
      <description>via Gravity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And I thought I was getting good at packing</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/and-i-thought-i-was-getting-good-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 16:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/and-i-thought-i-was-getting-good-at/</guid>
      <description>There’s just too many things to put in boxes, and the more I see old stuff the longer it’s taking me to organize them! If only I can use GTD principles here and not think about lengths, widths, and heights and just toss stuff in. ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 21:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_22/</guid>
      <description>Miguel looks like he just woke up and is giving everyone the foglamp treatment. Thanks to Pangga for the quick cam shot. ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 15:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_9/</guid>
      <description>I was installing the paddings on Miguel’s carrier and thought of posting a HOWTO, but I didn’t have a camera here; so I posted who’s using it instead. Does he look like me or what? ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In other news</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/in-other-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 12:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/in-other-news/</guid>
      <description>I’ve gone impulsive again. I was waiting for a good time to make this personal (more or less) blog, public. But then I realize that I may have just been waiting for my hair to grow back. Believe me, that’s going to take much, much longer!
I may as well chronicle everything now that my kids are growing up. I also think that I and my wife are now going through that most interesting phase of life, and it’s probably worth writing about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export TweetDeck groups in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/export-tweetdeck-groups-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 05:20:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/export-tweetdeck-groups-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>If you have multiple installs of TweetDeck on different computers, I bet you wished there were ways to save the groups you set up. These groupings are not saved in your Twitter profile, but are kept in a local database in your computer. This means that for each install of TweetDeck, you will have to re-set up your groups, and any changes won&amp;rsquo;t replicate to your other installs.
This post about copying TweetDeck settings in Windows explains this in detail, and I have been able to do the same for Ubuntu, replicating TweetDeck settings across 3 machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In other news</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/in-other-news_27-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 05:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/in-other-news_27-comments/</guid>
      <description>yes, it&amp;rsquo;s better THIS way :o) connie - Nov 5, 2009yes, it&amp;rsquo;s better THIS way :o)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In other news</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/in-other-news_27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 05:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/in-other-news_27/</guid>
      <description>I’ve gone impulsive again. I was waiting for a good time to make this personal (more or less) blog, public. But then I realize that I may have just been waiting for my hair to grow back. Believe me, that’s going to take much, much longer!
I may as well chronicle everything now that my kids are growing up. I also think that I and my wife are now going through that most interesting phase of life, and it’s probably worth writing about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F1 Live Timing</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/f1-live-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 18:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/f1-live-timing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make heads and tails with how the live timing applet presents data. Webber&amp;rsquo;s on 3rd!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 05:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_20/</guid>
      <description>This is my favorite group pic so far. Ate Kysa quit asking us to let her carry Miguel for this shot. What do you think?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And more waiting...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/and-more-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 17:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/and-more-waiting/</guid>
      <description>Mae was supposed to have given birth already, but all she ever had were a few minutes of labor, and they’d disappear and won’t come back until after a few hours. The baby’s already a 7+ pounder and all he wants to do is eat more I guess. He just keeps kicking until Mae munches on something. Definitely, we don’t want him growing as big as Kysa when she came out; at 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in 5.</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-in-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 23:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-in-5/</guid>
      <description>So I renewed my domain name earlier and thought about writing more just to balance the traffic I get for the domain, which is around 20% HTTP, and 80% SMTP.
Mail is obviously important, and since I had Gmail handle mails, everything’s been very stress free. Google just works, right? So migrating once again back to Blogger for my rant pages is now a no-brainer. Stay tuned for more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIIX3 cannot attach drive to the Secondary Master</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/piix3-cannot-attach-drive-to-secondary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 13:12:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/piix3-cannot-attach-drive-to-secondary/</guid>
      <description>I use VirtualBox for my server experimenting requirements, and it&amp;rsquo;s just great! Just this morning, I got an error message when I started an FC8 virtual machine.
PIIX3 cannot attach drive to the Secondary Master. VBox status code: -102 (VERR_FILE_NOT_FOUND).
This thread in the forums explains that the virtual machine was looking for a disk that was supposed to be mounted and could not find it. I was using an external DVD drive and had removed it before I shut down the VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plurk-weaned</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plurk-weaned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 11:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plurk-weaned/</guid>
      <description>thinks he&amp;rsquo;s weaned enough from Plurk to not bother checking his timeline anymore. :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things you do for your kids</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/things-you-do-for-your-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 11:46:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/things-you-do-for-your-kids/</guid>
      <description>feeding my daughter&amp;rsquo;s virtual pet in Club Penguin. *tsk*</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arping -s</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/arping-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 15:33:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/arping-s/</guid>
      <description>arping saves the day once again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to school blues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-to-school-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/back-to-school-blues/</guid>
      <description>I’m already feeling the need to kick myself for taking full load this semester, but as my wife would always say, I’ve seen worse days and situations and just as long as I stuck with “the” plan, no problems.
For now, I need to answer the following questions: Am I ready for distance education? Am I ready to teach online?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday Gold Rush on Y101</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/friday-gold-rush-on-y101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 13:03:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/friday-gold-rush-on-y101/</guid>
      <description>good morning! friday gold rush!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deplurked</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/deplurked/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 18:39:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/deplurked/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve deplurked long enough I guess. Karma points are way, way down!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Adobe Air apps on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 23:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu-comments/</guid>
      <description>I wrote Uninstaller for Adobe AIR for doing that a&amp;hellip; Bernard Opic - Mar 4, 2010I wrote Uninstaller for Adobe AIR for doing that automatically.It currently works on Ubuntu with GNOME and KDE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Adobe Air apps on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 23:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/removing-adobe-air-apps-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to remove AgileAgenda after fiddling with it for a week and deciding it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to cut it. There&amp;rsquo;s no Adobe Air Application &amp;ldquo;uninstaller&amp;rdquo; in the menu, and search engine results usually point to Mac lurv, or not. Seems like uninstalling Air apps on OSX is bloody.
I did find this nice article on removing Adobe Air on Linux and gave it (well parts of it) a shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Plesk Blues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-plesk-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:42:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-plesk-blues/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this problem with Plesk since I started relying heavily on it in 2006. For some reason, after you&amp;rsquo;ve added your client, allocated IP address to client&amp;rsquo;s pool, added a domain, and selecting physical hosting, you get the message:
 Unable to update hosting preferences: hosting update is failed: object ID is invalid
 After getting this error, you get the domain listed, but still requiring set up. Attempting to complete physical hosting setup will give you same result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on statuses(?) and micro-blogging</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-statuses-and-micro-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 10:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-statuses-and-micro-blogging/</guid>
      <description>hi. i&amp;rsquo;m testing out this feature in ping.fm. charo and jerome have been talking about this and thought i&amp;rsquo;d check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Plurking</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/now-plurking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/now-plurking/</guid>
      <description>Also playing in twitter, pownce, and soon identi.ca, but plurk wins for me, hands down. Check it out here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Bene Gesserit</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/feeling-bene-gesserit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 00:13:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/feeling-bene-gesserit/</guid>
      <description>I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my first tumble</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-tumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 21:42:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-tumble/</guid>
      <description>ok so it’s not really the first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my first tumble</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-tumble_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 14:42:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-first-tumble_18/</guid>
      <description>ok so it’s not really the first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cross-posting is about integration</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/cross-posting-is-about-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 23:08:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/cross-posting-is-about-integration/</guid>
      <description>got multiply? this is a test of the multiply-blogger cross-posting feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pink v.smile tv learning system for sale</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/pink-vsmile-tv-learning-system-for-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 02:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/pink-vsmile-tv-learning-system-for-sale/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I are selling one of Kysa’s barely-used toys. It’s one of Vtech’s multi-awarded preschool consoles and one of the best educational toys around.
It’s called the V.Smile TV Learning System (the ones they’re selling now are new models), and it’s in pink! It also comes with the Dora’s Fix-it Adventure game cartridge.
We’re selling it for only P4,000, after we’ve taken off 20% from the original retail price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my must-have&#39;s for firefox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-must-have-for-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2007 12:27:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-must-have-for-firefox/</guid>
      <description>in not so significant order:
1. mm3-proxyswitch
2. regular expressions tester
3. del.icio.us
4. greasemonkey
4. better gmail
5. firegpg
6. downThemAll
7. save as image</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more agua</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-agua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 04:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-agua/</guid>
      <description>just how much water can your body take? doing a little experiment while i’m on treatment. one freakin’ mug-full an hour. bloated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>you&#39;re looking good, opensource!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/you-looking-good-opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/you-looking-good-opensource/</guid>
      <description>opensource gets another breakthrough today, as canonical launches launchpad personal package archive (PPA), an ubuntu linux developers service intended to extend collaboration in software development and give the community equal opportunity to build and package code for ubuntu on the desktop, server, and for mobile applications.
great news for those itching to modify packages and contribute to the furtherance of opensource! users can make changes on packages of their choice, and these will be published in the PPA system, somewhat like a special repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more agua</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-agua_26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 21:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-agua_26/</guid>
      <description>just how much water can your body take? doing a little experiment while i’m on treatment. one freakin’ mug-full an hour. bloated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on work and blogging</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-work-and-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 20:42:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-work-and-blogging/</guid>
      <description>i haven&amp;rsquo;t been updating for several important, albeit lousy reasons.
work has been keeping me up at nights and i feel that if i were to write entries, i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be making much sense.
technobabble is fun, but i&amp;rsquo;ve long outgrown this preference for writing. call it a maturing of sorts, and i&amp;rsquo;m now ready to take things (read: blogging) to higher levels
i&amp;rsquo;ve almost completely forgotten about deepest sender, a cool firefox extension for blogging, and it&amp;rsquo;s great to be using it again</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plesk won&#39;t start after tweaking mysql</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plesk-won-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 12:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plesk-won-start-after-tweaking-mysql/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;ve had this happen to me again the other week and as always, felt like kicking myself for not remembering.
we do a lot of performance tuning on mysql, and as a result, we almost always manage to get plesk mangled. not its fault, it just can&amp;rsquo;t run without mysql, doh.
not of preference, but plesk happens to be there to make handling domains easier, as a single editing point when you want to change something and not worry about missing something out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>apt-get install kicker-kblogger</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apt-get-install-kicker-kblogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 11:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/apt-get-install-kicker-kblogger/</guid>
      <description>i don&amp;rsquo;t know with you, but i sometimes get the big push to update, if and when there&amp;rsquo;s something new (relatively, for me) to try.
up for this week is my dabbling with stuff around kicker, and using kblogger to do some much needed updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pushing on</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/pushing-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2007 09:49:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/pushing-on/</guid>
      <description>I recently got Ubuntu Feisty Fawn Beta running on my HP Pavilion dv2001tu notebook, and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the way it&amp;rsquo;s running. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and have been doing the past month. Nothing out of the ordinary for me, but some of the activities mentioned here could have been keeping you up late at nights, coveting much of the understated successes of
running Ubuntu on HP laptops. If this is indeed so, do let me know your woes and I&amp;rsquo;ll see what I can do to help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LJ rocks more than ever</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/lj-rocks-more-than-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 20:59:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/lj-rocks-more-than-ever/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to eclair for the links. :) And I thought scribfire rawked totally. Whee!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelving trigger.cdo.linux.org.ph</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/shelving-triggercdolinuxorgph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 15:31:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/shelving-triggercdolinuxorgph/</guid>
      <description>I am officially bringing down my old tech blog after Holy Week. It has virtually become a sinkhole for all kinds of spam links and I have barely done anything to keep it up-to-date.
Two of the milestones that I&amp;rsquo;ve unknowingly and unwittingly accomplished would include (in order, sorry):
1. PR6 (yea, before it went offline for almost a month, and before Google deployed new algorithms sometime in Feb)
2. 20,453 spam comments since I replaced my Wordpress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rush that&#39;s called Graduation</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-rush-that-called-graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 07:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-rush-that-called-graduation/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes wish it were me. But I’d rather have my daughter bask in her moment. It’s just that I clearly remember the feeling. You’re all bubbly and excited, and you can’t stop talking about it. My daughter’s graduating from preschool tomorrow, and my wife and I are as much into the rush as she is.
1st grade, here we come. *groan*</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rush that&#39;s called Graduation</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-rush-that-called-graduation_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 00:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/the-rush-that-called-graduation_23/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes wish it were me. But I’d rather have my daughter bask in her moment. It’s just that I clearly remember the feeling. You’re all bubbly and excited, and you can’t stop talking about it. My daughter’s graduating from preschool tomorrow, and my wife and I are as much into the rush as she is.
1st grade, here we come. *groan*</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will code for hosting</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/will-code-for-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2007 11:54:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/will-code-for-hosting/</guid>
      <description>Honestly, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done any coding in the last 4 months, which is really odd, because I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d be this detached from programming. But I guess there&amp;rsquo;s more to life than just developing or sustaining passion for singulars. So much for trying not to stay generalist.
So I have this personal domain now, and I&amp;rsquo;m just glad google apps isn&amp;rsquo;t as stiff with the applications anymore. The new interface totally rocks too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinoy Big Brother 2</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/pinoy-big-brother-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 16:20:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/pinoy-big-brother-2/</guid>
      <description>Forget the housemates! Mariel Rodriguez makes this reality TV show &amp;ldquo;watchable&amp;rdquo;. Half past midnight since the new season launched and the server is already borked! Good thing I got to grab this pic of Mariel before it went down (it seems to be failing intermittently&amp;hellip;but what can you expect from an M$ OS anyway?)
Here&amp;rsquo;s the error I see:
Could not load file or assembly &amp;lsquo;BizModules.UltraPhotoGallery&amp;rsquo; or one of its dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IP-hijacking and then some</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 19:51:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ip-hijacking-and-then-some/</guid>
      <description>Almost a month of downtime. The servers were fine, but our IP addresses were not. Somehow, a system bug from one of the hosting companies caused our plan to include 14 other IP addresses, and we only maintained 6 as far as I am concerned.
So the hosting company eventually understood what was happening and started asking the right questions. The bug is that the system allowed network administrators to assign to new clients, the IP addresses that have already been assigned to a current client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using symbolic links for MySQL data files</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 16:47:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-symbolic-links-for-mysql-data/</guid>
      <description>Over a year ago, we had several servers configured for high traffic websites. A mispartioning resulted in /var becoming obscenely small, and it was only after MySQL crashed that we remembered this. We couldn’t afford more downtime if we dealt with the partition size problem, so I thought of quickly moving the data files into /home/mysql/{dbname} from /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} and create the symlink /var/lib/mysql/{dbname} -&amp;gt; /home/mysql/{dbname}.
I was not certain of the performance implications to this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leeching for internet access</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/leeching-for-internet-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 12:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/leeching-for-internet-access/</guid>
      <description>Sure, my bosses do this all the time…in airports, hotel lobbies, and coffee shops. The mere act of “connecting” to an unsecured wireless network doubles as a necessity and as a leaching of sorts. Gotta love wireless. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leeching for internet access</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/leeching-for-internet-access_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 05:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/leeching-for-internet-access_28/</guid>
      <description>Sure, my bosses do this all the time…in airports, hotel lobbies, and coffee shops. The mere act of “connecting” to an unsecured wireless network doubles as a necessity and as a leaching of sorts. Gotta love wireless. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What it means to aggregate thinking</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/what-it-means-to-aggregate-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2006 08:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/what-it-means-to-aggregate-thinking/</guid>
      <description>I love thinking. They say thinking burns as many calories as when you&amp;rsquo;re having sex&amp;hellip;so you may liken thinking to sex. Sounds good, eh? But be warned. Although you can easily fake either one, you don&amp;rsquo;t lose as many calories as doing it for real!
This isn&amp;rsquo;t a sex column, so it&amp;rsquo;s best I get straight to the point and present my thoughts on what aggregated thinking is (and what constitutes faking it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hysteria</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hysteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2006 05:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hysteria/</guid>
      <description>Casey Kasem’s American Top 40 broadcast back in April 1988 is being streamed today over XM Radio. Def Leppard’s Hysteria is currently playing. Measures and measures of this classic hit flood my ears and I can’t help but smile. There must have been thousands of Icehouse, Def Leppard, and Nelson (to name a few) playbacks since I got them cassette and 8-track tapes.
I still think that the 1980’s was the best decade to grow in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hysteria</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hysteria_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 22:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hysteria_1/</guid>
      <description>Casey Kasem’s American Top 40 broadcast back in April 1988 is being streamed today over XM Radio. Def Leppard’s Hysteria is currently playing. Measures and measures of this classic hit flood my ears and I can’t help but smile. There must have been thousands of Icehouse, Def Leppard, and Nelson (to name a few) playbacks since I got them cassette and 8-track tapes.
I still think that the 1980’s was the best decade to grow in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you an 80s kid in the Philippines?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/are-you-80s-kid-in-philippines-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 02:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/are-you-80s-kid-in-philippines-comments/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;rsquo;m old now. I experienced all of thes&amp;hellip; Joy de Guzman - Jan 0, 2011I think I&amp;rsquo;m old now. I experienced all of these when I was a kid. Hahaha Great blog post Jon :) Cheers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you an 80s kid in the Philippines?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/are-you-80s-kid-in-philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 02:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/are-you-80s-kid-in-philippines/</guid>
      <description>You know you’re a kid of the 80’s in the Philippines if:
1.) You have scars on your knees and elbows
2.) You owned a bike
3.) You had a barkada around your neighborhood (all of you had bikes)
4.) You loved climbing on your house’s roof (and your neighbor’s roof as well)
5.) You went inside an abandoned house in your neighborhood just to see what it looks like inside</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote posting to Blogger Beta</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/remote-posting-to-blogger-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2006 23:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/remote-posting-to-blogger-beta/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a pretty slick Windows application that will allow you to post directly to your Blogger Beta account. The Firefox extension Deepest Sender, which allows posting to LJ, Blogger, and Wordpress, doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with Blogger Beta yet, so here&amp;rsquo;s a workaround that you can do meantime.
I prefer FOSS applications that run natively on GNU/Linux, but sometimes, you really need to use a platform where you are most productive. Writing stuff from anywhere will mean doing this from my Windows-run notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not walking on glass</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/not-walking-on-glass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 15:44:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/not-walking-on-glass/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a memo the other day and could not help but emphasize on the importance of using good ol&#39; wit and common sense, when on the internet. I probably had the gall to write these since I&amp;rsquo;m recklessly doing stuff on Ubuntu and couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less if an intrusion breaks something. LOL. Windoze is like walking on glass. Some of the guidelines I wrote:
 4. Browse and click responsibly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back and look what I checked out first!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-back-and-look-what-i-checked-out-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/i-back-and-look-what-i-checked-out-first/</guid>
      <description>This is how the rear of the NetBay rack in my previous company looks like now. I headed back to CDO for Halloween vacation and was able to drop by the office to pick up some of my personal stuff. They&amp;rsquo;ve slapped in a Cisco router (where the yellow fibre cable hooks up to) and another L3 switch. The old firewall appliance is still there, reliable as ever. Cabling got more structured as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps API Discovery</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/google-maps-api-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 19:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/google-maps-api-discovery/</guid>
      <description>Okay, it has been around for quite some time, and I remember writing an article about this in my older tech blog. I have a month to finish a pre-proposal on something GIS-related, so I&amp;rsquo;m seeing how this can be made possible with a renewed fascination with Google Maps.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently catching up on readings for my thesis pre-proposal. Some projects are quite interesting, notably those that do geographic encoding, location tracing via IP, or widget development, using Google Maps technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Talk with Kopete</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-google-talk-with-kopete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 09:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/using-google-talk-with-kopete/</guid>
      <description>I absolutely love Gaim, but the message to group feature isn&amp;rsquo;t readily available, even with gaim2-beta3, and this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me especially that I sometimes need to broadcast messages to team members over IM. Quick googling led me to Frank Spychalski&amp;rsquo;s very good article, which covers the essentials of configuring Google Talk on Kopete. For Ubuntu users, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have Kopete yet, you will need an internet connection to get the necessary packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settling down</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/settling-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2006 05:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/settling-down/</guid>
      <description>Finally had a little time in my hands, ergo some updates. One week down. Queen city of the South. Torrential rains. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be any more bushed than I currently am right now. Moving residence is definitely top in my list for most strenuous activities one can go through. It&amp;rsquo;s very prolonged; and the chores you thought you&amp;rsquo;d never do again, like wiring the aircon (Aside: among other things, and did I just forget about the aircon frame that we hacked?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movin&#39; on</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/movin-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 08:37:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/movin-on/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted in my &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; blog.
By the end of the month, I will be moving to the Queen City of the South, with my family in tow. I’m just glad that those guys at the new company were willing to wait for me. I was sure they understood the situation; I have established base in CDO and am currently employed. I was the one who was getting uprooted, so it was just proper that they agreed to waiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Shift to Dapper Beta</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-shift-to-dapper-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 22:03:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-shift-to-dapper-beta/</guid>
      <description>Over the Holy Week, two of our home computer&amp;rsquo;s drives crashed, probably due to extensive user download, software installs, and malware. I had to do work on the laptop for a while, and since everyone in the house was itching for Internet access, I brought in a small IDE drive (roughly around 9Gb) that was mounted as slave on my office computer and popped that in the home computer. I had more than enough reasons to put Ubuntu back in there, and nobody would be complaining!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uhmm..back to work</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/uhmmback-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2006 06:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/uhmmback-to-work/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to spend a few days vacationing in Manila. My mom-in-law was attending a national conference for pediatricians, and was given travel sponsorships for the entire family. I jumped at the chance to visit my aging Lola because she had not seen her great granddaughter, as the case was with all of my QC-based relatives. Our itinerary was real tight, but I was happy anyway since we went through so many unexpected, yet pleasant surprises en route to Manila until we got back here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Viewed in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/best-viewed-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 09:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/best-viewed-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s so dissapointing to see CSS that you really like &amp;ldquo;unrenderable&amp;rdquo; in IE. All I can say is get Firefox now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting GNU/Linux through Competition</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/promoting-gnulinux-through-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 01:33:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/promoting-gnulinux-through-competition/</guid>
      <description>Met up with hardwyrd last night for preliminary competition planning. Also present were some of the pillars of GNU/Linux and FOSS in Northern Mindanao: Mr. Rem Taga of MPSC, Mr. Botp Peña of DMPC, and Mr. Vidor Balbon of Philcom. I hope to keep up with these guys considering that my GNU/Linux experience is so diversified and I&amp;rsquo;d have to polish skills on specific services, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve not even bothered tinkering with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Making my way downtown...&#34;</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-way-downtown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2006 03:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-way-downtown/</guid>
      <description>I heard Vanessa Carlton’s “A Thousand Miles” about three times the entire day, and can’t help but snort and stifle a laughing bout each time. Who doesn’t associate that song with Latrell Spencer (Terry Crews) in the movie White Chicks? LOL!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling ntpupdate</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disabling-ntpupdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 03:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/disabling-ntpupdate/</guid>
      <description>This has been quite overdue, as I have been wanting to disable ntpupdate since the Hoary release. What is ntpupdate anyway? It&amp;rsquo;s the program that synchronizes your system time to an ntp server. NTP is a protocol for synchronising the clocks of computer systems over packet-switched, variable-latency data networks. Since Ubuntu defaults to an ntp server somewhere in the www, and that it will attempt to sync on boot, it causes your machine to go through a much much longer startup process if an internet connection is not available at boot time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>got Friendster?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/got-friendster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 05:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/got-friendster/</guid>
      <description>My wife just got her account and she found it awesome; as she was able to catch up on old friends. A highschool buddy paid us a visit today and she too told me to get a Friendster account and you know, start catching up as well (she&amp;rsquo;d rather that I find out about my batch&amp;rsquo;s whereabouts by myself than get bugged by me). So if you&amp;rsquo;re a buddy of mine, add me to your 300+ node network of friends, jon dot doblados at gmail dot com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-commerce Theory and Practice</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/e-commerce-theory-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/e-commerce-theory-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>The coming finals in my e-commerce class got me browsing through piles of readings and notes and I realized that I have not fully appreciated e-commerce as I should have. A techie will know what digital signatures, catalogs, EDI&amp;rsquo;s, EFT&amp;rsquo;s, shopping carts, or SSL are, as applied to buying and selling online; but graduate school won&amp;rsquo;t even let you wallow in those. Instead, one gets tasked to relate e-commerce with business processes, and usually, look for solutions to support business processes that e-commerce systems can&amp;rsquo;t support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Extension for Firefox</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/performance-extension-for-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 10:20:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/performance-extension-for-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Miko for the heads up. Check out this quite nice extension to Firefox, which will allow you to do updates without having to log in to your _numerous_ blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My LJ</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-lj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2005 05:42:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/my-lj/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a joy to see developments in LiVEJOURNAL. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plug: I&#39;m selling a Nokia 3200</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plug-i-selling-nokia-3200/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2005 23:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/plug-i-selling-nokia-3200/</guid>
      <description>If anyone&amp;rsquo;s interested, we&amp;rsquo;re selling a Nokia 3200. It has great features for an entry imaging-recording level gadget, plus more. I especially like the cover template cutter. Check it out from Nokia:
The Nokia 3200 is a canvas for your self-expression and artistry. Create original designs with unique Cut-out covers1 and your own pictures taken with the Integrated Digital Camera2. And as you create, groove to your favorite tunes on the built-in stereo radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meh</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/meh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2005 07:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/meh/</guid>
      <description>If I pointed you to another blog of mine, would you visit that as much, considering that it would have mostly techno babble in it, and that it won&amp;rsquo;t have the indispensable &amp;ldquo;my friends&amp;rdquo; link (because it&amp;rsquo;s not on LJ)?
Pardon me, I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d be quoting myself this early. =). I just feel like I got to explain myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on LJ since 2000. There&amp;rsquo;s a high level of pride associated with web logging that early, and I know most of us have been around and can relate to this feeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>just wondering...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/just-wondering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2005 02:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/just-wondering/</guid>
      <description>If I pointed you to another blog of mine, would you visit that as much, considering that it would have mostly techno babble in it, and that it won&amp;rsquo;t have the indispensable &amp;ldquo;my friends&amp;rdquo; link (because it&amp;rsquo;s not on LJ)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRASS</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2005 05:27:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/grass/</guid>
      <description>I had a good consultation session with my mentor last Saturday and I got great advise for my thesis. I&amp;rsquo;m planting my foot on GIS and applications, but the whole gamut of GIS is fairly large so I had to zero in on what I really wanted to focus on. Future research prospects on GIS led me to look up Geographic Resources Analysis Support System, commonly referred to as GRASS. It&amp;rsquo;s so cool because for starters, it&amp;rsquo;s GPLed, and it will run on PostgreSQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on Dune</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 01:15:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-dune/</guid>
      <description>Ayt, it has been almost 10 years since I last watched Dune, but the plot, the lines&amp;hellip;they all came back to me when Matt posted the Litany of Fear on his website. Sure does bring back the awe I felt back then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Critique] Implementing a public web based GIS service for feedback of surveillance data on communicable diseases in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/critique-implementing-public-web-based/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 05:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/critique-implementing-public-web-based/</guid>
      <description>Article by Per Rolfhamre1 , Katarzyna Grabowska1 and Karl Ekdahl1, 2
1Department of Epidemiology, Swedish Institute for Infectious Disease Control, Nobels vÃ¤g 18, SE-17182 Solna, Sweden
2Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institute, SE-17177 Stockholm, Sweden
 The authors have sufficiently summarized the study by including the purpose, methods, results, and conclusions or summary. The study was focused on the discussion of the considerations and technology of a created public web-based GIS service, which has already been deployed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Critique] Positional error in automated geocoding of residential addresses</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/critique-positional-error-in-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 05:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/critique-positional-error-in-automated/</guid>
      <description>Article by Michael R Cayo and Thomas O Talbot
Geographic Research and Analysis Section, Bureau of Environmental and Occupational
Epidemiology, New York State Department of Health, 547 River Street, Room 200,
Troy, NY 12180-2216, USA
 The authors have sufficiently summarized the study by including the purpose, methods, results, and conclusions or summary. The study has identified positional error correction as their purpose, with the objective of determining if the errors in geographic encoding could impact results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSI: Season Finale</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/csi-season-finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2005 07:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/csi-season-finale/</guid>
      <description>I am one with the millions of CSI fans raring to watch the 2-hour season finale of the top rated series on television. Quentin Tarantino has been tapped to direct this one and I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;ll be a very, very good 2 hours. My daughter needs to sleep a good hour before that starts because she won&amp;rsquo;t sleep if she sees CSI on. Like father, like daughter.
I posted this on my tech blog, but I feel that I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have more people see it here in LJ, which will hopefully translate to more ready answers for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mysql woes</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 07:37:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mysql-woes/</guid>
      <description>In my quest to have my &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; blog resuscitated on our new p5 server so that I have something to use for my tech notes here at work as well as my MS requirements, I downloaded MySQL-4.1.12-0.sles9.src.rpm from mysql.com in the hope of getting Wordpress running on our server. I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to install the darn thing. So I dl&amp;rsquo;ed mysql-standard-4.1.12-unknown-linux-gnu-powerpc-glibc23.tar.gz and tried to use the binaries instead.
Viola! MySQL4.1.12 managed to run fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiyaah!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hiyaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2005 23:16:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/hiyaah/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>all about me</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/all-about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2005 04:38:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/all-about-me/</guid>
      <description>here&amp;rsquo;s a trail of my exploits over
the internet
http://darealslash.livejournal.com #my very first blog
http://trigger_ph.livejournal.com #don&amp;rsquo;t ask why but i thought i&amp;rsquo;d make another one</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first week school blues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/first-week-school-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2005 01:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/first-week-school-blues/</guid>
      <description>I got really dissed last night waiting for instructors to report for class. It almost seemed prank-like to me, because we were all waiting for this guy to show up, and just a few minutes before we were afforded a free cut, somebody got SMS from the instructor, apologizing that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to make it (again). It probably came late because of network lag, but I&amp;rsquo;d glady discount that because it was a 3-hr class and we waited for almost an hour for the cut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TODO 06/21</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/todo-0621/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 23:49:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/todo-0621/</guid>
      <description>1. finish Perl script that will import mail accounts to the new p5
2. test alias IP and check what tcp_sync error means
3. do report on failed drive
4. finalize schedule for website design consultation sessions with concern personnel
present designs to staff
test clamv, amavis, &amp;amp; spamd configs
get BERT report from MGC (from RIA)
start and try to finish configuration work on vclass
start migrating email accounts to p5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>go San Antonio Spurs!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/go-san-antonio-spurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 04:06:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/go-san-antonio-spurs/</guid>
      <description>Robert Horry&amp;rsquo;s the man!!! What a clincher for a do-or-die game 5 for the Spurs! Horry&amp;rsquo;s 3 pointer shots saved his team twice, once to secure an OT, and the second to give them a 1-shot victory over the Pistons!
Simply awesome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dumbass mode</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/dumbass-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:04:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/dumbass-mode/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;m really hoping my old server gets up soon so i can download my shit out and start publishing again from our own servers here. all my scripts and applications that have been published are there, and most of the updates i did are there. the server went out even before i could sync my local copies. dumbass right? like why in the world would you be doing sync from a remote?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getting back on track</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/getting-back-on-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 08:45:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/getting-back-on-track/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back at work. My recent sickness made me think again about my eating habits, my vices, and how I love shunning medication and prescriptions; preferring proper rest and vigorous exercise over anything pharmaceutically made. It was a community-acquired viral infection that made the insides of my lungs all pulpy and lugaw-like. I was short of getting the P200+ kind of antibiotic. It was a good thing I was responding well to what I was taking in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>down with the flu...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/down-with-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2005 02:42:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/down-with-flu/</guid>
      <description>been barking since dawn. feel like i got beat up. =(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gobble-gobble-gobble...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gobble-gobble-gobble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 02:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/gobble-gobble-gobble/</guid>
      <description>Going cold turkey for good. We had deliverance last weekend and I was pretty sure then that it was time to quit. I’m a few months short of making it to 15 years of puffing away, but hell I’m not going to wait for that anymore. I’m on my 4th no-smoke day, and I think I’m going to make it. Withdrawal symptoms were raging hard yesterday and I had to take the rest of the afternoon off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTA setup</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mta-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2005 23:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/mta-setup/</guid>
      <description>Pending Tjay&amp;rsquo;s visit, the reconfiguration of the Firebox will have to wait. It is important to have the CDO MTA running along with the HTTPD service in the P5-520 to be able to test the configuration in more or less &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; conditions.
Public IP: 203.177.75.33 Public Alias: 203.177.75.37 
TODO:
  1. set up of CDO MTA (HTTP and Postfix in one machine)
  2. DNS entries for cdo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on emacs</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 23:46:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/on-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I have been trying to find time to install Emacs (temporarily) on jjd because I really want to get my planner running asap. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing that there is currently a good following for this editor, especially when add-on functionality is introducted: like PlannerMode, which I believe will be a very good tool for me. It will allow the conception of collaborative input/development for tasks and projects.
TODO:
  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>umpisa na!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/umpisa-na/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2005 04:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/umpisa-na/</guid>
      <description>man, this morning i sent off my kid to her first school day. she was too excited to even give me a hug before i reported for work. we decided on sending her to a montessori-patterned school for the summer so as to allow her to adjust to school life before she starts K1 in SMS this June (equivalent to Nursery in other schools). she hasn’t gone through toddler’s/playgroup class, so this will be her first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more stf blues</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-stf-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 23:47:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/more-stf-blues/</guid>
      <description>1. test batch nos. 003442 (solomon) and 003444 (intra)
  2. per InvtID, pick up LotSerNbr(s) as required or set by needed quantity, and insert corresponding number of rows in LotSerT
  3. if i will require 3 serials, then the top non-zero LotSerNbr&amp;rsquo;s will be retrieved and inserted accordingly to LotSerT
  4. during release by solomon, QtyOnHand will be set to 0 and a new row will be created for the same item, with QtyOnHand set to 1, indicating that the item has moved locations/sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>changes for stf</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/changes-for-stf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 23:49:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/changes-for-stf/</guid>
      <description>1. stf transactions (data entry) over the intranet had problems when solomon tries to do a &amp;ldquo;release now&amp;rdquo; action.
  2. further analysis by LPE shows that the intranet module hasn&amp;rsquo;t completely emulated the &amp;ldquo;transfers&amp;rdquo; transaction of solomon, in that the items transferred did not have corresponding serialized entries in LotSerT
  3. relations: Batch 1:1 TrnsfrDoc, Batch 1:n INTran, INTran 1:n LotSerT
  4. look up for LotSerT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>to blog or not to blog...is no longer the question</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/to-blog-or-not-to-blogis-no-longer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2005 02:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/to-blog-or-not-to-blogis-no-longer/</guid>
      <description>I have recently tried out WordPress for my requirements. I fell in love with it just about immediately. Miko has expressed disgust at my trolling, but really, I haven&amp;rsquo;t even started flaming other products. Not that I plan to. After all, I have started web logging in LJ, so there&amp;rsquo;s /dev/null chance that I&amp;rsquo;ll favor another over this one.
I&amp;rsquo;m giving myself a few more weeks to play around with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>soon-to-be-IBM-customer</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/soon-to-be-ibm-customer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2004 05:38:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/soon-to-be-ibm-customer/</guid>
      <description>What a month it has been! It was my first time to do facilitating work relevant to equipment acquisition, and everything has been so cooperative (thank God!). The only thing that&amp;rsquo;s keeping me from getting giddy with anticipation over the delivery of those servers is the fact that the PO hasn&amp;rsquo;t been issued yet. It seems to me that Purchasing people have this degree of power over everyone else, in the sense that they can always mull over our longing to have stuff bought right away and decide to do delaying tactics just for the hell of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what&#39;s in a name?</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/what-in-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2004 08:37:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/what-in-name/</guid>
      <description>with thanks to bench. :D
My japanese name is ?? Nakashima (center of the island) ?? Taiki (large radiance).
Take your real japanese name generator! today!
Created with Rum and Monkey&amp;rsquo;s Name Generator Generator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2004 08:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_23/</guid>
      <description>i got my snout buried in sheets and sheets of system design and specs. i&amp;rsquo;m complaining almost a fraction of a decibel higher each passing day. i love this job! idiot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2004 08:49:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_8/</guid>
      <description>crap&amp;hellip;what&amp;rsquo;s with monday&amp;rsquo;s anyway? i&amp;rsquo;m totally wasted!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2004 03:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_26/</guid>
      <description>gaddamit! i look like an extinct galunggong! pareha ra ta bench!
trigger_ph
Plecostomus
Agility
1
|
Strength
5
|
Stamina
8
Battle Rating
14
Origins
trigger_ph was found trapped in a can of tuna
Can your fishy beat trigger_ph ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2004 01:32:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_14/</guid>
      <description>thanks to bench! hmmm&amp;hellip;i admit, i had to refresh a couple of times cuz they all had filipino words in them and honestly, they didn&amp;rsquo;t even make sense to me. hahaha.
cheerios!
LiveJournal Haiku!
Your name:
trigger_ph
Your haiku:
of gnu or linux
is the ultimate goal of
our community
Username:
[Created by
Grahame](http://www.livejournal.com/users/grahame/)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2004 08:32:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_12/</guid>
      <description>watched the CSI premiere last night (yea, i guess Asia&amp;rsquo;s only watching the new season episodes now, thanks AXN!) and couldn&amp;rsquo;t get enough of it! (as usual) lolz. it was a bit frustrating though to see &amp;ldquo;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; at the end&amp;hellip;.lolz. it was a refreshing reprise of the kind of forensic shows we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten so used of, thanks to jerry bruckheimer. let&amp;rsquo;s face it, CSI paved the way for real and &amp;ldquo;authentic&amp;rdquo; forensics for the layman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haberdi!</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/haberdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2004 09:37:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/haberdi/</guid>
      <description>juryse, my dear dear ati&amp;hellip;:P happy birthday! sana u stay as sweet and as patient as u were last year nung bata ka pa at natitiis mo pa ung pangaalaska namin ng lolo mo&amp;hellip;*blub blub blub! :P
ack kahapon lang pala&amp;hellip;my bad. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ack...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2004 07:34:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/ack/</guid>
      <description>m down to my last two modules before this quarter ends. the first modules have been deployed and parallel-tested, with just a bit of flak coming from &amp;ldquo;concerned&amp;rdquo; users (since they&amp;rsquo;re sooo used to stand-alone applications, they think that intranet applications would have the same degree of difficulty, more or less). hell my scripts generate 5k lines of values each for 10 different select elements and they wanted a more &amp;ldquo;user-friendly&amp;rdquo; output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2004 07:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled_6/</guid>
      <description>nuthin new&amp;hellip;i still got sPrOcK up to my neck trying to fix wut went wrong with the servers over the holidays. why do unwanted things have to happen when nobody&amp;rsquo;s in the office? :D
happy three kings! whoopeee for Philippine politics! thanks to the upcoming elections, my job is starting to sound like a lost cause or sumthin. my wife&amp;rsquo;s about done with her nursing anyway, but it&amp;rsquo;ll be another 2 years or so before she can go anywhere; unless some hospital needs a nutritionist/dietician first, nurse second&amp;hellip;then maybe, just maybe&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;ll be a lot earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>one more time...</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/one-more-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2004 04:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/one-more-time/</guid>
      <description>aight, this is probably the last time i&amp;rsquo;m gonna be changing accounts here. i&amp;rsquo;m getting too old for this poppin&#39; syndrome, and i just hope that all of my friends (parang andami noh? hehe) would understand. i want to re-establish, re-build, and put some stability naman to my entries. meantime, imma wait till i finish archiving (nyek&amp;hellip;parang andami din noh?) my previous journals, which i will then delete for closure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2003 02:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/untitled/</guid>
      <description>(note: this here&amp;rsquo;s a repost. check out original post. sorry hehehe..
m finally leaving academic life. how long has it been gani? 9 years. sheesh. but i&amp;rsquo;m happy i&amp;rsquo;m this close to the finish line. now i&amp;rsquo;m pressured to grab my MS on the fly with all the projects i&amp;rsquo;m doing. I NEED A JOB! lol. i need the money for paying back people who believed i&amp;rsquo;d still get to finish this degree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Posts as Kysapop</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/past-posts-as-kysapop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/past-posts-as-kysapop/</guid>
      <description>[Jul. 30th, 2003|09:18 am]
Current Mood |
high
Current Music | One - Metallica (as performed by Korn)
papa&amp;rsquo;s birthday yesterday. so was my mom-in-law&amp;rsquo;s. so was my favorite uncle&amp;rsquo;s. i got to call my pop early just to tell him i got him a singing-chickens bday card. ahh the wonders of flash&amp;hellip; and free hallmark ecards! :P
kahapon was terrible. i ate like a pig. i slobbered on my wine glass like a st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Posts as Darealslash</title>
      <link>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/past-posts-as-darealslash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2003 00:03:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jondoblados.github.io/posts/past-posts-as-darealslash/</guid>
      <description>Yaaaaaaah!!! I burned myself with my own cig butt! Sheesh. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the butt. Surely, it&amp;rsquo;ll want to get back at u after u&amp;rsquo;ve used it, (kaw kaya sipsipin at paglaruan dyan!) even more if u don&amp;rsquo;t thank it for at least serving its purpose!
My wife&amp;rsquo;s giving birth anyday now and I&amp;rsquo;m just sooooo excited! Huh? Am I ready u mean? To be a father yes but frankly, we don&amp;rsquo;t have everything ready for the baby; y&amp;rsquo;know, the post natal stuff u need to have.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
