<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on </title>
    <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 10:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://triggered.doblados.net/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving Forward</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/moving-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/moving-forward/</guid>
      <description>In a month&amp;rsquo;s time, I would be transferring offices again. I started from a very technical department, under the administration cluster. A year and about 3 months later, I was given the privilege to transfer to one of the most influential and authoritative departments in the academic cluster. It was still a split engagement, with me going back and forth these two offices.
And for almost 2 years, I improved processes, handled, battled, and took care of hundreds of scenarios, cases, and situations that seem to always come with the university seasons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2013</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/christmas-2013/</guid>
      <description>We decided to go to Cebu and spend Christmas this year with my parents and brother. I suppose it has been more than 15 years since we last celebrated Christmas together. The trip was really stressful because it was passenger season. But it was really worth lugging heavy bags since the cousins got to goof off and have a lot of fun, and the grandparents got to see all of their grandchildren in one place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Googlers and GBG Managers learning from each other</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/googlers-and-gbg-managers-learning-from-each-other-and-collaborating-ondifferent-practices-that-can.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/googlers-and-gbg-managers-learning-from-each-other-and-collaborating-ondifferent-practices-that-can.../</guid>
      <description>Googlers and GBG Managers learning from each other and collaborating on different practices that can be adopted for communities! #searchsummit2013</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valentine Surprise</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/valentine-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/valentine-surprise/</guid>
      <description>Each year, on Valentine&amp;rsquo;s day, I usually surprise my darling wife with a letter/card, or a bouquet of roses. As it was a yearly thing, I knew she sort of expected these surprises; she&amp;rsquo;d look surprised, but I knew she wasn&amp;rsquo;t really. Occasionally, she does get surprised. Like that time back in Cebu when I bought her a rather intricate bouquet of flowers. Her head spun when she found out how much I paid for it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>on SLMIS</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/on-slmis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/on-slmis/</guid>
      <description>End users complain because the system isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;user-friendly&amp;rdquo;. FYI, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be that way. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way we can guarantee that the system will still be helpful 25 years from now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civic Stories - December 2012</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/civic-stories---december-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/civic-stories---december-2012/</guid>
      <description>I sort of miss being in the backseat. A lot of my goofing off years have been conducted within the confines of the passenger doors, backside of the front seats, and the backseat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Blog changes, etc.</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/revisited-blog-changes-etc./</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve once more moved my blog. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s on my own hosting account and it&amp;rsquo;s back to using WP. Same blog, different flavor now and moving forward. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this short discussion with a co-leader in church on going back to blogging, and he pointed out the importance of identifying to a particular niche. I said sure, it&amp;rsquo;s important, but I think I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to separate my technical gibberish from my thoughts and reflections on God and Christianity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honor God, Make Disciples</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/honor-god-make-disciples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/honor-god-make-disciples/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, I started attending this workshop/training for leaders at Victory CDO. It&amp;rsquo;s called Training for Victory (T4V), and it was a once-a-week engagement for about 10 weeks; although it took longer than that because of several holidays around that time. We graduated and were commissioned, not as pastors, but as servants who will lead people to take on a personal relationship with Christ. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace, I was also the recipient of the Award for Excellence during the ceremonies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kids on Photobooth</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/kids-on-photobooth/</guid>
      <description>Miguel and Isabel goofing off in front of the laptop. They discovered the 4-shot option and started taking pictures by themselves.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t mind if I start posting more pictures here. I’ve really been keeping myself from posting these to Facebook, which was the natural tendency, no thanks to endless egging by the family. But no. It’s been a couple of years now that I’ve wanted to steer clear from FB when it comes to posting pictures; especially of family.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thank you!</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>I am home, and enjoying my second lease in life, one slow day at a time. I have never been hospitalized for something as life-threatening as DHF with complications before, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit frustrating that even when I&amp;rsquo;m already out of the hospital, I could not move around as much as I want. I could not even attempt to lift and carry my son when he feels like asking me to hoist him up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musuan Trip</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/musuan-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/musuan-trip/</guid>
      <description>We went to Musuan, in Bukidnon. It&amp;rsquo;s home to the &amp;ldquo;boob&amp;rdquo; mountain, hence the name &amp;ldquo;Musuan&amp;rdquo;. Our dear Aunt Celia passed on and relatives from all over convened in CMU (where she was administrator). We spent the night in RR Family Spring Resort in Tubigon, border of Maramag, and after the wake swam in the fresh water pools, braving the intense cold. :D</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimsum again</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/dimsum-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 22:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/dimsum-again/</guid>
      <description>We love Dimsum Diner, but we gotta start learning to keep ourselves from eating there too often. Why? We&amp;rsquo;re all high risk people, that&amp;rsquo;s why.
In this set, my sister-in-law was playing around with the camera settings, which explains the no-flash feature. Will try to do another shoot next time and will play with ISO and WB. Not a DSLR. Lugging that with us during family eat-outs is overkill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New theme, needs more work</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/new-theme-needs-more-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/new-theme-needs-more-work/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m doing some major cosmetic changes with this blog; and I&amp;rsquo;m sort of working off this to-do:1. come up with a manageable set of tags2. update posts with appropriate tags3. look for any form of twitter integrationYes, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging more now. More than anything else, I need the writing exercise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Jejemon Bashing</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/stop-jejemon-bashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/stop-jejemon-bashing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not my business, but I&amp;rsquo;m really tired of all of these jejemon-bashing stuff I&amp;rsquo;m seeing in twitter and facebook. Why not make an effort to educate these language-challenged people?
Come on, this monsters been around a long time. It just took on a new name. Let&amp;rsquo;s do something productive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fever and what-not&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/fever-and-what-nots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/fever-and-what-nots/</guid>
      <description>I dare not say what we hope our daughter didn&amp;rsquo;t get thats causing her on and off high fever since Tuesday night. We&amp;rsquo;re still hopeful that it&amp;rsquo;s some ordinary viral infection that&amp;rsquo;s been plaguing kids these hot El Nino days.
My wife and I are in distress due to lack of sleep, but we&amp;rsquo;re still hopeful. We were advised to wait until 6pm tonight to get another CBC exam. That&amp;rsquo;s because aside from her fever, she hasn&amp;rsquo;t been showing the other symptoms, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deplurked</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/deplurked/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/deplurked/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve deplurked long enough I guess. Karma points are way, way down!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Bene Gesserit</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/feeling-bene-gesserit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/feeling-bene-gesserit/</guid>
      <description>I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LJ rocks more than ever</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/lj-rocks-more-than-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/lj-rocks-more-than-ever/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to eclair for the links. :) And I thought scribfire rawked totally. Whee!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movin&#39; on</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/movin-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 08:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/movin-on/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted in my &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; blog.
By the end of the month, I will be moving to the Queen City of the South, with my family in tow. I’m just glad that those guys at the new company were willing to wait for me. I was sure they understood the situation; I have established base in CDO and am currently employed. I was the one who was getting uprooted, so it was just proper that they agreed to waiting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meh</title>
      <link>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/meh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2005 07:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://triggered.doblados.net/posts/meh/</guid>
      <description>If I pointed you to another blog of mine, would you visit that as much, considering that it would have mostly techno babble in it, and that it won&amp;rsquo;t have the indispensable &amp;ldquo;my friends&amp;rdquo; link (because it&amp;rsquo;s not on LJ)?
Pardon me, I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d be quoting myself this early. =). I just feel like I got to explain myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on LJ since 2000. There&amp;rsquo;s a high level of pride associated with web logging that early, and I know most of us have been around and can relate to this feeling.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
